You became the world's youngest
你成为了世界上最年轻的
billionaire at the age of 25. You've got
25岁就成为亿万富翁。你拥有
Mark Zuckerberg offering you $3 billion.
马克·扎克伯格出价30亿美元给你。
That was a a fateful day for sure, but
那一天无疑是命运攸关的一天，但是……
we decided that we'd rather go it alone.
我们决定还是独自行动。
Was there ever a day where you doubted
你是否曾有过怀疑的时候？
that decision?
那个决定？
Evan Spiegel is the co-founder behind
埃文·斯皮格尔是联合创始人
one of the world's biggest social media
全球最大的社交媒体之一
platforms, Snapchat. He turned
平台，Snapchat。他转过身
disappearing messages into a
将消失的信息放入一个
multi-billion dollar empire, redefining
价值数十亿美元的帝国，重新定义
how we connect online. Evan, you don't
我们如何在线联系。埃文，你不用
do many podcasts, do you? I don't do
你经常做播客节目吗？我不做
much public speaking at all, but I want
我很少公开演讲，但我想要
to share a bit more. So, if let's go
再多分享一点。那么，我们走吧
back to those early days. So, I was an
回到那些早期的日子。所以，我当时是
introvert growing up and I loved to
我从小性格内向，但我热爱……
build stuff. At school, I had built my
建造东西。在学校里，我建立了我的
own computer. And once you start
自己的电脑。一旦你开始
realizing that things that look really
意识到那些看起来真正
complicated on the surface aren't that
表面上很复杂，不是吗？
difficult, you start wondering, you
很难，你会开始怀疑，你
know, what else you can build. So, that
知道你还能建造什么。以便
led to building Snapchat at 21. So, I
这促使我在21岁时创立了Snapchat。所以，我
was in undergrad at Stanford and we'd
当时我在斯坦福大学读本科，我们
raised
提高
$485,000 at a $4.25 million valuation.
售价 48.5 万美元，估值 425 万美元。
What a deal. But back then there
真是太划算了。但当时
were a lot of apps that would get
有很多应用程序会获得
popular really really quickly and then
很快就流行起来了，然后
sort of fade away. And a lot of people
渐渐消失。还有很多人
told us that we should sell it. They
他们告诉我们应该把它卖掉。他们
said you're just sending photos back and
你说你只是把照片发回去而已
forth. How is this going to grow for the
第四。它将如何发展壮大？
long term? But the growth of Snapchat
长期？但 Snapchat 的增长
was atypical to say the least. It was
说它是反常的，一点也不为过。那是
like this virus and it was reaching 75
就像这种病毒一样，它的感染率达到了75%。
million users on a monthly basis. So I
每月数百万用户。所以，我
wondered if you had any advice on the
不知道你有没有什么建议？
fundamental principles of success. How
成功的基本原则。如何
much people care about what they do and
很多人都在乎自己所做的事情，
the ability to move quickly is the
快速移动的能力是
predictor of success. And at Snapchat we
成功预测指标。在Snapchat，我们
have a really small design team. It's
设计团队规模非常小。它是
nine people who are constantly
九个不断
generating an incredible number of ideas
产生了数量惊人的想法
and products and features because 99% of
以及产品和功能，因为99%
ideas are not good, but 1% is. I want to
想法本身并不好，但1%是好的。我想要
know what they teach at Stanford because
我知道斯坦福大学教什么，因为
the success rate of creating some of the
创建某些项目的成功率
world's pre-minent entrepreneurs is
世界上最杰出的企业家是
really, really high. There were a lot of
非常非常高。有很多
very good lessons. The first one is
非常好的课程。第一个是
this has always blown my mind a little
这件事一直让我有点难以置信。
bit. 53% of you that listen to this show
少量。 53% 的听众收听了这个节目
regularly haven't yet subscribed to the
经常还没有订阅
show. So, could I ask you for a favor
展示。所以，我能请你帮个忙吗？
before we start? If you like the show
开始之前？如果你喜欢这个节目
and you like what we do here and you
你喜欢我们在这里做的事情，你
want to support us, the free simple way
想支持我们吗？免费又简单的方式！
that you can do just that is by hitting
你可以通过点击来做到这一点。
the subscribe button. And my commitment
订阅按钮。我的承诺
to you is if you do that, then I'll do
对你来说，如果你那样做，那么我也会那样做。
everything in my power, me and my team,
我和我的团队将竭尽全力
to make sure that this show is better
为了确保这个节目更好
for you every single week. We'll listen
每周都为您准备。我们会听的。
to your feedback. We'll find the guests
感谢您的反馈。我们会找到客人。
that you want me to speak to and we'll
你想让我跟谁谈谈，我们……
continue to do what we do. Thank you so
继续做我们正在做的事情。非常感谢
[Music]
[音乐]
much, Evan. When you look back over your
埃文，非常感谢。当你回顾你的
earliest years and you you try and make
早年时光，你努力尝试
sense of the dots that connected in
感受到点与点之间的联系
hindsight, I guess, as Steve Jobs once
事后看来，我想，正如史蒂夫·乔布斯曾经说过的那样
said, what are those dots?
他说：“那些点是什么？”
There were a couple fateful choices that
有几个影响深远的决定
my parents made that I think had a huge
那是我父母做的，我觉得它很大
impact. One was that they never let me
影响。其中一点就是他们从来不让我……
watch TV. So, they never let me watch
看电视。所以，他们从来不让我看
TV. It didn't uh want me to spend my
电视。它不想让我花时间
time doing that, but at the same time
花时间做这件事，但与此同时
would allow me to get whatever book I
这将使我能够得到我想要的任何书
wanted. And that was a really uh I think
通缉。那真是……呃，我觉得
formative experience for me and and
对我来说，这是一次塑造我人生的经历。
reading a book you get to use your
读书时你可以运用你的
imagination a lot you know to try to
想象力很重要，你知道要尝试
paint the characters in your own mind
在脑海中描绘出这些角色
and that was really helpful and because
那真的很有帮助，因为
I wasn't watching TV I had a lot of time
我没看电视，我有很多时间。
on my hands and so I like to build stuff
我天生擅长动手，所以我喜欢做东西。
I mean when I was young I would make a
我的意思是，我小时候会做
little fake hotel in our living room and
我们客厅里的小假酒店
you know have a guest experience where
你知道，要营造一种宾客体验，
my parents could come and you know try
我父母可以过来试试。
to stay at our hotel and I I got to use
我入住我们酒店，我可以使用
my imagination a lot at home and my
我在家的时候想象力很丰富，而且
parents never made me feel bad about
父母从来没有让我感到难过
turning the house upside down, moving
把房子翻个底朝天，搬家
chairs around to to express myself and
周围的椅子让我可以表达自己和
and make stuff. Did you feel like you
然后制作东西。你感觉自己像……
fitted in when you were a kid? No, not
你小时候很合群吗？不，不是
not at all. No. Um I I was more of an
一点也不。不。嗯，我更像是一个
introvert um growing up. So, you know, I
内向的……嗯，成长过程中。所以，你知道，我
think sometimes that made it harder for
有时我认为这反而使情况变得更糟
me to, you know, feel like I fit in. And
让我感觉自己能融入其中。
when did computers come into the picture
计算机是什么时候开始进入这个领域的？
for you? Uh I guess I I was exposed to
为你？呃，我想我接触过……
my first computer. Gosh,
我的第一台电脑。天哪，
probably kindergarten, first grade,
可能是幼儿园，一年级，
maybe around that uh period of time. I
大概就在那段时间吧。我
my godfather brought over one of the
我的教父带来了其中一个
early Macintoshes to show our our family
早期的麦金托什电脑向我们展示我们的家庭
and I got to try out things like Kidpics
我有机会体验了像 Kidpics 这样的产品。
and and stuff like that. And then I
诸如此类的事情。然后我
guess later on in school, I I went to
我猜后来在学校里，我去了
the computer lab a lot. My I really
经常去电脑室。我的天啊，我真的
wanted my own computer. So the big
我想要一台属于自己的电脑。所以，大
breakthrough was when my mom said, you
转机出现在我妈妈说“你”的时候。
know, if you build your own computer,
要知道，如果你自己组装电脑的话，
you can have it. uh we won't let you
你可以拿走它。呃，我们不会让你们这么做的。
connect it to the internet, but if you
将其连接到互联网，但是如果你
build your own computer, you can have it
你可以自己组装电脑，然后拥有它。
to to play with. And so that was
用来玩。事情就是这样。
probably by sixth grade, I had a teacher
大概到了六年级，我就有了一位老师
who helped me uh you know, take all the
谁帮我了，你知道，把所有的
different pieces you need and and put
你需要不同的部件，然后把它们放好
them all together to to build a
将它们全部结合起来，建造一个
computer. And I think the this act of
电脑。我认为这一行为
you know, putting together these pieces,
你知道，把这些碎片拼凑起来，
turning it on, you know, getting uh you
打开它，你知道，就是……
know, windows up and running, um just
我知道，Windows 系统已经启动并运行了，嗯，就是
made me realize why it's it seems so
这让我意识到为什么它看起来如此
complicated on the outside when you're
外表复杂，但实际上
just looking at that tower, that box,
看着那座塔，那个盒子，
right? or you know and you haven't yet
正确的？或者你知道但你还没知道
open opened it up and seen what's inside
打开它，看看里面是什么。
I think it can seem really confusing or
我觉得这可能会让人非常困惑或
complicated but as soon as you realize
很复杂，但一旦你意识到
it's not that hard uh you know to to put
其实没那么难，你知道，把它放进去。
it all together and and to get started I
把这一切结合起来，然后开始吧
think there's something really
我觉得这里面肯定有什么问题。
empowering about that about that feeling
那种感觉令人振奋
what what does that feeling teach you I
那种感觉教会了你什么？
I think you know and I think this is
我想你知道，而且我认为这是
much more the case now because you know
现在这种情况就更是如此，因为你知道
if you go on YouTube you can learn how
如果你上YouTube，你就能学会如何
to do pretty much anything right but I
我几乎什么都能做好，但我
think uh once you start realizing that
想想一旦你开始意识到这一点
things that look really complicated or
看起来很复杂或
confusing on the surface aren't aren't
表面上令人困惑，但实际上并非如此。
that difficult. Do you you start
那很难。你开始吗？
wondering, you know, what else you can
我在想，你知道，还能做些什么
build or what else you can create or,
建造或者你还能创造出什么，或者，
you know, how else you can can
你知道，你还能怎样呢？
experiment with something that seems
尝试一些看似
impossible from the outside, but really
从外部来看不可能，但实际上
it's just not that hard. And you got
其实没那么难。你得到了
bullied in school, right? Was it sixth
在学校被欺负过，对吧？是第六个吗？
grade that you got bullied or was it
你因为被欺负而获得的成绩，还是另有其他原因？
sometime thereafter? Yeah, middle school
此后的某个时间？是的，中学
was not the I think not the easiest
我觉得这并不是最容易的。
easiest time for me. Why? Um, you know,
对我来说最方便的时候。为什么？嗯，你知道，
as I mentioned, I sort of, you know, had
正如我之前提到的，我有点，你知道，曾经
trouble fitting in. I I I didn't do a
难以融入。我没做
lot of activities that some other
许多其他活动
schoolmates did like you know sports and
同学们喜欢运动之类的。
stuff. I played t you know a little bit
东西。我玩了一会儿，你知道的。
on the on the tennis team. Um but so I
在网球队里。嗯，但是……
think you know the combination of not
你认为你知道“否”的组合
really playing sports with friends,
和朋友们一起真正地进行体育运动，
spending a lot of time in the computer
花费大量时间在电脑上
lab uh you know at lunch or or after
实验室，你知道，午饭后或者之后
school I think you know just led to me
我想你知道，学校最终把我引向了这里。
feeling a bit socially isolated at you
感觉有点社交孤立你
know at what is I think a tricky time
我知道现在正处于一个棘手的时期。
for for lots of kids. What were you like
为了很多孩子。你当时是什么样的人？
as a kid? Were you confident? I don't I
小时候？你当时有信心吗？我不
don't know if I was confident in myself
我不知道自己当时是否对自己有信心。
per se, but I definitely was confident
就其本身而言，但我当时确实很有信心。
in my ideas. Like I was willing to take
在我的想法里。就像我愿意接受一样
a stand for ideas that I thought were
一个支持我认为是的想法的立场
different or I was willing to explore
不同，或者我愿意探索
ideas that didn't seem popular at the
那些在当时似乎并不受欢迎的想法
time because I thought it was, you know,
因为我以为是，你知道的，
important. I I was uh I was talking to
重要的。我，我当时在跟……说话
my my dad's has been staying with us for
我爸爸一直和我们住在一起
a while and I was talking with him. I
我和他聊了一会儿。我
was like, "What do you know, what
当时我就想，“你知道什么，什么？”
stories do you think I could tell about
你觉得我可以讲些什么故事呢？
growing up? What do you think?" And he
长大？你觉得呢？”他
was like, "Oh, you should tell them. You
当时我就想，“哦，你应该告诉他们。”
were definitely like a contrarian, you
你绝对是个喜欢唱反调的人。
know." I was like, "What do you mean by
我知道。”我当时就想，“你这话是什么意思？”
contrarian?" He's like, "Don't you
“你是个唱反调的人吗？”他回答说：“难道你不是吗？”
remember you wrote that article that was
还记得你写过那篇文章吗？
like an expose of the math program
就像对数学计划的揭露一样
because you were, you know, you you
因为你就是，你知道，你
basically interviewed all these teachers
基本上采访了所有这些老师。
and kids and parents and, you know, uh,
还有孩子、家长，你知道，呃，
wrote this whole expose about how the
我写了整篇揭露文章，讲述了……
math program could be better." And he
数学课程可以做得更好。” 他
was like, you know, it was sort of like
感觉就像，你知道，有点像……
maybe better left unsaid in that
或许最好还是别说了。
environment. But the school to their
环境。但学校对他们来说
credit supported me and like let me
信用支持了我，也让我……
publish it. And uh you know I think
发布它。呃，你知道，我觉得
created an environment where you know
创造了一个你知道的环境
kids could challenge authority which
孩子们可能会挑战权威，这
which was really uh you know something
那真是……你知道的。
that that I learned was okay. I guess
我后来才知道这样做是可以的。我猜
that's a principle as well of many of
这也是许多人秉持的原则。
the people that I meet like you is that
我遇到的像你这样的人就是
they're okay with pushing against
他们乐于推搡
convention and you know certain moments
惯例，你知道某些时刻
in your life you make these decisions
在你的人生中，你会做出这些决定
which one would say are contrarian bets.
可以说，这是反向投注。
I can I can see them all over your
我能看到它们遍布你的
story, but clearly that was something
故事，但显然那是某种东西。
innate in you from a fairly young age as
从很小的时候起，你就与生俱来具备这种特质。
you look back. You don't do many
你回头看。你做的并不多。
podcasts, do you? I don't do much public
你听播客吗？我不太参与公开活动。
speaking at all. It's it's a 2025 New
完全不说话。这是2025年新款
Year's resolution for me, though. So,
这是我今年的新年计划。所以，
we'll see. You know, I'm I'm trying to
我们拭目以待。你知道，我正在努力
trying to, you know, share a bit more.
想多分享一些。
Why? Um, I think it's really important
为什么？嗯，我认为这真的很重要。
that people understand our our company
人们了解我们公司
and what we stand for, why we make the
以及我们所代表的价值观，以及我们为何要这样做
decisions that we do and and I think
我们做出的决定，我认为
part of that is, you know, getting to
其中一部分是，你知道，到达
know me and Bobby and I, you know,
认识我和鲍比，你知道的，
started this business 13 years ago and
我13年前创办了这家公司，
we have made a bunch of different
我们已经制作了很多不同的
choices along the way. But I think
一路上的选择。但我认为
unless we talk about them, nobody knows.
除非我们谈论它们，否则没人会知道。
Um, and so it's it's really important
嗯，所以这真的很重要。
for us to share, you know, how how we
为了让我们分享，你知道，我们如何
make decisions and our design philosophy
做出决策和我们的设计理念
and and that kind of thing. It's a
诸如此类的事情。这是一个
really interesting time I think to be a
我觉得这是一个非常有趣的时期。
CEO generally because I think even 1015
CEO通常是因为我认为即使是1015
years ago CEOs of major companies that
多年前，一些大型公司的首席执行官们
so many people use and love weren't
很多人使用并喜爱它们，但它们并非如此。
doing podcasts. They weren't they would
做播客。他们不是，他们会
maybe release press releases and their
或许会发布新闻稿及其
marketing team would kind of run the
市场营销团队会负责运营……
coms. But there's been this almost big
coms。但一直以来都存在着一种几乎巨大的现象。
shift towards leadership transparency
转向领导层透明度
now where leaders are like expected to
现在，人们期望领导者们……
be glass boxes.
就像玻璃盒子一样。
I think even beyond that media has
我认为，即便抛开媒体本身，也存在着其他问题。
really reshaped to focus on individuals,
真正进行了调整，更加注重个体。
right? Individuals are the are what
正确的？个人就是什么
people are interested in. They're the
人们对此感兴趣。他们是……
ones who have distribution. So I think
拥有分销渠道的人。所以我觉得
that like the the center of gravity has
就像重心一样
shifted away from the entity like the
远离了像……这样的实体
business to focus more on the individual
企业应更加注重个人。
characters, right, and storytellers. So
角色，没错，还有讲故事的人。所以
you went off to university um you went
你去上大学了，嗯，你去了
to Stanford University which is an
斯坦福大学，这是一所
incredible university and you went to
这是一所很棒的大学，而你去了那里。
ultimately try and pursue product design
最终尝试并追求产品设计
at Stanford. Why did you choose product
在斯坦福大学。你为什么选择这款产品
design at that stage in your life? What
你人生那个阶段有从事设计工作的想法吗？什么
was it that was calling you about that
是不是那个人打电话给你谈这件事？
course? Well, what's really cool about
课程？那么，真正酷的是什么呢？
product design is the basic concept is
产品设计的基本概念是
like you don't need to wait around and
比如你不需要闲着等待，
you know wait for an idea to fall out of
你知道，等待灵感迸发。
heaven or get struck by lightning. You
要么上天堂，要么被闪电击中。你
can systematically create new ideas by
能够系统地创造新想法
listening to people, empathizing with
倾听他人，感同身受
them and then basically prototyping
它们，然后基本上就是原型制作
solutions to the problems that they
他们提出的问题的解决方案
share with you and then iterating on
先跟你分享，然后迭代
those solutions by bringing those
通过引入这些解决方案
solutions back to them and saying, "What
把解决方案反馈给他们，并说：“什么？”
do you think? does this solve your
你觉得呢？这能解决你的问题吗？
problem? So for me to be able to combine
问题？所以对我来说，能够结合
um my love of making things with this
嗯，我喜欢用这个制作东西。
process for making things that could be
制造可能存在的事物的过程
useful to people making new products
对制造新产品的人来说很有用
that was really uh exciting to me and
那真的让我很兴奋。
and the product design school was
产品设计学院是
created by a really visionary guy named
由一位名叫……的极具远见的人创建
David Kelly. I had the opportunity to
大卫·凯利。我有机会
take a class from him and it was it was
跟他上课，结果就是这样。
really just uh an incredible experience.
真是一次令人难以置信的体验。
What is product design for someone like
对于像我这样的人来说，产品设计是什么？
someone like me that has no idea what
像我这样完全不知道该怎么做的人
they teach in such a course? Is it cuz
他们会在这样的课程中教授吗？是因为
my head says like designing like
我的脑子里想的是，就像设计一样
physical products or a lot of the
实物产品或很多
product design school at Stanford is
斯坦福大学的产品设计学院是
oriented around physical products of
以实体产品为导向的
course now you know it's so much more uh
当然，现在你知道它远不止如此。
than that but when I when I was there at
比那更甚，但当我在那里的时候
the time and it was under the mechanical
当时正值机械故障时期
engineering department it was very
工程部门非常
oriented around physical products
以实体产品为导向
understanding materials but all part of
理解材料，但这一切都是其中的一部分
this framework of how do we understand
这种理解框架
the problems that people are facing how
人们面临的问题是如何
do we empathize with them and then how
我们是否对他们感同身受，以及我们如何做到这一点。
do we design solutions that solve those
我们是否设计出能够解决这些问题的方案？
problems. Did you learn entrepreneurship
问题。你学过创业吗？
through this time as well? Because I
这段时间也是这样吗？因为我
think in your sophomore year you took a
想想你大二那年你选修了什么
a class on entrepreneurship and venture
一门关于创业和风险投资的课程
capital, right? Yeah, that was that was
资本，对吧？对，就是这样。
really a gamecher. So I that that uh
真是个游戏高手。所以我觉得……
class called entrepreneurship and
一门名为创业学的课程
venture capital and the class is a
风险投资，而这门课是
series of case
一系列病例
studies basically led by entrepreneurs
研究主要由企业家主导
who come in and present the story of
他们进来讲述这个故事
creating their business and lessons
创建他们的业务和课程
learned and then it's an open Q&amp;A. I got
学习结束后，将进行开放式问答环节。我得到了
to listen to their amazing stories and
聆听他们精彩的故事
and ask them questions and and that was
问他们问题，就是这样。
super inspiring to me. Do you remember
对我来说非常鼓舞人心。你是否记得
anything you took away from those
你从那些人身上学到了什么
classes that ended up being really
那些最终真的
important for you in terms of an idea or
对你来说，在想法或方面很重要
a philosophy or anything? I think the
一种哲学理念或其他什么？我认为
biggest thing that I took away from my
我从中得到的最大收获
time at at Stanford and from that class
在斯坦福大学的时光以及那门课程
was the focus on going after really
重点是追求真正
really big opportunities. And I think
巨大的机遇。我觉得
one of the things that's so different
其中一件截然不同的事情
and growing up here in LA, I think a lot
在洛杉矶长大，我觉得很多
of the the business community that I was
我所在的商业界
exposed to is more focused on cash flow,
更注重现金流的因素
right? Like how quickly can this
正确的？比如这能多快？
business turn a profit, you know, how
企业如何盈利，你懂的。
can we do that really predictably? How
我们真的能做到完全可预测吗？如何
much cash are we going to generate? At
我们能赚到多少现金？在
Stanford, the business culture is
斯坦福的商业文化是
entirely oriented around well, how big
完全围绕着“多大”这个问题展开。
is that opportunity? Like is that a huge
那是一个机会吗？那是不是一个巨大的
opportunity? Is that opportunity big
机会？那是一个很大的机会吗？
enough? Because if it if you're not
足够的？因为如果你不是
going after something that could reach
追求能够达到的目标
billions of people, that's not that
数十亿人，那可不是这样。
interesting. Uh and that was a totally
有趣的。呃，那完全
different way of thinking for me
对我来说，这是一种不同的思考方式。
combined with the venture capital
结合风险投资
approach which is really to invest a lot
这种方法实际上需要投入大量资金。
of money early and scale quickly and
尽早投入资金并快速扩大规模
then build out the business later uh
然后稍后再逐步拓展业务。
after you've achieved scale after you've
当你达到规模之后，当你……
achieved mass adoption. I've always
已实现大规模普及。我一直
wondered what they teach at Stanford
我想知道斯坦福大学都教些什么。
especially as it relates to business
尤其是在商业领域。
because the success rate of creating
因为创造的成功率
some of the world's sort of pre-minent
世界上一些最杰出的
entrepreneurs is really really high. So
创业者比例真的非常高。所以
you're telling me one of the key ideas
你正在告诉我一个关键理念。
is big ambitions. Yeah. And and I think
雄心勃勃。是的。而且我认为
it makes sense because it's so hard to
这很合理，因为这太难了
create a business, your odds of success
创建企业，你的成功几率
are so low. So it's really important
太低了。所以这真的很重要
that you go after something really big.
你追求的是非常大的目标。
So that if you're successful that at the
所以，如果你成功了，那么在……
end of the day there there's a huge
一天结束时，那里会有一个巨大的
opportunity at the at the end of the
在最后的机会
rainbow. So my in my head I go, well, if
彩虹。所以，我脑子里想的是，如果
it's really really big, then the chance
它真的很大，然后就是机会。
of failure is probably going to go up.
失败率可能会上升。
So you know, I could open a coffee shop,
所以你知道，我可以开一家咖啡店。
right? And my chance of success is
正确的？我的成功几率是
pretty decent. But if I go after
还不错。但如果我追随
building a new social network, which is
构建一个新的社交网络，即
something only a psychopath would do,
只有精神变态者才会做的事。
then my odds of success are what, one in
那么我成功的几率是多少？百分之一
a gazillion. Yeah. I I I think what is
数不胜数。是的。我想什么是
exciting though about the technology
这项技术令人兴奋
business is the way that it scales. And
商业的本质在于其规模化发展。和
so I think what's different than your
所以我觉得和你的有什么不同呢？
coffee shop example is once you build a
咖啡店的例子就是一旦你建好一个
great service, once once we build
服务很棒，我们建了一次就成功了。
Snapchat one time, it can scale to 850
Snapchat 一次就能扩展到 850
million people around the world, right?
全世界有数百万人，对吧？
Whereas you'd have to go build a new
而你则需要新建一个
coffee shop. uh you know on every on
咖啡馆。呃，你知道，在每个
every street corner to scale the
每个街角都要进行缩放
business. And so once once I think you
商业。所以，有一次，我想你
start seeing the world in terms of the
开始从这个角度看待世界
potential to scale and the potential to
规模化潜力和潜力
build you know a product or service that
打造你所知的产品或服务
can reach billions of people it really
真的可以触及数十亿人吗？
changes you know the opportunities you
改变你了解的机会
identify or the things that you know the
识别或你所知道的事物
services that you want to build.
你想构建的服务。
Interesting. So the question that most
有趣的。所以，大多数人提出的问题
of us especially in the UK we we often
尤其是在英国，我们经常
don't think about building businesses
不要考虑创办企业
that have the potential to reach huge
有可能达到巨大规模
scale.
规模。
um in part because we don't have as much
嗯，部分原因是我们没有那么多。
of a robust I think technical track
我认为这是一个稳健的技术方向
record in terms of building great
在建造伟大建筑方面有着辉煌的记录
unicorn tech companies in Europe as you
欧洲的独角兽科技公司，正如你所说
guys do over here. One of the I mean I
这边的人都这样。其中一个我的意思是……
don't know if we want to go down this
不知道我们是否想走这条路。
path and talk about entrepreneurship in
路径和谈论创业精神
Europe, but I think one of the real
欧洲，但我认为其中一个真正的
challenges in Europe is how small the
欧洲面临的挑战在于其规模之小。
different markets are in each country.
每个国家都有不同的市场。
And so I think what's really interesting
所以我觉得真正有趣的是……
what I when I talk to entrepreneurs in
当我与企业家交谈时，我通常会说：
Europe oftentimes they're very focused
欧洲人往往非常关注
on growing first in their country and
在本国率先发展壮大
using that market as a stepping stone.
把那个市场当作跳板。
But the all the countries in Europe are
但欧洲所有国家都是
quite different. They're different
截然不同。它们不一样
cultures and different languages. And so
不同的文化和语言。所以
sometimes entrepreneurs can spend too
有时创业者会花费过多。
much time trying to grow in Europe
花费大量时间在欧洲发展
rather than what I've seen out of some
而不是我从某些方面看到的。
companies. In Australia, for example,
公司。例如在澳大利亚，
they're on an island. The first thing
他们在一个岛上。第一件事
that these entrepreneurs are thinking
这些企业家正在思考
about is like, how do I go grow in the
大概就是，我该如何成长？
US? How do I go grow in China? How do I
我们？我如何才能在中国发展壮大？我该怎么做？
go grow in a really really big market
在非常非常大的市场中发展壮大
and get to scale really quickly? And
并且能够快速实现规模化？和
then I can go reinvest and grow in
然后我就可以继续投资并实现增长。
Europe or grow in other countries where
欧洲或在其他国家发展
it might be more difficult to to grow.
它可能更难生长。
That is so true. Thinking about my
说得太对了。想着我的
investment portfolio, there's about 40
投资组合中大约有40个项目
different companies there and almost
那里有不同的公司，几乎
every single one of them without without
他们每一个人都没有
really an exception has adopted the
确实，一个例外已经采纳了
approach of we'll crack the UK first and
采取的策略是，我们先攻克英国市场。
then we'll go and figure out the US. But
然后我们再去了解美国的情况。但
in that transition to the US, they
在向美国过渡的过程中，他们
encounter tons of challenges with how
遇到很多挑战
expensive it is to succeed here, like
在这里取得成功的代价是巨大的，就像
marketing costs here, if they're in
这里的营销成本，如果它们存在的话。
retail, how difficult it is to get into
零售业，进入这个行业有多难
Target or Walmart here. Also, the
这里是Target或沃尔玛。此外，
founders end up building their lives,
创始人最终打造了自己的生活，
their families in the UK, which means
他们在英国的家人，这意味着
that the f the founders can't really,
创始人真的做不到这一点。
you know, uproot and and move to the US
你知道，就是举家搬迁到美国。
later in the journey. So, most of them
旅程后期。所以，他们中的大多数
try the US, waste a ton of money, get
去美国试试，浪费一大笔钱，然后……
burnt, run back, and then I've seen that
烧伤了，跑回去，然后我就看到了。
story play over and over again. When you
反复播放故事。当你
think about penetrating these
想想如何渗透这些
international markets, do you send core
国际市场，你们是否发送核心产品
team members there? Often times, what
那里有团队成员吗？通常情况下，什么
we've done with Snapchat is actually
我们对 Snapchat 所做的一切实际上是
follow the growth. So looking for
关注增长。所以正在寻找
countries where people have already
已经有人居住的国家
started using the product, already love
开始使用这款产品，已经爱上了
it, are giving us a bunch of feedback,
它给了我们很多反馈，
and then, you know, we'll send folks
然后，你知道，我们会派人去。
there or we'll figure out how to sort of
要么在那里，要么我们会想办法……
build on the momentum or make sure it's
乘势而上，或者确保……
localized properly, make sure we're
本地化正确，确保我们
working with local creators so that the
与当地创作者合作，以便
content's relevant. But I think, you
内容相关。但我认为，你
know, because our service is based on
了解这一点，因为我们的服务基于
communication, it, you know, Snapchat
沟通，你知道，就是Snapchat
doesn't really work unless you're using
除非你使用……，否则它实际上不起作用。
it with a friend. You got to use it
和朋友一起读。你必须用它
together. uh what we look for is just
一起。呃，我们寻找的只是
that momentum where friends are are
朋友们在一起的那种势头
using it to communicate with one another
用它来相互交流
and then figure out how to build on top
然后思考如何在此基础上进行构建。
of that with the content ecosystem or
与内容生态系统或
augmented reality and those sorts of
增强现实以及类似的技术
things. What was your first idea that
事物。你最初的想法是什么？
failed? Oh my well there there were I
失败的？哦，我的天哪，那里有我
mean I made an orange juicer at one
意思是，我当时做了一个橙汁机
point um but this but um but I think the
嗯，重点是，但是，嗯，但是我认为
biggest the biggest failure was future
最大的失败是未来
freshman Bobby and I I I was really
大一新生鲍比和我，我真的
fortunate to meet Bobby. He lived across
很荣幸能认识鲍比。他住在对面
the hall from me uh at our our
从我这里看大厅，呃，在我们这里
fraternity at at Stanford and we you
斯坦福大学的兄弟会，我们和你
know we shared this love of making
我知道我们都热爱创作。
stuff. So we you know we had kind of
东西。所以你知道，我们当时有点
worked on a couple social ideas that
我曾参与过几个社会议题的讨论。
were interesting but the one thing we
很有趣，但有一件事我们
decided to spend a lot of time on was
决定花大量时间在……上
future freshmen which was designed to
面向未来大一新生，其设计目的是
help kids apply to college. It was
帮助孩子申请大学。那是
something that we'd had direct
这是我们直接拥有的东西
experience with so we could empathize
有过类似的经历，所以我们能够感同身受。
with how difficult the process is. We
这个过程非常困难。我们
had siblings who were also applying to
还有其他兄弟姐妹也在申请
college. So we spent about 18 months
大学。所以我们花了大约18个月的时间。
building like a fullfeatured website.
构建一个功能齐全的网站。
You could select the schools you wanted
您可以选择您想去的学校。
to go to. it would aggregate all the
去。它会将所有内容汇总起来
essay questions and requirements and
论文题目和要求
make it really easy to apply. Um, but it
让申请流程变得非常简单。嗯，但是它
was very clear by the end of that 18
到那18年结束时，这一点已经非常清楚了。
months or so that it was going to be
大约几个月后，它就要发生了。
really difficult for us to to win. We
我们真的很难赢。我们
were up against a company called
我们面对的是一家名为
Naviance which had their own software
Naviance 拥有自己的软件
suite and they had a really good idea
套房，他们有个非常好的想法
which is they went to all the college
也就是说，他们都上了大学。
counselors around the US you know and
你认识的美国各地的咨询师
high schools and things like that and
高中之类的学校
said hey tell everyone to use Naviance
我说，嘿，告诉大家使用 Naviance。
uh make sure your students parents are
呃，确保你的学生的家长是
using our platform and so they got a a
他们使用我们的平台，因此他们获得了一个
lot of distribution through all the
大量分销遍布各地
different schools and so obviously
不同的学校，所以很明显
you're going to use the platform that's
你将使用那个平台。
being recommended by your college
获得大学推荐
counselor not you know an app made by
咨询师，你不知道一个由……开发的应用程序
two kids uh out of Stanford um and so we
两个孩子，呃，从斯坦福大学毕业的，呃，所以我们
had a real distrib contribution
确实做出了分配贡献
disadvantage. And then we also realized
缺点。然后我们也意识到
like even if we were wildly successful
即使我们取得了巨大的成功
and we got, you know, the million
我们拿到了，你知道的，那一百万美元。
students, you know, a year who applied
你知道，就是申请的那一年的学生。
to four-year colleges or, you know,
上四年制大学，或者，你知道的，
something like that, we would have to
类似的事情，我们必须……
then reacquire another million students
然后重新招收另外一百万名学生。
the next year. Uh, and so we sort of had
第二年。呃，所以我们当时就有点……
this uh realization that it was going to
这种意识到它将会
be really hard to build a big uh a big
建造一个大的……真的很难。
business and that we really ought to try
商业，而且我们真的应该尝试
something different and most importantly
与众不同的东西，最重要的是
try to to build something that wouldn't
尝试建造一些不会
take 18 months to build before we got
花了18个月才建成，之后我们才拿到。
great feedback. So to try to build
非常好的反馈。所以，为了尝试构建
something really simple um you know that
一些很简单的事情，嗯，你知道的。
that people could could try and and that
人们可以尝试，而且
we could collect feedback on faster. So
我们可以更快地收集反馈。所以
two points there. How do you know when
这里有两分。你怎么知道什么时候
to quit? You've kind of assembled a
辞职？你已经大致组装好了
couple of principles there but even it's
这里面包含几个原则，但即使是这样也是
I think it's difficult in business
我认为这在商业中很难。
because you can be getting lots of
因为你可以获得很多
negative feedback but that doesn't
负面反馈，但这并不会……
necessarily mean that the idea is
必然意味着这个想法是
something that you should quit. Maybe it
你应该戒掉的东西。或许吧
means you should pivot or iterate or
这意味着你应该调整方向或迭代，或者
just keep going. But how did you know
继续前进。但你怎么知道的？
what were the stars that align that told
是什么样的星象排列预示着这一切？
you to quit that business? I I think for
你打算退出那个行业吗？我认为为了
us it was that we didn't love the
对我们来说，问题在于我们并不爱他/她。
product enough. I think if you really
产品足够。我认为如果你真的
love the product, you you know, and you
你知道，你很喜欢这款产品，而且你
love what you're building, what you're
热爱你正在创造的一切，热爱你所创造的一切。
doing, you can fight through just about
这样做，你几乎可以战胜一切。
anything. I mean, that was really the
任何事物。我的意思是，那真是……
case with the early days of Snapchat. We
以 Snapchat 早期为例。我们
loved uh build, you know, using using
喜欢构建，你知道，使用使用
the product. We were using it all day
该产品。我们整天都在用它。
with our friends. So, we could really we
和朋友们一起。所以，我们真的可以
just had an attachment to it that we
我们只是对它有一种依恋而已。
never, you know, really developed with
从来没有真正发展起来，你知道的。
future freshmen because we weren't
因为我们不是未来的大一新生，所以我们不是
applying to college. So, we didn't have
申请上大学。所以，我们没有
that same, I think, connection with the
我认为，这与……的联系是一样的。
product that we ended up developing with
我们最终开发出的产品
Snapchat. And why does that end up
Snapchat。为什么最终会这样呢？
mattering so much? That like love and
这么重要吗？就像爱一样
passion for the thing that you're
对你所做的事情充满热情
building? Because I think that's what
建筑？因为我觉得就是这样
you know, the love and passion for what
你知道，那种对……的热爱和激情
you're building and the love and passion
你正在建设，以及其中的爱与激情
for the people you're working with, like
对于与你共事的人来说，比如
that's what allows you to get through,
这就是你能够坚持下去的原因。
you know, all the challenges that come
你知道，所有随之而来的挑战
when you try to to to build a business.
当你尝试创办企业时。
I think if you don't love what you're
我认为，如果你不热爱你所做的事情，那你就太糟糕了。
doing, I mean, I just absolutely love
做这件事，我的意思是，我真的非常喜欢
what I do and and the team that we get
我所做的工作以及我们组建的团队
to work with and and of course the the
与……合作，当然还有……
products that we make, the community we
我们生产的产品，我们的社区
serve. And I think without that just
服务。我认为如果没有那一点就……
love for what you do, it's it can be,
热爱你所做的事，就是这样。
you know, it can it can be hard. And you
你知道，这可能会很难。你呢
the other thing you said was you felt
你说的另一件事是，你感觉
that you should go after a business that
你应该去追求一家这样的企业
didn't take like 18 months, like two
没花18个月，大概两个月吧。
years of your time to build before you
你花了数年时间去建设，然后你
got it to market. Why is that for
已成功推向市场。为什么会这样？
entrepreneurs that are listening that
正在收听的企业家们
maybe have spent years perfecting
或许花费数年时间才臻于完美
something in their bedroom that hasn't
他们卧室里有件还没……的东西
gone to market yet? Why was that insight
上市了吗？为什么会有这样的洞察？
so important to you for your next
这对你的下一步至关重要
venture? I think getting that feedback
冒险？我认为获得反馈很重要
from your customers as quickly and early
尽快从您的客户那里获得早期反馈
as possible is critical, even if it's on
尽可能做到最好至关重要，即使它处于……
like the back of a napkin. and like,
就像餐巾纸的背面一样。就像，
"Hey, here's what I'm thinking. This is
“嘿，我是这么想的。这是……”
what it's going to look like." What do
它会是什么样子呢？
you think about that idea? Because it's
你考虑过这个主意吗？因为是
very hard to know whether or not you
很难知道你是否
have a good idea unless you can put
除非你能提出好主意，否则不要轻易放弃。
something in front of people and have
在众人面前展示一些东西，并且拥有
them use it. I mean, that's almost one
让他们使用它。我的意思是，这几乎就是一个
of the cardinal rules of the product
产品的基本规则
design program that you I guess we will
设计程序，我想我们会……
willfully uh ignored, which is that you
故意忽略，那就是你
should really rapidly prototype and get
应该尽快制作原型并完成
feedback as quickly as possible so that
尽快提供反馈，以便
you know you're on the right track. I
你知道你走在正确的道路上。我
mean, even in the early days, you know,
也就是说，即使在早期，你知道，
Snapchat before was called Snapchat was
Snapchat 以前叫做 Snapchat was
called Pickaboo. It was more focused on
名叫 Pickaboo。它更侧重于
disappearing messages. Very quickly we
阅后即焚信息。我们很快就
learned that wasn't interesting to
发现那对他来说并不有趣
people. They wanted to communicate with
人们。他们想与……沟通
pictures. They wanted to talk with
图片。他们想和……交谈
pictures. So when we called the app
图片。所以当我们调用该应用程序时
Snapchat, we explained that it was 10
我们解释说，Snapchat 的意思是 10
times faster than sending a photo via
比通过以下方式发送照片快数倍
text message. People were like, "Oh, I
短信。人们会说：“哦，我
want that. Like that's something that
想要那个。就像那件事一样
I'll use every day." And so it was just
我会每天都用。”就这样，就这么定了。
really interesting to get the feedback
收到反馈真的很有意思。
really really early on, you know, with
非常非常早的时候，你知道，和
the with an initial version of the app
该应用程序的初始版本
that took, you know, a couple months to
那花了，你知道，几个月的时间。
create. I think this is a really
创造。我觉得这真是太棒了
interesting point that a lot of founders
很多创始人都有这样一个有趣的观点
don't realize that even companies like
他们没有意识到，即使是像这样的公司也是如此。
yours, they start with an initial
你的，它们以首字母开头
hypothesis which is nearly always wrong.
几乎总是错误的假设。
But kind of when you hear these stories,
但当你听到这些故事时，你会有点……
you hear like had an idea in my basement
你听着，就像我在地下室里突然冒出一个主意一样。
and then pursued it and then it became a
然后就一直追寻它，然后它就变成了
billion dollar business. But there's
价值数十亿美元的企业。但是还有
something in the like humility and the
类似谦逊之类的品质
realization that your initial idea might
意识到你最初的想法可能
be wild be off and that your job isn't
放纵自己，放松身心，别让你的工作成为负担
to like be right, it is to be successful
正确就是成功。
and they're like two different things,
它们就像两件完全不同的事情。
right? I I totally agree and I think the
正确的？我完全同意，而且我认为
the challenge someone I I think this was
我觉得这是某人提出的挑战。
like one of those Vanity Fair parties a
就像《名利场》杂志举办的那种派对一样
million years ago. The the the souvenir
百万年前。纪念品
was a lighter and like on one side it's
打火机，而且一边是……
like the director is always right and on
就像导演总是对的一样，而且
the other side it's like the customer is
另一方面，就像顾客是
never wrong, you know? And I think like
你知道，我从不出错？我觉得就像
that's like always the interesting
那总是很有趣的。
challenge with a business that you have
你所面临的业务挑战
to stay true to your vision, the reason
为了坚持你的愿景，原因
why you're building a product, your
你为什么要开发产品，你的
philosophy, but at the same time, your
哲学，但同时，你的
customers are the people you serve and
顾客就是你服务的对象。
and ultimately how they feel about your
以及最终他们对你的看法。
product is is right, whether or not you
产品是否正确，无论你是否
agree with it. So, how did you get past
同意。那么，你是如何度过难关的？
um future freshmen to your next
嗯，未来的大一新生们，接下来
business? What was the journey from
商业？这段旅程是从哪里开始的？
there? So, you'd met your co-founder at
那里？所以，你是在……认识你的联合创始人的。
that point, Bobby. And how did you then
鲍比，就是这一点。那你当时是怎么做的呢？
move over to the idea of Snapchat? I
转而考虑使用Snapchat吗？我
think one of the things that was really
我觉得其中一件真正重要的事情是
helpful is that I did a semester a
有帮助的是，我做了一个学期的
quarter abroad uh in Cape Town and I
我在开普敦待了四分之一的海外时间，我
think taking a step back and being there
想想退后一步，置身其中。
sort of gave me perspective about what
这让我对什么有了新的认识
we were working I was working on it
我们当时在工作，我当时也在做这件事。
while I was still working on future
当我还在研究未来的时候
freshman while I was there but it really
我大一的时候在那里，但真的
gave me like more perspective and and I
这让我有了更广阔的视角，而且
think you know I just realized this is
我想你知道，我刚刚意识到这是
going to be really hard and I don't
这会非常困难，我不知道
really love what we're doing we got to
我们真的很喜欢我们正在做的事情，我们必须……
find something else and was that more
找到别的，那岂不是更好？
than anything a feeling you had like a
比任何感觉都更像你曾经有过的那种感觉
feeling of just I'm not enjoying doing
感觉自己根本不享受做这件事。
this every day opening my emails
每天打开邮件都是这样。
thinking about this problem. Yeah. I
思考这个问题。是的。我
think it's so important to listen to
我认为倾听非常重要
those feelings. Yeah.
那些感觉。是的。
Yeah. We were very good at not listening
是的。我们很擅长不去听人说话。
to them. Think because parents and other
对他们来说。想想父母和其他
pressures, right, to continue doing
对，压力迫使我们继续这样做。
something. So then how did you get from
某物。那么你是如何从……
there from being in Cape Town to the
从开普敦到
idea for Snapchat? Well, I came back uh
对 Snapchat 有什么想法吗？嗯，我回来了……
from Cape Town. I moved into um a dorm
来自开普敦。我搬进了宿舍。
at Stanford. One of my buddies who had
在斯坦福大学。我的一个朋友曾经
been Reggie, one of my friends who had
是雷吉，我的一个朋友，他
been living in our fraternity before,
之前就住在我们兄弟会里，
was also in that same dorm. So, we were
我也住在同一栋宿舍楼里。所以，我们当时
hanging out and, you know, one day he
闲逛的时候，你知道，有一天他
was like, "Man, I wish I I could send a
当时我就想，“唉，我真希望我能寄一个
disappearing photo." I was like, "That's
“消失的照片。”我当时想，“那是……”
a super interesting idea." And we looked
一个非常有趣的想法。”然后我们看了看
it up. There were a couple other apps
把它搞定。还有其他几个应用程序
that were doing some similar stuff at
他们当时也在做一些类似的事情
the time. Um, but they were very they
时间。嗯，但他们非常……
were much more like like security
更像是安保人员。
focused. They weren't really focused as
专注。他们当时并没有真正集中精力。
much on on fun, you know? So, that's a
乐趣多多，你知道吗？所以，这就是一个
super interesting idea. And you could
这个想法太棒了。而且你还可以
see really quickly that it it was simple
很快就发现这很简单
enough that we could build it and get
足够我们建造并获得
feedback really quickly, you know, and I
反馈速度很快，你知道的，而且我
I think there were a couple uh important
我认为有几个重要的
design choices uh that we made at the
我们在设计方面做出的选择
time. One was opening to the camera. Um
时间。其中一人正对着镜头张开嘴。嗯
we really wanted to be the, you know,
我们真的很想成为，你知道的，
the the tagline is the fastest way to
标语是最快捷的方式
share a moment. We wanted to be the
分享片刻时光。我们想成为……
fastest way to share a moment. And at
分享精彩瞬间的最快方式。而且
the time, I don't know if you remember,
时间，我不知道你是否还记得，
the iPhone had like a shutter animation.
iPhone 有类似快门动画的效果。
So you would like tap the camera to open
所以你想点击相机打开
it and it would take forever to like
它，而且要花很长时间才能喜欢上它。
open up the camera super slow. Oh, and
超慢速度打开相机。哦，还有
there was a big toggle. You had to
那里有个很大的开关。你必须
choose between the camera and and video,
在相机和视频之间进行选择，
right? So, there's all this friction in
正确的？所以，这里存在着各种各样的摩擦。
in using the camera. So, we decided
在使用相机时。所以，我们决定
we're going to open the camera. We're
我们要打开摄像头。是
going to get rid of that animation and
打算去掉那个动画。
you're going to be able to go straight
你可以直接走。
into capturing what's happening in front
捕捉眼前发生的事情
of you before the moment disappears. So,
趁着这美好瞬间还未消逝，好好珍惜你。所以，
that I think that was a a really
我觉得那真是……
important um choice that we made. And
我们做出的一个重要选择。和
then of course the choice to let people
当然，还有是否允许人们这样做的选择。
choose how long they wanted to let
他们可以选择想要保留多长时间
someone um you know see their snap, but
有人，你知道，看到了他们的Snapchat，但是
with the caveat that you could always
但需要注意的是，你总是可以
take a screenshot. Um and that was
截屏。嗯，那就是
probably one of the most important
或许是最重要的之一
pieces of feedback we got in the initial
我们在最初阶段收到的一些反馈
in in the initial day. So we built the
在第一天。所以我们建造了
prototype of the app. I took it to my
应用程序原型。我把它带到了我的
design class. Here's this new app. It's
设计课。这是个新应用。它是
called Pikaboo. You can set a photo that
名叫皮卡布。你可以设置一张照片，
disappears. You know, this is really
消失了。你知道，这真是
different than social media. Social
与社交媒体不同。社会的
media is all about permanence and you're
媒体的本质在于永恒，而你
trying to look popular and collect all
试图显得受欢迎并收集所有
these likes and comments and pretty
这些点赞、评论和漂亮的
pictures. You know, that's the 1% of
图片。你知道，那是1%的人。
moments in your life. And here's
你生命中的重要时刻。这就是
Snapchat. This is or Peek-ab-oo at the
Snapchat。这是或偷看
time. Here's Peek-ab-oo. This is for the
时间。这是 Peek-ab-oo。这是为了
other 99%. Right? All the other moments
其余99%。正确的？所有其他时刻
that you might be embarrassed to post to
你可能不好意思发帖
all your friends, but that you want to
你所有的朋友，但你想要的
share with your best friend or, you
和你的好朋友分享，或者，你
know, your family. Um, everyone's like,
认识你的家人。嗯，大家都是这么说的。
"This is never going to work because you
“这永远行不通，因为你
can always take a screenshot. This makes
可以随时截屏。这使得
no sense." So, it it doesn't go away.
毫无道理。”所以，它不会消失。
You can take a screenshot. And I think
你可以截屏。我觉得
one of the the big inventions and that's
其中一项重大发明就是
why I think it's so important to get
为什么我认为获得它如此重要
this feedback. One of the big inventions
这条反馈。其中一项重大发明
that we made uh at that later that
我们后来也做了那个。
summer when Bobby and I were working out
那年夏天，我和鲍比一起健身。
at my dad's house, we invented a way to
在我爸爸家，我们发明了一种方法
detect if someone had taken a
检测是否有人拿走了
screenshot. And so we would send a
截屏。因此，我们会发送一份
little notification back that said,
几乎没有收到任何回复。
"Hey, you know, your friend took a
“嘿，你知道吗，你的朋友拿走了……”
screenshot." And I think that was part
截图。” 我觉得那是一部分
of what made the service fun that, you
是什么让这项服务变得有趣呢？
know, you could set how long it would uh
你知道，你可以设置它持续多长时间……
appear for your friend, but if they
为你的朋友露面，但如果他们
wanted to save it, they could take a
想要拯救它，他们可以采取
screenshot, but you would know that they
截图，但你会知道他们
saved it. And I think that was one of
已保存。我认为那是其中之一
sort of the early uh feedback loops of
早期反馈回路的某种形式
the product that helped, you know, make
你知道，这款产品帮助了……
people feel comfortable using it for
人们觉得使用它很方便
picture messaging. How long was that
图片短信。那段时间有多长？
journey between you having that
你们之间的旅程
conversation with Reggie about wanting
与雷吉谈论想要什么
photos to disappear and the moment when
照片消失的那一刻
you knew Snapchat was going to be a big
你知道 Snapchat 会大火。
deal? like how how long is that gap?
交易？这个差距到底有多大？
I would say it took until maybe
我觉得大概花了这么长时间。
um certainly the following school year
嗯，当然是指下一个学年。
for me. So over that summer, Bobby and I
为我。所以那年夏天，我和鲍比
went to my dad's house, worked a lot uh
去了我爸家，干了很多活儿……
on the service, renamed it Snapchat, got
该服务更名为 Snapchat，并获得了
a lot of feedback when we were using it
我们在使用它的时候收到了很多反馈。
with our friends, everyone wanted like,
和朋友们在一起时，每个人都想这样，
"Hey, can I add a caption? Can I add,
“嘿，我可以加个标题吗？我可以加，
you know, can I draw on it?" Because in
你知道，我可以在上面作画吗？因为在
the original version, it was just a
原版只是一个
photo. Um, but because people were, you
照片。嗯，但因为人们是那样，你
know, using just our friend group using
知道，我们只是利用我们的朋友圈来使用
it to to communicate, we needed to add
为了进行沟通，我们需要添加
things like captions and and drawing.
比如配图说明和绘画。
So, I think the Snapchat launched in the
所以，我认为Snapchat是在……推出的。
app store about September of 2011. And
应用商店大约在 2011 年 9 月上线。
it probably wasn't until late that fall,
可能要到那年秋末才发生。
maybe or even into into the following
或许，甚至进入以下状态
beginning of 2012 that I was I remember
我记得2012年初的时候。
sitting in the back of my classroom. And
坐在教室后排。和
we had a a snap counter that would count
我们有一个可以计数的计数器。
the total number of snaps ever sent, you
你发送过的快照总数。
know, and in the early days it was like
我知道，在早期就是这样。
hundreds or a thousand or whatever. um
几百、几千，或者更多。嗯
and you'd you know I'd refresh the page
你知道我会刷新页面
and it wouldn't the number wouldn't
而且这个数字不会
change you know but by that time by you
你知道，改变是可以的，但到那时，你已经……
know the beginning of 2012 every time I
每次我想起2012年初，我都会想起这件事。
refreshed the snap counter page you know
刷新一下快照计数器页面，你知道的。
the number would go up and it would jump
数字会上升，而且会猛烈跳动。
by one or two or 10 so it was clear that
一两个，或者十个，所以很明显
people were using the service and and
人们正在使用这项服务，而且
communicating and that's when I was like
沟通的时候，我就觉得……
ah this is this is fun you know not only
啊，这真有趣，你知道，不仅如此。
are we loving it with our friends but
我们和朋友们在一起很开心吗？
there's more people using it too one of
使用它的人也越来越多了。
the things you said there is that you
你刚才说的那些话是……
were using people around you your
我们正在利用你周围的人
friends to give you feedback on what
让朋友们给你反馈什么
features you should add next you said
您说接下来应该添加哪些功能？
people wanted to write on and they
人们想继续写下去，他们
wanted to add
想补充
captions. As a founder, that must be
图片说明。作为创始人，这必须是
quite hard because you're getting lots
相当难，因为你要面对很多问题。
of feedback to change lots of things all
反馈意见可以改变很多事情
the time. How do you know what to filter
时间。如何知道要过滤什么
as good feedback that you'll implement
你会采纳的良好反馈
versus a distraction or bad feedback? Is
是干扰还是负面反馈？是
there a framework at all that you have
你根本没有任何框架。
you've had to deploy? So, I think all
你必须部署吗？所以，我认为所有
feedback is good feedback. All feedback
反馈是好的反馈。所有反馈
is valuable. I think what you do with it
很有价值。我认为你如何处理它
is what matters. So, for example, let's
这才是最重要的。例如，我们来……
take the use of the the caption tool for
使用字幕工具
example. You know, we could have added a
例子。你知道，我们本来可以添加一个
super clunky caption tool that took
超级笨拙的字幕工具，花了很长时间
forever to use that was like, you know,
永远使用它就像，你知道的，
like social media where you add the
就像社交媒体一样，你可以在上面添加内容
caption at the bottom of the photo and
照片底部的说明文字和
tap it and hashtag stuff. The way that
点击它并添加话题标签。方式
we decided to implement captions to make
我们决定添加字幕来制作
it easier for people to communicate is
便于人们沟通是
all you have to do is tap on the photo
你只需要点击照片即可。
right after you took it. So, you'd snap
你刚拿完之后。所以，你会猛然惊醒
take the photo, tap, the keyboard would
拍照，点击，键盘就会
pop up. there was a little caption bar,
弹出窗口。有一个小小的字幕栏，
you know, the caption bar uh well, you
你知道，字幕栏，嗯，你
know, that still allowed you to see the
要知道，那仍然能让你看到……
photo behind it instead of it being sort
后面是一张照片，而不是某种东西
of attached to the photo below it. It
附在下方照片上。它
was right on top of the photo. And then
就在照片的正上方。进而
as soon as you hit enter, you could, you
你一按下回车键，就可以……
know, jump to the page where you select
知道了，跳转到你选择的页面
uh which friends you wanted to send it
呃，你想把它发给哪些朋友？
to. So I think, you know, what was more
到。所以我觉得，你知道，更重要的是
important than hearing feedback of, hey,
比听到诸如“嘿，
I I want a way to, you know, add a
我想要一种方法来添加一个
caption or express more in the snap. The
添加文字说明或在照片中表达更多内容。这
way that we implemented that feedback
我们落实反馈的方式
and designed something really fast and
然后很快就设计出了一些东西
easy to use is why that black bar
易于使用就是那条黑条的原因。
caption is you know now I think
标题是“你现在知道了”，我想
synonymous with Snapchat and and is like
与 Snapchat 同义，并且就像
you know well well well known around
你很清楚，大家都知道。
around the world. So it was a year from
遍布世界各地。所以那是一年之后的事了。
the idea to the day when you raised
从你提出这个想法的那一天起
capital for the first time roughly. Yeah
首次获得资金，大致如此。是的
more or less. And talk me through that.
或多或少。请你详细地给我讲解一下。
So how much did you raise about raising
那么，你们筹集了多少资金？
the capital and what was the business
资本以及业务内容
like at that time in terms of users and
就像当时的用户数量和
downloads? Yeah, I I don't remember the
下载？是的，我不记得了。
exact uh sort of user statistics, but
确切的用户统计数据，但是
what was really really helpful is that
真正有帮助的是……
we had about a a year of data. So, if
我们有大约一年的数据。所以，如果
you remember back then there were a lot
你还记得那时候有很多吗？
of apps that were sort of like a a flash
一些类似 Flash 的应用程序
in the pan, like they would get popular
在平底锅里，就像它们会流行起来一样
really really quickly and then sort of
非常非常快，然后就有点
fade away. And so, venture investors
渐渐消失。因此，风险投资者
would kind of jump into these apps and
会一下子就投入到这些应用程序中，
then the apps would get really popular
那样一来，这些应用就会变得非常流行。
and then kind of fade. And so when we
然后就渐渐消失了。所以当我们
were raising money, one of the things
筹款是其中一件事。
that really helped us is we had a year's
真正帮助我们的是，我们有一年的时间……
worth of data to basically show, hey,
大量数据基本上是为了说明，嘿，
when people start using this product to
当人们开始使用这款产品时
talk to their friends, they keep doing
他们和朋友们聊天，他们继续这样做
it because it's really fun and it's
因为它真的很有趣，而且
better than text message based
比基于短信的更好
communication. Visual communication is
沟通。视觉传达是
way more fun, more powerful, more
更有趣、更强大、更多
expressive than textbased communication.
比文字交流更具表现力。
And you know, people use it consistently
你知道，人们一直在使用它。
once they learn how. Um, and that was
一旦他们学会了。嗯，那就是
really important to the investors who
对投资者来说，这一点非常重要。
were worried is this, you know, just
我们担心的是，你知道，这只是
another flash in the pan type service.
又一个昙花一现的服务。
Um, so, so we really just led I think we
嗯，所以，所以我觉得我们真的只是领先而已
had like three maybe five slides of just
大概只有三五张幻灯片吧。
the data. Um, do you remember feedback
数据。嗯，你还记得反馈吗？
you got from investors at that early
你早期从投资者那里得到了什么
stage? I think this is important because
阶段？我认为这很重要，因为
all founders are going to get the email
所有创始人都会收到这封邮件。
that tells them that they're not on to
这告诉他们，他们还没找到方向。
something. Yeah, I think the biggest
某物。是的，我认为最大的
piece of feedback was just like, hey,
一条反馈意见就像是：嘿，
this seems like something that these
这似乎是这些事情
really big powerful tech companies are
真正强大的大型科技公司是
just going to copy and um, you know,
就复制一下，嗯，你知道的。
it's they're really tough to compete
他们真的很难对付。
with. So, you know, we we're not really
和。所以，你知道，我们其实并不是
sure we want to invest in something
当然，我们想投资一些东西。
that's going up against these really
那可是要跟这些家伙对抗啊
really big powerful tech companies. I
规模庞大、实力雄厚的科技公司。我
mean, there's some wisdom in that.
也就是说，这其中确实蕴含着一些智慧。
Certainly a lot of foresight in that
这其中确实蕴含着很多远见卓识。
one. Yeah. Because the odds anyway of
一。是的。因为无论如何，概率都很高。
building a a social networking app are
构建社交网络应用程序
extremely low. It's we were saying
极低。我们刚才说的就是这个。
before we started recording that you've
在我们开始录音之前，你已经……
got to be almost like delusional to
这几乎等同于妄想症。
think that you can. I think at that time
你认为自己可以。我想那时候
too, you know, Snapchat came last after
而且，你知道，Snapchat是最后才出现的。
Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, like you
Facebook、Twitter、Instagram，就像你一样。
name it. All of those services had come
说出它的名字。所有这些服务都已到来
first. And so I think the idea that
第一的。所以我认为这个想法是
like, you know, and that was still at
你知道，那时候还是这样。
the time when people believed that
人们相信这一点的时代
network effects meant that you couldn't
网络效应意味着你不能
compete, right? Whoever has the biggest
对吧？谁拥有的最大
biggest network is going to win. No one
最大的电视网将会获胜。没有人
else is going to be able to compete. And
否则就无法与之竞争。和
so I think there was that concern that,
所以我认为当时存在这样的担忧：
you know, oh, if these other competitors
你知道，哦，如果这些其他竞争对手
are much bigger and they have network
它们规模更大，而且它们拥有网络
effects, how are you ever going to grow
影响，你到底要怎么成长
uh grow and and compete? So that was a
呃，发展壮大并参与竞争？所以，那是……
big piece of feedback. And then I think
非常重要的反馈。然后我想
there was just a whole other group of
还有另一整整一群人
people who didn't really understand what
那些不太了解情况的人
the service was um and so weren't that
服务嘛，嗯，那也不是。
interested. But Jeremy at Lightseed
感兴趣的。但 Lightseed 的 Jeremy
reached out. He had his profile picture
已联系。他有自己的头像。
was a photo of him with Obama. Uh and I
那是一张他和奥巴马的合影。呃，还有我
was like, "Oh, okay. Must be like a real
当时我就想，“哦，好吧。肯定像真的一样。”
you." Now with AI, you never know. But
你。”如今有了人工智能，一切皆有可能。但是
but back then I was like, "Okay, must be
但当时我想，“好吧，一定是这样。”
legit." So we met up with them and and
合法的。”于是我们和他们见了面，然后
one of his partners that uh I guess his
他的其中一位合伙人，呃，我猜是他的
daughter used Snapchat and loves
女儿使用Snapchat，而且很喜欢。
Snapchat and so they understood the
所以他们理解了Snapchat
service and what it was about and how
服务及其内容和方式
she was using with her friends and so
她和朋友们一起用，所以
they ended up investing
他们最终投资了。
$485,000 at a $4.25 million valuation.
售价 48.5 万美元，估值 425 万美元。
What a deal in hindsight. How
事后看来，这真是一笔划算的买卖。如何
many users did you have at the time when
当时你有多少用户？
you raised that capital? Uh I would have
你筹集到资金了吗？呃，我本来会……
guess about a h 100,000 or something
猜大概10万小时左右吧
like that. And the valuation was $4
就是这样。估值是 4 美元
million roughly. 4.25. Yeah. In that
大约一百万。 4.25。是的。在那
first year up until the point that you
第一年直到你
raised that money, did you ever doubt
筹集到这笔钱后，你是否曾怀疑过？
that Snapchat was going to work? And I
Snapchat真的会成功吗？我
guess to understand the question a bit
我猜想大概能理解这个问题。
more, you almost have to add
此外，你几乎必须加上
a goal or ambition to it. So, I'm
实现目标或抱负。所以，我是
presuming you wanted it to be and
假设你希望它是这样的，
thought it could be a company. Did you
我以为它是一家公司。你……
ever doubt that it would be? Was there
你曾怀疑过它会是真的吗？有吗？
anything that ever happened in that
那段时间发生的一切
first year?
一年级？
There was one moment where we
曾有那么一刻，我们
accidentally took down the Snapchat
不小心把Snapchat账号注销了
infrastructure for three days. So the
基础设施需运行三天。所以
service stopped working entirely for
服务已完全停止运行
three days. Actually it something broke
三天。实际上，是什么东西坏了。
and it took us three days to fix it. And
我们花了三天时间才修好。和
we were like we're we're done. I mean
我们当时就想，我们完了。我是说
what are we going to do? You know uh the
我们该怎么办？你知道，呃……
service has been down for three days.
服务已中断三天。
It's a messaging service you know. Uh so
你知道，它是一款即时通讯服务。呃，所以
people haven't been able to talk to
人们一直无法交谈
their friends like is anyone going to
他们的朋友会问：有人要去吗？
use it? Um, and when we turned it back
用它吗？嗯，当我们把它转回来的时候
on, people just started using it again.
然后，人们又开始使用它了。
And that gave us a lot more conviction
这让我们更加确信这一点。
and that, you know, we had a product
而且，你知道，我们当时有一个产品
that people really just loved using. How
人们真的很喜欢用它。如何
and why was it growing? Was it a
它为什么会生长？是吗？
marketing campaign or was it organic?
这是营销活动的结果，还是自然而然形成的？
The only thing that we ever saw work
我们唯一见过有效的方法。
was, you know, friends using it with
你知道，朋友们都在用它。
friends, telling their friends about it
朋友们，告诉他们的朋友这件事
and wanting to, you know, learn how to
并且想要学习如何
use it because communicating with photos
使用它是因为可以用照片交流
was a new thing. I mean people were
这是一件新鲜事。我的意思是，人们是
hadn't been talking with pictures before
之前从未用图片交流过
and even the way people thought about
甚至人们思考问题的方式
photos it was like a photo is for saving
照片就像是用来保存的一样
a precious moment right like that's or
那一刻弥足珍贵，就那样。
like a family photo like that's really
就像那样的全家福照片
how people were thinking about photos at
人们当时是如何看待照片的
the time you weren't able like that was
你当时无法那样做的那段时间是
just coming out of the digital camera
刚从数码相机里出来
like plug it into your computer and
就像把它插到电脑上一样
upload the photos era. So there was this
上传照片的时代。所以就有了这件事。
massive, I think, behavioral change of
我认为，这会带来巨大的行为改变。
people realizing like, wow, like no, a
人们意识到，哇，不，这
picture is worth a thousand words. And
一张图胜过千言万语。和
now that I can take it instantly on my
现在我可以立即把它带回家了
phone and and send it with my friend in,
用手机发给我的朋友，
you know, uh, a couple hundred
你知道，呃，几百个
milliseconds, like we can talk with
毫秒级，就像我们可以用它说话一样
pictures and instead of just use
图片，而不仅仅是使用
pictures to save memories. I don't think
用照片保存回忆。我不认为
we really remember that. Isn't that
我们真的记得这件事。难道不是吗？
crazy that we don't remember? It wasn't
太疯狂了，我们竟然不记得了？并非如此
that long ago. I know, but we just don't
很久以前。我知道，但我们就是不这么做。
remember. Like, as you were saying, I
记住。就像你刚才说的那样，我
was like, Yeah, you couldn't like
当时我就想，卧槽。是的，你不能喜欢
send a photo to your friend to talk.
发张照片给朋友聊天。
Yeah. I was like I was trying to think
是的。我当时就像在努力思考一样。
of the app that I could have used back
我本来可以用那个应用程序的
then to do that and there just like
然后去做这件事，就像
isn't one. Yeah. But now I'm dating
不是其中之一。是的。但我现在正在约会
myself, you know. It's terrible.
我自己，你知道的。太糟糕了。
No, that's crazy. We We forget that
不，这太疯狂了。我们忘记了这一点
because it's so common place now on
因为现在这种情况太常见了
every app. You You can And I guess they
每个应用。你可以，我想他们
they ultimately got that from you.
他们最终是从你那里得到的。
Copied that from you. I've got this
是从你那里复制的。我明白了
photo um from the early days. Do you
早期的照片。你
remember this photo? Oh, this is
你还记得这张照片吗？哦，这是
awesome. This picture is great. What is
惊人的。这张照片真棒。什么是
this picture? Where are you? What are
这张照片？你在哪里？什么是
you doing? Who is that? Well, this was
你在做什么？那是谁？嗯，这是
actually our first office, which was
实际上，我们的第一个办公室是
great. It was called the Blue House in
伟大的。它被称为青瓦台
Venice, 523 Oceanfront Walk. And
威尼斯，海滨步道 523 号。和
actually, you know, things sort of uh
实际上，你知道，事情有点……
had had reached a breaking point at my
当时我已经到了崩溃的边缘。
dad's house. I think there were seven or
爸爸的家。我想应该有七个吧
eight of us living there. You know, one
我们八个人住在那里。你知道，一个
one night, his girlfriend at the time,
一天晚上，他当时的女朋友
now wife, came in and one of, you know,
现在，我妻子进来了，其中一个，你知道的，
one of our teammates was like sleeping
我们队里有个队友好像睡着了。
on the couch with a blanket she had
她躺在沙发上，身上盖着一条毯子。
bought him for Christmas and she was
她给他买了份圣诞礼物，她
just like, I think there's like we've
就像，我觉得就像我们已经……
had enough here. So, we we had to get an
受够了。所以，我们不得不弄一个
office uh and and move out. And we were
办公室呃，然后搬出去。我们当时
going to dinner in Venice and we walked
去威尼斯吃晚饭，我们散步
past this old blue house and it had a
穿过那栋老旧的蓝色房子，它有一个
four lease sign on it. We were like,
上面有四份租赁合同。我们当时就想，
"Wow, this would be wild. We could have
“哇，这太疯狂了。我们本来可以……”
an office on the beach on the Venice
威尼斯海滩上的一间办公室
boardwalk." Um, let's let's call them.
木板路。”嗯，我们还是给他们打电话吧。
And we called them. They wanted a crazy
我们给他们打了电话。他们想要一个疯子
amount per square foot in rent. We
每平方英尺租金金额。我们
couldn't afford at the time, but we
当时负担不起，但是我们
ultimately waited uh a bit longer and
最后还是等了一会儿。
and were able to to negotiate that down
并成功协商降低了价格。
quite a bit and moved in to the Blue
相当多，然后搬进了蓝色区域。
House. And I think the best thing about
房子。我觉得最棒的一点是
the Blue House was that the the Venice
蓝房子就是威尼斯
Boardwalk is one of the most popular
木板路是最受欢迎的步道之一
destination tourist destinations in the
旅游目的地
in California, maybe even in the world.
在加利福尼亚州，甚至可能是在全世界。
I mean, it's more than 10 million people
我的意思是，人数超过1000万。
a year come to the Venice Boardwalk. And
每年都来威尼斯海滩木板路。和
we had a big ghost logo, our big app
我们有一个很大的幽灵标志，我们的大型应用程序
icon outside and all day long people
外面的图标和整天的人们
would come up and talk to us about the
会走过来和我们谈论……
app or give us feedback or need help
应用程序或给我们反馈或需要帮助
with their account. And so we were just
使用他们的账户。于是，我们就……
immersed in people from all over the
沉浸在来自世界各地的人们之中
world who were using Snapchat and wanted
全世界使用 Snapchat 并想要
to come talk to us about it. ult
来和我们谈谈这件事。终极
ultimately became like a little too
最终变得有点像太……
much. But in the beginning in the
很多。但最初在
beginning uh it was just so amazing to
一开始真是太棒了
be right there on the boardwalk uh with
就在木板路上，呃，和
so many people. And so how many people
很多人。那么，有多少人？
could fit into the blue house? I think
能住进那栋蓝色房子里吗？我认为
you know at max capacity it was 20
你知道，最大容量是20。
something. I think we were 20some people
某物。我想我们当时大概有二十来个人。
by the time we moved out. Maybe 30. It
在我们搬出去的时候。或许30岁。
was pretty cra I mean I was playing
挺糟糕的，我是说我当时在玩游戏。
footsie with you know people under the
和你知道的人玩脚趾游戏
under the table. We were pretty
在桌子底下。我们当时很漂亮
smooshed. And how many users did you
压扁了。你有多少用户？
have at that time for people to be
那时人们有理由……
coming up on the broadwalk and having
沿着木板路走来，然后……
conversations? You must have been pretty
对话？你一定很漂亮
popular at that point. It must have been
当时很受欢迎。那一定是
millions, I would have I would guess.
我猜想，应该有数百万美元。
Yeah. And you've dropped out of
是的。你已经辍学了
university by that point, obviously.
显然，那时他已经是大学学生了。
Yeah. Tell me about that decision
是的。请告诉我关于那个决定的事。
because that's not I know the app's
因为我知道这个应用程序的
growing and everything, but to drop out
发展等等一切，但要辍学
of a prestigious university can't be a
一所著名大学的毕业生不可能是
super easy decision.
很容易做出决定。
I I really felt I had no choice. I
我当时真的觉得我别无选择。我
didn't have enough credits to graduate.
学分不够，无法毕业。
I mean, I you know, I was doing the I
我的意思是，你知道，我当时正在做我
was doing the product design program,
当时正在学习产品设计课程。
the engineering program. I had a lot
工程专业。我有很多
more classes that I had to to finish and
我还有更多课程要完成。
ultimately we'd raised $485,000
最终我们筹集到了48.5万美元。
uh from investors and you know I was
呃，来自投资者，你知道我当时
spending all day trying to pass these
整天都在尝试通过这些考试
you know I was taking I think 20 credits
你知道我当时好像修了20个学分。
at the time or something uh and trying
当时或者类似的时候，呃，尝试
to trying to work on our business. I
努力发展我们的业务。我
just couldn't do both at the same time.
我不可能同时做到这两件事。
So I was like you know hopefully one day
所以我就想，希望有一天……
I'll be able to go back. I actually did
我还能回去。我确实这么做了
end up going back and got my degree in
最后我还是回去拿到了学位。
2018 which was awesome. Um and uh but um
2018年真是太棒了。嗯，呃，但是嗯
I just couldn't do both at the same
我实在无法同时做这两件事。
time. Why did you go back and get your
时间。你为什么回去拿你的
degree? I really did not want to have
程度？我真的不想有
that debate with our kids where they're
和孩子们讨论这个问题，他们
like, you know what I mean? Where
你明白我的意思吗？在哪里
they're like, but dad, like you, you
他们会说，但是爸爸，就像你一样，你
know what I mean? Like, you you didn't
你明白我的意思吗？比如，你没有
you dropped out. You don't have a
你辍学了。你没有
degree. Like, why do I need one? You
程度。我为什么需要一个？你
know, I I think colleges can can be
我知道，我认为大学可以
really valuable. It's not for everybody,
非常有价值。它并不适合所有人。
but it made a huge impact in in my life.
但这对我的生活产生了巨大的影响。
So, I wanted to be able to, you know,
所以，我希望能够，你知道，
show how important that is to our to our
展现这对我们的重要性
kids. I was thinking earlier when we
孩子们。我之前在想，当我们
were talking about college
我们在谈论大学。
university the world was different when
大学时的世界与现在截然不同。
you went to university and college and
你上了大学和学院，
you've got these four boys now the
你现在有这四个男孩了。
oldest I think is 14 years
我觉得最大的也14岁了。
old if he wants to be like dad say he
如果他想像爸爸那样，那就老实说吧
wanted to follow in your footsteps is
想追随你的脚步是
there anything else based on how the
还有其他基于以下情况的因素吗？
world is currently that you'd be
世界现状是，你将……
advising him to learn before the age of
建议他在几岁之前学习
like 21 is are there any topics or
比如21，有没有什么话题？
degrees that you would be pushing him
你会把他推到那种程度
towards now if he wanted to be like dad
如果他现在想成为像爸爸那样的人，那就得看他自己的选择了。
if that was his decision
如果那是他的决定
I think one of the most important things
我认为最重要的事情之一
today is really nurturing creativity. I
如今正是培养创造力的好时机。我
mean, I think creativity is really the
我的意思是，我认为创造力真的是
the X factor, certainly in the age of
X因素，尤其是在当今时代
AI, right? And so, I think nurturing
人工智能，对吧？所以，我认为培育
creativity, finding ways to develop
创造力，寻找发展途径
those skills. For example, Flynn who's
这些技能。例如，弗林，他是
14, he loves drawing. He's unbelievably
14岁，他喜欢画画。他简直不可思议
talented at drawing. And I think
擅长绘画。我觉得
sometimes he's like, well, I don't know
有时候他会说，嗯，我不知道。
if there's a career in drawing, but I
如果绘画能成为一种职业，但我
think sometimes he doesn't see that
有时候我觉得他没意识到这一点。
drawing is just the way that he's
画画就是他的一种方式
expressing creativity. drawing is the
表达创造力。绘画是
beginning of that journey of exercising
那段锻炼之旅的开始
those muscles in your brain that allow
大脑中那些允许你活动的肌肉
you to visualize something that other
让你想象其他事物
people don't see. Right? And and that's
人们看不见。正确的？就这样。
one way that's one tool, one skill he
一种方法就是用一种工具，一种技能。
can use to express what's in his in his
可以用来表达他内心的想法
brain. But I think exercising that that
脑。但我认为练习一下
muscle, that creativity is so important.
肌肉，以及创造力，都非常重要。
I think creativity is just becoming more
我认为创造力正变得越来越强。
and more rare ultimately because so much
而且最终会变得更加罕见，因为太多了
of our society is oriented around things
我们的社会以事物为中心。
we can measure. creativity is so hard to
我们可以测量。创造力是如此难以培养。
measure and so I think it can be really
衡量一下，所以我认为它真的可以做到
tough um you know to to find the the
很难，你知道，要找到
dedication to invest in developing
致力于投资发展
creativity when it's uncertain what the
当不确定未来走向时，创造力
outcome is. Um but that that's really
结果是。嗯，但那真的
what I would encourage him or so many so
我会鼓励他，或者说，我会鼓励很多人。
many people to do. We're all born
很多人要做这件事。我们生而为人。
creative. We're all you know we're all
有创造力的。我们就是你们都知道的我们都是
born with this ability to express
天生就具备这种表达能力
ourselves. And it's only over time I
我们自己。随着时间的推移，我才意识到这一点。
think that we stop you know practicing
想想我们停止练习吧
that ability or you know uh or we become
那种能力，或者你知道，呃，或者我们变成
fearful of expressing ourselves. And and
害怕表达自己。而且
I think that that can be overcome
我认为这个问题是可以克服的。
because we think through job titles at
因为我们会仔细考虑职位名称。
that age, don't we? We think what's the
我们都到了那个年纪，对吧？我们认为什么是
job title that I should be aiming at. So
我应该努力争取的职位。所以
doctor, lawyer, etc. versus we don't
医生、律师等等，而我们没有
necessarily think as much about
不必过多考虑
collecting useful long-term skills. I'd
积累有用的长期技能。 ID
say I've got a my girlfriend's little
假设我有一个我女朋友的小
brother now who's like racking his brain
哥哥现在正绞尽脑汁地想着呢。
trying to pick a job title for the next
正在为下一个职位挑选职位名称
like 60 years of his life. I'm like, it
就像他生命中的60年。我当时就想，它
doesn't work like that, you know? And
事情不是那样运作的，你知道吗？和
the world is changing so quickly now as
世界变化如此之快，如今
well. It's probably makes more sense to
出色地。这样做可能更有意义
try and get some fundamental skills that
尝试掌握一些基本技能
will translate. Plus, job titles are
将会翻译。此外，职位名称是
totally ridiculous. Anyways, in the in
简直荒谬至极。总之，在
the early days, we would just make up
早期，我们只能凭空捏造。
anyone who joined the team, we would
任何加入团队的人，我们都会
just make up their uh their title. It
随便编造一下他们的头衔。它
would have nothing to do with anything.
与任何事都无关。
Yeah. Um so job titles are ridiculous
是的。嗯，所以职位名称都很荒谬。
when the team is small, right? Just in
团队规模小的时候就是这样，对吧？最新消息
general, right? Because I think people
将军，对吧？因为我认为人们
anchor to job titles to confer confer
将职位名称与授予联系起来
status, right? And I think ultimately
地位，对吧？而且我认为最终
like amazing impact, creativity, great
比如惊人的影响力、创造力、伟大
ideas come from anywhere, right? And the
灵感可以来自任何地方，对吧？以及
more that you focus your organization
你越专注于你的组织
around hierarchy, I think the less
关于层级结构，我认为越少越好。
you're focusing on the right things,
你关注的事情是对的。
which are how are we making sure great
我们如何确保优秀
ideas are coming from anywhere, getting
想法可以来自任何地方，获取
surfaced, you know, and um being built.
浮出水面，你知道，而且正在建设中。
But hierarchy comes into place when
但当等级制度出现时，它就发挥作用了。
things start to get big and we need to
事情开始变得复杂，我们需要……
put processes and reporting lines in
将流程和汇报关系纳入其中
place. How do you defend against that?
地方。如何防范这种情况？
Well, I I think you're getting at like
嗯，我觉得你想表达的是……
the fundamental problem that all
所有问题的根本问题都在于
companies end up having and I I think
公司最终都会拥有，而且我认为
there's there's a great book called
有一本很棒的书，叫做
Loonshots which I really love that
我非常喜欢 Loonshots。
actually gets at this issue directly and
实际上，它直接切入了这个问题。
and
和
basically what the author Safi Beall
基本上，作者萨菲·比尔（Safi Beall）
found was essentially that very big
发现的基本上就是这么大
companies you know once they get a lot
你知道，一旦公司发展壮大，他们就会积累大量财富。
larger they have a lot of customers to
规模越大，他们的客户就越多。
serve they need to build all this
他们需要建造这一切
organizational infrastructure and
组织架构和
ultimately that comes with hierarchy but
归根结底，这都与等级制度有关。
the ones that continue to innovate that
那些不断创新的公司
are very successful at innovating
在创新方面非常成功
consistently over long periods of time
长期持续
also have very small, very flat teams
团队规模也很小，层级很扁平。
that don't have any hierarchy at all
完全没有任何层级结构的
that are really, really focused on
真正专注于
innovating and on trying new things. And
勇于创新，乐于尝试新事物。和
ultimately, the companies that are
最终，那些公司
really successful find a way to build a
真正成功的人会找到一种方法来建立
relationship between the huge
巨大的关系
organization that is supporting all
支持所有组织的机构
these customers and needs to be
这些客户需要
operationally rigorous and metrics
操作严格且指标
focused. Builds a relationship between
专注。建立关系
them and this very small group of people
他们和这极少数人
who are trying crazy things. And he
他们正在尝试一些疯狂的事情。而他
gives a lot of examples. You know, one
列举了很多例子。你知道，一个
of the ways that the United States was
美国的方式之一是
able to win World War II, they had these
他们有能力赢得第二次世界大战，他们拥有这些
crazy group of scientists that were
一群疯狂的科学家
trying new things like radar and stuff
尝试雷达之类的新技术
like that at the time. But then they
当时就是这样。但后来他们
were taking those ideas, bringing them
我们采纳了这些想法，并将它们带了过来。
to the military, which is a huge, very
对军队来说，这是一个巨大的、非常
structured, hierarchical organization
结构化的、层级分明的组织
and saying, "What do you guys think
然后说：“你们觉得怎么样？”
about this? How can you play with this?
关于这件事？这个怎么玩？
What are your ideas? What are your
你有什么想法？你的
feedback? Take this into battle. Put it
反馈？把这个带上战场。把它放进去
on an airplane. See what happens." and
在飞机上。看看会发生什么。
then give that feedback back to this
然后将反馈意见反馈给这个部门。
very, you know, unstructured, flat,
非常，你知道，无结构，扁平的，
small group of of uh inventors and
一小群发明家和
scientists. And by really focusing on
科学家。通过真正专注于
the relationship between those parts of
这些部分之间的关​​系
the organization, ultimately companies
该组织，最终是公司
can figure out how to build a strong
能够想办法建立一个强大的
relationship between the two and then
两人之间的关系，以及之后
innovate over time. So, how have you
随着时间的推移不断创新。那么，你感觉如何？
done that at Snapchat? At Snapchat, we
在Snapchat上做过这件事吗？在 Snapchat，我们
have a really small design team. I think
设计团队规模非常小。我认为
it would surprise people. It's nine
这会让人们感到惊讶。现在是九点
people really. It is totally flat, so
真是人啊。它完全平坦，所以
there's no fancy titles. everyone is a
没有花哨的标题。每个人都是
product designer. Um the the way that
产品设计师。嗯，就是那种方式
the team works is very focused around
团队的工作非常注重以下方面
making things. That's the entire job. In
制作东西。这就是全部工作内容。在
fact, your very first day when you start
事实上，你入职的第一天就是你开始工作的第一天。
you we have design critiques once a week
我们每周都会进行一次设计评审。
for a couple hours. Your very first day
几个小时。你的第一天
you have to present uh something. So you
你得展示点什么。所以你
have to make something and and present
必须制作并展示一些东西。
it. And what that does that I think is
它。我认为这样做是
really interesting and and powerful is
非常有趣且强大的
that ultimately of course on your first
当然，最终在你第一次
day when you have no context for what
当你完全不了解情况的那一天
the company's working on, no idea what's
公司正在研发什么，我也不知道。
going on. How how on earth are you
正在进行中。你到底怎么样了？
supposed to come up with a great idea? I
应该想出一个绝妙的主意？我
mean it's almost impossible. But you
意思是几乎不可能。但是你
have to show an idea your first day. And
第一天上班就要拿出想法。和
so ultimately on your very first day
所以最终，在你第一天
your worst fear has come true that like
你最害怕的事情发生了，就像
we're sitting there al together and
我们一起坐在那里，
we're looking at an idea that's like
我们正在研究一个类似这样的想法
ultimately not that great. I mean
总的来说，效果并不理想。我是说
sometimes they're pretty good but
有时候他们确实不错，但是
ultimately not that great. And that I
总的来说，效果并不理想。而我
think opens the door to creativity
思考开启了创造力之门。
because you've already it already
因为你已经有了
happened. You already failed. There's
发生了。你已经失败了。有
all the idea wasn't good. Uh and you
这个想法本身并不好。呃，还有你
know what ultimately happens on our own
我们自己知道最终会发生什么
design team is that 99% of ideas are not
设计团队认为，99% 的想法都不是
good but 1% is. And you know we really
不错，但只有 1% 也算不错了。你知道我们真的
abide by that idea of like you know or
遵守那种想法，就像你知道的那样，或者
the concept that like the best way to
这个概念就像最好的方式
have a good idea is to have lots of
拥有一个好主意就是拥有很多……
ideas. So the team is just constantly
想法。所以团队一直都在
generating an incredible number of ideas
产生了数量惊人的想法
and products and features and that sort
以及产品、功能等等
of thing. And ultimately our job is to
事物。最终，我们的工作是
try to figure out what the great ones
试着弄清楚那些伟大的人是什么
are and then most importantly build a
是，然后最重要的是建立一个
strong relationship between this little
这个小家伙和我们之间有着很深的感情
team that's coming up with all this
负责制定所有这些方案的团队
stuff all the time and our you know much
一直都有各种各样的事情，你知道的。
bigger engineering organization our
更大的工程组织
bigger product organization who also
更大的产品组织也
have all sorts of amazing ideas and are
他们拥有各种各样奇妙的想法，而且
also innovating in their own way and
他们也在以自己的方式进行创新
build a flywheel between the two where
在两者之间安装一个飞轮
we can ultimately you know make a lot of
我们最终可以创造很多……
new products and then consistently make
新产品，然后持续生产
them better. So many questions there
让他们更好。问题真多啊！
that I'm very very curious about. The
我对此非常非常好奇。这
first one is do you measure the amount
第一个问题是，你是否测量了数量？
of ideas that that small design team are
这个小型设计团队有很多想法
producing?
生产？
No, but I I do know when we need more.
不，但我知道什么时候我们需要更多。
Okay. Okay. Fine. Okay. So, you've got a
好的。好的。美好的。好的。所以，你有一个
you've got a sort of an intuitive
你有一种直觉
feeling. It's small team. You can stay
感觉。这是一个小团队。您可以继续
close. And then how do you get the
关闭。那么，你如何获得……
bigger organization to cooperate with
更大的组织可以与之合作
the smaller design team when the bigger
较小的设计团队，而较大的
organization have their own incentives,
各个组织都有自己的激励机制，
they have their own planning cycles,
它们有自己的规划周期，
they have their own egos as all humans
和所有人类一样，他们也有自己的自尊心。
do. How do you get them to work
做。如何才能让他们工作
together? For us, the the bridge
一起？对我们来说，这座桥
organization is probably our product
组织可能是我们的产品
organization. And they really helped
组织。他们真的帮了我很多。
connect the dots between the engineering
将工程学中的点连接起来
folks and the design folks. And a lot of
各位以及设计人员。而且很多
this stuff, you know, actually mirrors
你知道，这些东西实际上反映了……
the relationship that Bobby and I had in
鲍比和我之间的关系
the very early days where I was more
在我更早的时候，我更
design focused. I had a bit of an
以设计为中心。我有点
engineering background and had taken
拥有工程背景并曾就读
some CS, but I was more design focused.
我学过一些计算机科学，但我更专注于设计。
And Bobby, you know, is an unbelievable
你知道，鲍比真是个不可思议的人。
uh computer scientist, right? He, you
呃，你是计算机科学家吧？他，你
know, took math and and uh computer
我知道，我学过数学和计算机。
science at school, but he also loved
他在学校学科学，但他也热爱其他事物。
design. And so we had this really you
设计。所以，我们真的有了这个。
know powerful relationship where you
了解你与他人之间强大的关系
know I I could talk with him about new
我知道我可以和他谈谈新的事情。
ideas and and design and he could talk
他有想法，有设计，而且他能说会道。
about the engineering constraint. So
关于工程限制。所以
when you know for example when we were
例如，你知道我们当时的情况
inventing this this notion that you know
发明了你知道的这个概念
you would tap to take a photo and hold
你会点击拍照并按住
to record a video at the time that was a
当时录制了一段视频
really big deal right to to you know to
这可是件大事，你知道的。
help people more easily use their
帮助人们更轻松地使用他们的
cameras. Now every camera on a
相机。现在每台摄像机
smartphone is tab for a photo hold for
智能手机是拍照保持用的标签
video. But the engineering complexity
视频。但工程复杂性
that was required to enable that design
这是实现该设计所必需的。
was something that we really talked
这是我们认真讨论过的话题。
about and worked through because the way
关于并努力克服了因为这种方式
that the design and the animations had
设计和动画都具备这些特点。
to work and the way that you, you know,
工作方式以及你的方式，你知道的，
held your finger really mattered with
握住你的手指真的很重要
the way that ultimately we were flipping
最终我们转变的方式
between, you know, the the video feed
你知道，在视频信号之间
and or capturing uh a still a still
和/或捕捉静止的画面
image. And it was that dialogue that
图像。正是那段对话
ultimately ended up you know resulting
最终的结果你知道的
in a in a new product and a new you know
在新产品中，你知道
uh thing that people could use. So we
呃，人们可以用到的东西。所以，我们
mirrored a lot of that and tried to
很多方面都与之类似，并且试图……
build that relationship across the
建立这种关系
organization constantly over time where
组织随着时间的推移不断变化
you know there's there's a real dialogue
你知道，这里面有真正的对话。
and an understanding and an appreciation
以及理解和欣赏
both for design and engineering um you
无论是设计和工程方面，嗯……
know that oftentimes is facilitated by
要知道，这种情况通常是由……促成的。
our product organization. In terms of
我们的产品部门。按照
that small design team you said you have
你说的那个小型设计团队
a critique session once a week. What is
每周一次点评会。什么是
a critique session? So it's just where
点评会？所以问题就在这里
we look at work. That's all we do. Uh we
我们来看看工作。我们只做这些。呃，我们
people just share uh new work. So for a
人们只是分享一些新作品。所以对于
couple hours we'll just look at all the
几个小时后，我们就看看所有的东西。
new ideas that have come out of that
由此产生了一些新想法。
small and new designs that have come out
一些小型和新颖的设计已经问世
of the last week from that team. And
上周该队的表现。和
these can be anything. Really anything.
这些可以是任何东西。真的什么都行。
Yeah. Oftentimes they're oriented around
是的。它们通常围绕着……
solving a problem. So kind of coming
解决问题。所以有点来了
back to that product design philosophy
回到产品设计理念
like what problem are we trying to
我们试图解决什么问题？
solve? How can we empathize with our you
解决？我们如何才能与你产生共鸣？
know community? Okay. our creators are
了解社区吗？好的。我们的创造者是
having friction, you know, posting to to
你知道，有摩擦，发布到
Snapchat. It's, you know, confusing the
Snapchat。你知道，这很令人困惑
way that they're reading their story
他们解读自己故事的方式
replies or that's not working the right
回复或那件事行不通
way. How can we make that easier? And
方式。我们怎样才能让这件事变得更容易？和
then we'll just look at a ton of ideas.
然后我们会考虑很多想法。
And are these you said there's eight or
你说有八个，这些就是吗？
nine people. Are they working in
九个人。他们在工作吗？
isolation within that team or are they
团队内部是否存在孤立？或者他们是否……
working as one team? They very often are
像一个团队一样合作？它们通常是
getting feedback from one another.
互相获取反馈。
Oftentimes are tackling projects
经常要处理项目
together and small teams, you know, um
一起，还有小团队，你知道，嗯
but all come together on a on a regular
但所有这些都会定期地聚集在一起。
basis. I love this this point you were
基础。我喜欢你刚才的这一点。
making about the key thing that you've
想想你最关键的那件事
discovered is is that the game is more
发现的是，这款游戏更
ideas, not trying to find a perfect
想法，而不是试图找到完美
idea. More ideas, more feedback. Yeah.
主意。更多想法，更多反馈。是的。
More ideas, more feedback. You increase
更多想法，更多反馈。你增加
your failure rate, you get more
你的失败率越高，你得到的就越多
feedback. It it does kind of go contrary
反馈。但这确实有点反其道而行之。
to what people think when they're
人们在……时的想法
building a business. They think the game
创建企业。他们认为游戏
is to have the perfect idea. I But those
就是要有一个完美的想法。但那些
are all people who've never built a
都是从未建造过的人
business before.
以前是生意。
Yeah. Because eventually you learn you
是的。因为最终你会明白
learn something, right? You learn that
学到点东西，对吧？你了解到
you're not that good at guessing. Yeah.
你不太擅长猜。是的。
And I think ultimately you have to
我认为最终你必须
maximize your rate of learning. I mean
最大限度地提高学习效率。我是说
that's that's just critical. Maximize
这才是关键所在。最大化
your rate of learning. Let's go back to
你的学习速度。让我们回到……
the um those early days. You're in that
嗯，那些早期的日子。你身处其中。
office. When you think about the people
办公室。当你想到人们
in that photo that were part of the
照片中那些是……的一部分
first sort of 20, how important in
第一种20类，有多重要
hindsight is hiring? I think it's
事后诸葛亮式招聘？我认为是
everything. I think it's everything. And
一切。我觉得它包含了一切。和
these were really really just wonderful
这些真的太棒了！
people. I mean still you know uh in many
人们。我的意思是，你知道，在很多方面。
cases close friends and I think
案例中的亲密朋友，我认为
interesting there was a moment I
有趣的是，我曾有过那么一刻……
realized
已实现
um David Daniel Bobby and a couple other
嗯，大卫·丹尼尔·鲍比和其他几个人
of our original engine all of them uh
我们最初的引擎，它们都……
you know original engineers were
你知道最初的工程师是
musicians as well and it was really
音乐家们也参与其中，而且真的
interesting this moment you know because
你知道，此刻很有意思，因为
the the early folks who were working on
早期从事这项工作的人们
the engineering side of of Snap were
Snap 的工程方面是
unbelievably creative and
极富创造力且
unbelievably talented and it it was an
才华横溢，而且……
interesting interesting like aha moment
真有趣，就像灵光乍现的那一刻
because I think often times people think
因为我觉得人们常常会这样想
of the disciplines as separate like oh
把各个学科看作是彼此独立的，就像哦
there's designers and then over there
有设计师，然后那边……
there's engineers and I think so much of
那里有很多工程师，我认为他们很多
the magic actually is when those
实际上，魔法就在于那些
disciplines like combine or cross over
像组合或跨学科这样的学科
or people who really love and appreciate
或者那些真正热爱和欣赏的人
both especially for a company that's
尤其对于一家公司而言，
aspiring to be creative absolutely in
渴望在绝对的范围内发挥创造力
everything that it's doing um on this
它在这方面所做的一切
point of hiring did you make any hiring
在招聘环节，您是否进行了任何招聘
mistakes in those early days oh
早期犯的错误哦
absolutely and what were those mistakes
当然，那些错误是什么？
not necessarily people but the the
不一定是人，而是
frameworks were were off or the way that
框架要么是关闭的，要么是关闭的方式。
you've hired these people or what what
是你雇佣了这些人吗？
what caused the mistakes? I think
造成这些错误的原因是什么？我认为
occasionally in the early days um we
早期偶尔会……嗯，我们
almost like overindexed on the wrong
几乎就像在错误的地方过度索引了一样。
types of experience if that makes sense.
如果这样说你能理解的话，就是各种类型的经历。
So one of the things we really wanted to
所以我们真正想做的一件事是
do was bring in people who were very
要做的就是引进那些非常
very experienced leaders who had run
经验丰富的领导者，他们曾领导过
much bigger teams. That was like if we
规模更大的团队。那就像我们
want to build a big company we got to
我们想打造一家大公司，我们做到了。
find people who have run big companies
寻找那些曾经运营过大公司的人。
and big teams. And so one of the early
以及大型团队。因此，早期之一
engineering leaders who joined our team,
加入我们团队的工程领导者们，
I think he, you know, he was coming from
我觉得他，你知道，他来自
from working on a team of 300 or
从在300人的团队中工作，到
something like that at at Amazon was
亚马逊上也有类似的事情。
coming to like a team of eight at at
大约有八个人组成一个团队
Snapchat. But we were really thinking
Snapchat。但我们当时真的在想
ahead about like how can we hire people
接下来要讨论的是如何招聘人员
who can actually help us scale here and
谁能真正帮助我们扩大规模？
and build something uh really big. And I
并建造一些非常大的东西。我
think that that sort of focus on
认为这种关注点
leadership experience and experience
领导经验和经验
leading at scale was really valuable. I
大规模领导经验非常宝贵。我
think what was oftentimes a bit less
想想那些通常略少一些的事情
valuable in those early days were was
在那些早期日子里，最有价值的是
almost more people who had very specific
几乎更多的人都有非常具体的情况
domain expertise. So there were people
领域专业知识。所以当时有人
who would you know come into our come
你知道谁会来我们这里吗？
for an interview or something like that
比如面试之类的
and be like well I think what you guys
然后就像，嗯，我觉得你们怎么看？
should do is add likes because every
应该做的就是点赞，因为每个
other platform has likes. So if you just
其他平台也有点赞。所以如果你只是
add likes then people will you know use
点赞后，人们就会知道你用了
your service more and not really coming
您的服务更多了，但并没有真正到来
with the same open-mindedness and
秉持同样的开放心态和
curiosity about well why is Snapchat
好奇为什么 Snapchat
doing it differently? like why don't you
换个方法？比如，你为什么不……
have likes and comments? It's like what
有点赞和评论吗？这就像什么
how are you thinking about the service
您对这项服务有何看法？
um differently and and how could I how
嗯，不一样，而且我怎么可能呢？
can I change and grow and adapt to the
我能否改变、成长并适应？
way you're thinking about it to help you
你思考的方式对你有帮助
grow faster and and so I think now one
增长速度更快，所以我认为现在一个
of the things we're always looking for
我们一直在寻找的东西
in the interview process is adaptability
面试过程中的适应能力
right it's amazing to have prior
没错，拥有前期经验真是太棒了。
experience but the question is how do
经验，但问题是如何
you apply that prior experience to a new
你将之前的经验运用到新的工作中。
context and change and adapt the way
背景、变化和适应方式
that you see things change your
你看到事情发生了变化
perspective um you know to be able to
视角，嗯，你知道，能够
meet the needs of our business which is
满足我们业务的需求，即
different than you know other businesses
与其他企业不同，你了解的其他企业
What what are the other factors? If if
还有哪些其他因素？如果
you were to make a perfect Snapchat
你要制作一个完美的 Snapchat
employee now, what would their
现在的员工会怎么做？
personality be? Their their psychology,
性格是？他们的心理，
their their attributes. We we have three
它们的属性。我们有三个
values and three leadership behaviors.
价值观和三种领导行为。
Three values are kind, smart, and
三种价值观是善良、聪明和
creative. That's been the those have
有创造力的。那些就是那些……
been the values since the the very
自那时起，这些价值观就一直是……
beginning really because Bobby and I
真正开始于鲍比和我
were just having a conversation like
我们只是在进行这样的对话
what kind of people do we want to work
我们想和什么样的人一起工作
with? Kind, smart, creative. Like great.
和？善良、聪明、有创造力。太棒了。
But since then and and we can spend some
但从那时起，我们可以花一些时间
more time talking about this. I think
再花点时间讨论这个问题。我认为
what was really fascinating over time
随着时间的推移，真正令人着迷的是什么？
was to learn you know and by the way 10
是为了学习你知道，顺便说一下，10
years ago people were not talking about
几年前人们并不谈论……
kindness at work. I mean people would be
工作中的善意之举。我的意思是，人们会
like sorry what you know no kind no kind
就像对不起，你知道的，没有善良，没有善良
smart creative like why kindness. What
聪明有创造力的人为什么喜欢善良？什么
we found was that with the that the
我们发现的是，与此
relationship between kindness and
善良与……之间的关系
creativity is really really important
创造力真的非常重要
because unless people feel comfortable
因为除非人们感到舒适，否则
coming up with crazy ideas, unless they
除非他们提出疯狂的想法，否则
feel comfortable that if they say, you
感到自在，如果他们说，你
know, they have some new idea and it
我知道，他们有一些新想法，而且
actually isn't that great that they're
其实他们并没有那么了不起
not going to be laughed at that they'll
他们不会因此而被嘲笑。
be supported, right? Unless you have
应该得到支持，对吧？除非你有
that sort of supportive culture, it's
那种互助互爱的文化，真是太棒了。
very hard to be creative. And so we
很难发挥创造力。所以，我们
learned over time that actually wow
随着时间的推移，我逐渐意识到，哇！
kindness is is kind of the essential
善良是一种至关重要的东西。
ingredient if you want to have a
如果你想添加某种成分……
creative a creative culture. But
创造一种富有创造力的文化。但
anyways, kind, smart, creative, smart,
总之，善良、聪明、有创造力、机智。
pretty self-explanatory. Um, and then uh
无需赘述。嗯，然后呃
when it comes to leadership behaviors,
就领导行为而言，
there's three leadership behaviors or
有三种领导行为或
attributes we look for. I just want to
我们寻找的特质。我只想
pause on that point of kind. Do you make
就这一点稍作停顿。你制作
a distinction between someone being nice
友善与否之间的区别
and being kind? Because in your
还有，善良？因为在你的
environment, you also mentioned that you
在环境方面，你也提到了你
do these critique sessions and you're
参加这些点评会，你就会……
giving people crit critical feedback and
给予人们批判性的反馈和
if a culture gets a little bit too kind,
如果一种文化变得过于仁慈，
then isn't that going to inhibit
那岂不是会起到抑制作用吗？
innovation and feedback? We always
创新与反馈？我们总是
differentiate between kind and nice.
区分善良和友善。
There's a couple examples that I think
我想举几个例子。
help with that. So like for one, um I
请帮忙。比如，首先，嗯，我
think it's really kind to tell somebody
我觉得告诉别人这件事真的很好。
that they have something stuck in their
他们好像有什么东西卡在里面了
teeth. Yeah, you have something stuck in
牙齿。是的，你那里卡了东西。
your teeth, you want to know about it,
你想知道你的牙齿状况吗？
right? It might make you feel awkward.
正确的？这可能会让你感到尴尬。
Certainly as the person pointing it out,
当然，正如指出这一点的人所说，
it's a little awkward, right? If you
有点尴尬，对吧？如果你
want if you just want to be nice, you
如果你只是想表现得友善，你
pretend nothing's going going going on
假装什么都没发生
and you just say, "Oh, you know, nice to
然后你就说，“哦，你知道，很高兴……”
meet you, whatever." But if you're
见到你，无论如何。”但如果你是
really being kind and you want to help
真心善良，想帮忙。
that person, you say, you know, you got
你说，你知道，你认识的那个人。
something stuck in your teeth. You you
牙齿里卡了东西。你你
got to take care of that. And I think
得处理这件事。我觉得
that helps distinguish between, you
这有助于区分你
know, nicities and being kind and really
懂得礼貌、友善和真诚
wanting to help help somebody. I think I
想帮助别人。我觉得我
think another great example is if
另一个很好的例子是……
somebody's really struggling, you know,
你知道，有人真的很难过。
at work or they're struggling to grow or
在工作中，或者他们在成长方面遇到困难，或者
they're struggling with, you know, to to
他们正在努力，你知道，去……
perform um you know, their duties at at
履行他们的职责，你知道的。
SNAP, you know, the nice thing to do is
你知道，SNAP（补充营养援助计划）的善举是……
maybe just make them feel good about it.
或许只是想让他们感觉良好而已。
Oh, don't worry. Uh you know, um I'm
哦，别担心。呃，你知道，嗯，我是
sure it'll be okay. The kind thing to do
肯定没问题。这是应该做的善事
is really help them succeed, right? Say,
确实能帮助他们取得成功，对吗？说，
hey, this isn't working because you're
嘿，这行不通，因为你……
doing X, Y, and Z. You know, here are
做 X、Y 和 Z。你知道，这里是
some things to do to think about that
有一些事情需要思考。
differently. provide that really direct
不一样。提供真正直接的信息
feedback that allows people to grow and
能够帮助人们成长的反馈
that's the kind thing to do rather than
这样做才是善良的做法，而不是
just making them feel good about not
只是让他们感觉良好而已
meeting expectations. Leadership values.
符合预期。领导力价值观。
You said there's three leadership
你说过有三位领导人
values. Okay, there's three of them. The
价值观。好的，一共有三个。这
first one is is T-shaped leadership. So,
第一种是T型领导力。所以，
we talk a lot about T-shaped leadership.
我们经常谈到T型领导力。
What we mean by that uh is that you have
我们这么说的意思是，你拥有
a real depth of experience, a depth of
丰富的经验，深厚的……
expertise in a given area and then a
在特定领域拥有专业知识，然后
real breadth of understanding of the
对……的真正广度理解
business overall and an ability to
整体业务及能力
connect with lots of different types of
与许多不同类型的人建立联系
people who think different ways because
思维方式不同的人
you need to be able to connect your
你需要能够连接你的
expertise to all the different areas of
在所有不同领域拥有专业知识
our business to really drive impact as a
我们的业务旨在真正推动影响力。
leader. I mean, I think that's one of
领导者。我的意思是，我认为这是其中之一
like almost the hallmarks of of running
就像跑步的几乎所有标志一样
a business today is it's basically
如今的商业活动基本上就是这样。
impossible to do anything interesting
根本不可能做任何有趣的事。
without a team, right? The way that the
没有团队，对吧？方式
world works today is very complicated
当今世界运作非常复杂。
and it's really important that you have
这一点真的非常重要。
folks who have deep expertise but then
那些拥有深厚专业知识的人，但是
they have to apply it to all these other
他们必须将其应用于所有其他方面。
crossunctional areas you know so they
你知道的跨职能区域，所以它们
have to have a familiarity with it and
必须熟悉它，并且
an ability to relate to people with
能够与人建立良好关系
different you know viewpoints or or
不同的观点，或者
other you know uh areas of expertise. So
其他你知道的专业领域。所以
and as we proceed with this these
随着我们继续推进这些
leadership principles are you saying
您指的是哪些领导原则？
that in order to become a leader at
为了成为一名领导者
Snapchat you need these three things or
使用 Snapchat 你需要这三样东西或
are you saying everybody at Snapchat
你是说Snapchat上的所有人吗？
needs these three things? We think
需要这三样东西吗？我们认为
everyone is a leader. So, we do apply it
人人都是领导者。所以，我们确实应用了它。
uh broadly. But, of course, you know, um
嗯，大致如此。当然，你知道，嗯
you know, I think it's really important
你知道，我认为这真的很重要。
as we're thinking about hiring or
当我们考虑招聘或
bringing in a new leader that, you know,
引入一位新领导人，你知道，
that this is something that we we talk
这是我们谈论的话题。
to folks about. So, if someone's not
告诉周围的人。所以，如果有人不是
quite T-shaped, if they're a little bit
形状有点像T字形，如果它们稍微有点
eye-shaped, is there something they can
眼睛形状的，他们能做什么？
do to become a bit more te T-shaped?
怎样才能变得更像T型身材呢？
Yeah, that that's almost maybe the the
是的，那几乎就是……
easier one, right? If you can build on a
这题比较简单，对吧？如果你能以此为基础……
if you can build on a real depth of
如果你能建立在真正的深度之上……
expertise by going engaging with folks
通过与人互动来获得专业知识
maybe outside of your comfort zone or in
也许超出你的舒适区，或者在
different parts of the business and
企业的不同部门和
build that curiosity and understanding
培养好奇心和理解力
that helps develop I think that breadth
我认为这有助于拓展视野。
of understanding. I think what's harder
理解。我认为更难的是什么
is if you're a generalist and you don't
如果你是通才，而且你不
have that deep skill set or that deep
拥有那种深厚的技能或那种深度
area of expertise, it's really really
这是我的专业领域，真的非常非常
hard to bring enough value to the team,
很难为团队带来足够的价值，
right? And I think that's that's where
正确的？我认为那就是原因所在。
people get frustrated with like the idea
人们会对这种想法感到沮丧。
of middle management, right? Where it's
是中层管理人员，对吧？它在哪里
like, oh, this is just a person who, you
比如，哦，这只是一个人，你
know, knows a little about a lot but
知道，对很多事情略知一二，但
can't really help me solve this problem
真的帮不了我解决这个问题
because they don't really know the
因为他们并不真正了解
details. They don't really understand,
细节。他们其实并不了解。
you know, how how to help me, you know,
你知道，该怎么帮帮我呢，你知道吗？
grow as an individual or solve this
个人成长或解决这个问题
tough technical problem. And so I think
棘手的技术问题。所以我认为
that's why that area of expertise is so
这就是为什么这个专业领域如此重要的原因。
important because it's so hard to
之所以重要，是因为它很难
inspire people that you're working with
激励与你共事的人
if you don't know a lot about, you know,
如果你不太了解，你知道，
the the area that you're working in. And
你所在的工作区域。
do you need to be a T-shape leader at
你需要成为T型领导者吗？
Snapchat now and when there was 10 of
Snapchat 现在和以前只有 10 个的时候
you in the in the bedroom or in your
你在卧室里还是在你的
dad's house? Has it always been
爸爸家？一直以来都是如此吗？
important or is that a function of being
重要吗？或者这只是存在的一种功能？
bigger? That's a great question. I wish
大？这是一个很好的问题。我希望
we had been more thoughtful about the
我们之前对这件事考虑得更周全了。
leadership values and and
领导价值观和
characteristics we were looking for back
我们一直在寻找的特征
then. I think, you know, when you're
然后。我觉得，你知道，当你
working on a team of 10 or a team of 20,
在10人团队或20人团队中工作，
you're not thinking as much about what
你并没有过多地思考什么
what leadership characteristics are
领导者应具备哪些特质？
really important to us. It's more about
对我们来说非常重要。更重要的是
like how do we survive tomorrow? Um, you
我们明天该如何生存？嗯，你
know, but but I think over time as we
我知道，但是，但是我认为随着时间的推移，当我们
learned what leaders were really
明白了真正的领导者是什么样的人。
successful at Snap, we were able to, you
在Snap取得成功后，我们能够做到，你
know, kind of look at those attributes
知道，要仔细看看这些属性。
and say, okay, you know, these are the
然后说，好吧，你知道，这些是
leaders who can who who really succeed
能够真正成功的领导者
here and drive a lot of value for our
在这里，我们创造了很多价值。
business. Before we move on to this the
商业。在我们继续讨论之前
second two, if this Evan could have gone
第二点，如果埃文能去的话
back to the Evan that was running a team
回到之前带领团队的埃文身上。
of 10 and he could have pulled him aside
他有10个人，而且他本来可以把他拉到一边。
and said, "Listen, here's some advice
然后说道：“听着，我给你一些建议。”
that you're going to need to know about
你需要了解以下内容
leadership in building this team. The
在组建这支团队方面发挥了领导作用。这
most critical advice I could give you at
我能给你的最关键的建议是
this time, and this is for all the
这一次，也是为了所有人
entrepreneurs out there that are
那些创业者们
building at they're laying the
他们正在建造
foundations of a potentially very big
一个潜在非常大的基础
company right now, what would you have
你现在所在的公司有什么发展方向？
whispered in his ear?" I would have
在他耳边低语？我会的
said, "Everything's going to be okay."
他说：“一切都会好起来的。”
Really? Everything's going to be okay.
真的吗？一切都会好起来的。
Um, you know, I I think sometimes people
嗯，你知道，我觉得有时候人们
are too focused
过于专注
on making the right decision and not as
做出正确的决定，而不是作为
focused on fixing it if they're wrong.
专注于改正错误。
And I think what I would have put more
我觉得我应该多加一些。
emphasis on is just how quickly are you
重点在于你的速度有多快
changing your mind when you receive new
收到新东西后改变主意
information? How quickly are you fixing
信息？你们修复的速度有多快？
a problem or a mistake if you didn't
如果你没有这样做，那就是个问题或错误。
make the right decision in the first
一开始就做出正确的决定
place? And that's the feedback loop that
地方？这就是反馈回路。
is so missionritical to building a
对于建设而言，这是至关重要的使命
business in the early days. It has very
早期的商业活动。它非常
little to do. Obviously, there's
没什么事可做。显然，有
existential decisions, you know, and and
你知道，这是关乎生存的抉择，而且
those can, you know, create some big
你知道，这些可能会造成一些大问题。
problems for your business. But most
给您的企业带来的问题。但大多数
decisions are not existential decisions.
决定并非关乎生死存亡的决定。
And the more important thing is to make
更重要的是要做到这一点。
a decision and then if you're wrong, fix
做出决定，如果错了，就改正。
it. Um, and I think it's the when you're
它。嗯，我觉得是当你……
wrong, fixing it part that deserves most
错了，纠正它才是最值得关注的部分
of the attention and and also how you
关注度以及你如何
can identify, you know, who your great
可以认出，你知道，你的伟大之处。
leaders are, who, you know, uh, who
领导者就是，你知道，呃，谁
really talented folks on the team are
团队里真正有才华的人是
because they're very quick to point out,
因为他们总是很快指出这一点，
you know, I don't think we did that
你知道，我觉得我们没做过那件事。
right. I think we should take this path,
正确的。我认为我们应该走这条路。
you know, this other path that, you
你知道，还有这条路，你
know, we we maybe hadn't considered the
我知道，我们可能没有考虑到这一点。
first time. And and I think it takes
第一次。而且我认为这需要
courage to to say that in in an
鼓起勇气说出来
organization rather than just say, "Oh,
组织而不是仅仅说，“哦，
we're doing a great job." Yeah. And when
我们做得很好。” 是的。而且当
you're back there and you're you've made
你又回去了，你已经做到了
a mistake, there's something you've done
错误，你做了某件事
wrong in hindsight, did you know in your
事后看来是错的，你当时知道吗？
because because one of the things that I
因为其中一件事就是
think of when I was a first-time founder
想想我第一次创业的时候
building a student notice board was I
搭建学生公告栏是我
would get feedback and the feedback
会收到反馈，而这些反馈
would be saying you're wrong about this.
也就是说，你在这件事上错了。
You need to change. And I think at
你需要改变。而且我认为
sometimes there was a part of me that
有时我内心深处会想：
knew, but I was like too scared to act
我知道，但我太害怕了，不敢采取行动。
upon it. So I kind of like gaslit myself
就在上面。所以，我有点像是在自我欺骗。
to just keep going. And I think a lot of
继续前进。而且我认为很多
founders do that. I know this because
创始人会这样做。我知道这一点是因为
they they come to me in my portfolio and
它们出现在我的作品集中
they say, "Ah, Steve, there's this guy
他们说：“啊，史蒂夫，那边有个人……”
we've hired and he's been there now for
我们已经聘用了他，他现在已经在那里工作了。
a year and he's just not cutting it."
一年过去了，他还是不行。
I'm like, "Why the are you telling
我当时就想，“你他妈的为什么要说这些？”
me?" And they're they're procrastinating
我？”他们正在拖延。
avoiding the conversation, but clearly
回避谈话，但显然
they know. Clearly they know it's not
他们知道。显然他们知道并非如此。
right.
正确的。
It's funny you say that because anytime
你说得真有意思，因为任何时候
someone comes to ask me about like that
有人来问我这类问题。
type of people advice, like, "What do
这类人的建议，比如，“你该怎么办？”
you think we should do?" You know, do
你觉得我们应该怎么做？你知道，怎么做
you think that I'm like sounds like
你觉得我听起来像……
you've already made up your mind.
你已经下定决心了。
So um so yeah I I think it is I think it
所以，嗯，是的，我想是的，我想是的
is really important to you know act on
了解并采取行动真的非常重要。
that feedback not be afraid to change
反馈意见不要害怕改变
direction quickly if you know you you
如果你知道你，就能很快找到方向。
realize that you made a mistake but as
意识到自己犯了错误，但是……
you point out it's it's hard to do and
你指出这很难做到，而且
sometimes it is worth seeing if you know
有时候值得看看你是否了解
your your bet you know plays out. You
你知道你的赌注会如何发展。你
don't want to thrash the team and change
不想大动干戈地整顿球队，也不想做出任何改变。
your mind all the time. So sometimes you
你时时刻刻都在想这件事。所以有时候你
know it is it is sometimes worth seeing
要知道，有时候值得一看。
things through a little bit before you
在你之前，先把事情理顺一下。
change. Is there anything else you would
改变。您还有什么想说的吗？
have said to that younger Evan in that
曾对年轻的埃文说过
in your dad's house advice? Um at at
在你爸爸家有什么建议？嗯，在
that point before we had scaled to a lot
在那之前，我们的规模已经非常庞大了。
of you know thousands of people I think
你知道，成千上万的人，我想
we could have been much more clear on
我们本可以把这一点说得更清楚些。
the culture the kind smart creative
这种文化，这种聪明而富有创造力的风格。
piece and really embedded that in the
并将其真正融入到作品中。
team prior to scaling because one of the
团队在规模化之前就已成立，因为其中一个
biggest challenges that we confronted
我们面临的最大挑战
was you know as we went from 20 people
你知道，我们从20人增加到现在的人数。
to 2,000 people we basically imported
我们基本上是从国外引进了2000人。
all of these different cultures from all
来自世界各地的所有这些不同文化
sorts of different companies like we
像我们这样的各种不同类型的公司
imported an an Amazon contingent right
导入亚马逊或有权利
we you know who They really love their
你知道他们真正爱的是谁
six-page documents. We, you know,
六页文件。我们，你知道，
imported a a Google uh contingent,
导入了一个谷歌呃……团队，
right? And they're very focused on
正确的？他们非常关注……
consensus based decision-making. We
基于共识的决策。我们
imported, you know, a contingent from
你知道，是从国外引进的一支队伍
from Meta as well. And I think we were
来自 Meta 也是如此。我认为我们当时
too slow to be really clear about what
速度太慢，无法真正清楚地了解情况。
our values were and what that looked
我们的价值观是什么，以及它看起来是什么样子。
like in practice, what those behaviors
就像在实践中，这些行为会是什么样子？
looked like. And I think if we had
看起来像。而且我认为如果我们有
earlier and and faster one, so when when
更早、更快的那个，所以当……
we're evaluating performance, we look at
我们正在评估绩效，我们会查看
our values, kind, smart, creative, we
我们的价值观：善良、聪明、有创造力，我们
have specific behaviors attached to that
具有与此相关的特定行为
that are actually researchbacked and
实际上是有研究支持的，而且
whatever. We did a whole study to
任何。我们进行了一项完整的研究……
understand which of those behaviors are
了解哪些行为是
really tied to performance and those
与表现和那些密切相关
values. But that gives people a really
价值观。但这确实给了人们一个很大的
clear framework for the expectations for
明确的预期框架
how to behave at Snap and our unique
在Snap的行为规范以及我们独特的
culture. And there there was a moment of
文化。那一刻……
time moment in time where I felt like we
在某个时刻，我感觉我们
were losing control of our culture. And
我们正在失去对自身文化的控制。和
I wasn't happy with our our company and
我对我们公司很不满意，
the team. I remember I was complaining
团队。我记得我当时在抱怨。
to a friend of mine. This is probably
致我的一位朋友。这大概是
like your story of of folks coming to
就像你讲述的人们前来的故事一样
you and saying, "Oh, it's not working."
你然后说：“哦，它不起作用。”
I was I was complaining to a friend of
我当时正在向一个朋友抱怨……
mine and I was just like, "Man, I just
我当时就想，“唉，我真是……”
don't like I don't like it. Like I don't
我不喜欢，我真的不喜欢。就像我不这样
like my job. I don't like what our
我喜欢我的工作。我不喜欢我们现在的样子
company's become." And she just looks at
公司已经变成了……”她只是看着
me and she's like, "Then fix it." And I
我和她就说：“那就把它修好。”我
was like, "Great point." Um and and I
当时我就想：“说得太对了。”嗯，还有我
you know I think at that it just it had
你知道，我觉得当时就是这样。
changed and grown so quickly that it was
变化和发展如此迅速，以至于
really hard to stay true to our values
要坚守我们的价值观真的很难。
but I think you know uh I really took
但我觉得你知道，我真的接受了
that advice to heart and just started
把这些建议铭记于心，然后就开始行动了。
trying to fix it with our team getting
我们的团队正在尝试解决这个问题
really clear about the values getting
对价值观的理解非常清晰
really clear about the behaviors holding
对这些行为的理解非常清晰。
a higher bar and saying hey you know if
更高的标准，然后说，嘿，你知道吗？
you're not into the kind smart creative
你对那种聪明又有创造力的人才不感兴趣。
thing that's okay there are other
没关系，还有其他的。
companies with different cultures but
具有不同文化的公司，但
you know that really matters to us here.
你知道这对我们来说非常重要。
So, do you do you wish you had this
所以，你希望拥有这个吗？
would have been a pretty remarkable
那将是一件非常了不起的事情
thing to do, but do you wish you had
这是件值得做的事，但你是否希望自己当初做了呢？
made like a culture bible in the early
早期被当作文化圣经来制作
days and then like I'm thinking
几天后，就像我在想……
practically what should a founder do
创始人实际应该做什么
then if they're at that stage when
那么如果他们处于那个阶段，
they've got a small team now to prevent
他们现在有一个小团队来阻止这种情况。
what happened to you in terms of the
你那边发生了什么事？
culture becoming a little bit too pick
文化变得有点太挑剔了。
and mix. So, I think it's less about the
然后混合。所以，我认为这与……关系不大。
culture bible and more about how you
文化圣经以及更多关于你如何
apply whatever your values are to your
将你的价值观运用到你的
hiring processes, to your promotion
从招聘流程到你的晋升
processes, to whether or not people
过程，以及人们是否参与其中。
still work at the company. And so, we
仍在公司工作。所以，我们
were too slow to embed those values in
速度太慢，无法将这些价值观融入其中。
our performance evaluation. And so, I
我们的绩效评估。所以，我
think if we had been way faster at just
想想如果我们当时速度更快就好了
saying, hey, these are our values and
说，嘿，这些是我们的价值观，
what we stand for. This is what it looks
我们的立场。这就是它的样子
like in practice. Uh, and if you're not
就像在实践中一样。呃，如果你不是
living up to that, this isn't the right
如果真要如此，那就不对了。
home for you. like that that would have
你的家。就像那样，就会有
helped shape the culture a lot faster
更快地塑造了文化
also because immediately people see oh
也因为人们会立刻看到哦
wow if they're serious about their
哇，如果他们是认真的的话……
values and they're asking people to
价值观，他们要求人们
leave if they won't live up to their
如果他们不能履行承诺，就离开。
values well then I you know I I better
价值观很好，那么你知道我更好
get on board with the values or find you
要么认同这些价值观，要么找到你
know another culture that fits you know
了解另一种适合你的文化
fits my personality better it just
它更符合我的个性，就是这样
doesn't seem like a priority to founders
创始人似乎并不把这当回事。
culture I think it's such a priority but
我认为文化非常重要，但
it's hard to understand what it means
很难理解它的意思。
you know I had so many people telling me
你知道吗，很多人都跟我说过这些话
like really you got to really focus on
真的，你必须真正专注于……
the culture focus on the culture like
文化关注点在于文化，例如
like what do you mean by culture it's
你说的文化是什么意思？
like it's actually just how people
就像人们实际上就是这样做一样
behave, right? I mean, that's really
守规矩点，对吧？我的意思是，那真是
what we're saying like what is the
我们说的意思是，什么是……
collection of group behaviors, you know,
你知道，这是一系列群体行为的集合。
that are uh acceptable or norms in your
那些在你看来是可以接受的或符合规范的。
in your company. So, I think instead of
在你公司。所以，我认为与其说是
using this big culture word, which I was
我用了这个很大的文化词汇，我当时
hearing a lot, but not understanding how
听到了很多，但却不明白是怎么回事。
it was like tactically connecting to our
这就像是与我们进行战术上的联系。
business, I think when we're talking
我觉得，当我们谈论商业的时候。
with founders, we should just be more
对于创始人，我们应该更加……
specific about, you know, how people are
具体来说，你知道，人们是如何……
living their the values of their company
践行他们公司的价值观
every day through their behaviors. And
每天都能通过他们的行为体现出来。和
that's dictated essentially by the
这基本上是由……决定的
incentives of the organization because
组织的激励机制
what you said is you basically
你说的基本上就是你
introduced incentive structures said
引入激励机制
you're going to be exited or you're
你会感到兴奋，或者你会
going to be promoted and and getting
将会得到晋升和发展
really real about that and serious. But
对此非常认真，也很实在。但
it, you know, that the tough
你知道，这很艰难。
conversations come where it's like,
对话有时会变成这样：
well, that person's a superstar, you
嗯，那个人可是个超级巨星，你
know, but they're not really living our
我知道，但他们并没有真正生活在我们身边。
kindness value. And Bobby, I think, is
善良的价值。而我认为，鲍比是
so is was so great on this. Bobby is
所以，这方面做得太棒了。鲍比是
like, Evan, there's no such thing as a
比如，埃文，根本没有这种事
brilliant jerk. If you're really
聪明绝顶的混蛋。如果你真的
brilliant, how could you possibly be a
太棒了，你怎么可能……
jerk? I mean it just me, you know, and
混蛋？我的意思是，就我一个人，你知道的，
you're like, damn, I love that. So, so I
你会想，哇，我太喜欢这个了。所以，所以
think this concept that like if you're
想想这个概念，就像如果你是
really that smart, how could you
你真那么聪明，怎么会这样？
possibly be a jerk to people? I mean,
可能会对别人很刻薄？我是说，
what that that I think, you know, really
我觉得，你知道，真的
informed our approach to to building out
这影响了我们对建设方式的理解
our team and and I think gives you that
我们的团队，而且我认为能给你带来这一点。
clarity in those moments where you're
在那些你感到清醒的时刻
like, "Wow, but they're so smart or
比如，“哇，他们真聪明！”
they're so talented." It's like, yeah,
他们太有才华了。” 是啊，
but if they're that smart and talented,
但如果他们真的那么聪明又有才华，
why can't they just be kind to people?
为什么他们就不能善待他人呢？
What was the worst advice you got in
你听过的最糟糕的建议是什么？
those early years? We talked about some
那些早年时光？我们谈了一些
of the good advice and the good advice
好的建议和好的建议
you'd give now, but was there any like
你现在会给，但之前有这样的吗？
really bad advice that you got that
你得到的那个建议真是太糟糕了。
seemed to make sense but was terrible
听起来有道理，但实际上很糟糕。
advice?
建议？
I think a lot of people in the early
我认为早期很多人都这样认为
days, you know, told us that um that uh
你知道，几天前告诉我们，嗯，呃
we should sell it. I mean, there there
我们应该把它卖掉。我的意思是，就在那里
were a lot of there was one embarrassing
有很多，其中有一个令人尴尬的
moment. I remember I I joined a
片刻。我记得我加入了一个
conference call uh early with some of
很早的时候，和一些人开了个电话会议。
our lawyers and I don't think they had
我们的律师，而且我认为他们没有
known I I had joined and they were
我知道我加入了他们，他们是
talking about you know this thing is
说到你知道的这件事是
basically going to zero you know what I
基本上归零了，你知道吗？
mean this was in the early days like
这意味着这是在早期的时候
it's just a fad you know da da da da and
这只是一时的风潮，你知道的，哒哒哒哒。
I'm like oh hey guys you know you're
我就像，哦，嘿，伙计们，你们知道你们是
joking or and they didn't know you were
开玩笑，或者他们不知道你是
on the call they hadn't known I joined
在通话中，他们并不知道我加入了。
because I joined a minute or two early
因为我提前一两分钟加入了。
or something like that. Um, so I think
或者类似的事情。嗯，所以我觉得
there was a lot of skepticism in the
当时很多人都持怀疑态度。
early days and a lot of people who said,
早期，很多人都这么说，
you know, hey, sell now while you can.
你知道，趁现在还能卖，赶紧卖掉吧。
Um, you know, you're competing in a
嗯，你知道，你正在参加一个比赛
really really tough industry with a lot
非常非常艰难的行业，有很多……
of big players and you don't know if
大玩家，你不知道他们是否
people are going to, you know, continue
人们将会继续，你知道的。
to love this product. But I think what
喜欢这款产品。但我认为什么
they missed was our vision for the
他们错失了我们对未来的愿景。
future, right? They only saw what was in
未来，对吧？他们只看到了里面的东西。
the public. We were working on all sorts
公众。我们当时在做各种各样的事情
of and still are working on all sorts of
并且仍在从事各种各样的工作
amazing new products that give us
令人惊叹的新产品给我们带来
conviction in the future and and our
对未来的信念以及我们的
ability to make products that that
有能力生产出这样的产品
people really love. But I think from the
人们真的很喜欢。但我认为从
outside when you were looking at
当你在外面看着的时候
Snapchat, you're like, people are just
Snapchat，你会觉得，人们就只是
sending photos back and forth. I mean,
互相发送照片。我是说，
how is this ever going to be a business?
这怎么可能成为一项生意呢？
How is this ever gonna grow for the long
它怎么可能长期发展下去呢？
term? But you do end up getting an
学期？但你最终还是会得到一个
offer, a very very famous offer when
优惠，一个非常非常著名的优惠
you're 23 years old from Mark Zuckerberg
你今年23岁，来自马克·扎克伯格
at Facebook. Yeah, that was a a fateful
在 Facebook 上。是的，那是一次命运攸关的事件。
fateful day for sure. How does how does
这绝对是命运攸关的一天。如何如何
that begin? How does that story begin?
那是什么开始的？这个故事是如何开始的？
Is it an email, a phone call, an
是电子邮件、电话还是其他什么？
introduction?
介绍？
I think it was an initial email.
我想那是一封初始邮件。
Um, and I think we met at at some point
嗯，我想我们曾经见过面。
and they they were interested in what we
他们对我们感兴趣
were doing and you know at that time
我们当时正在做，你知道，那时候
they were working on a competitor called
他们当时正在研究一个竞争对手，叫做
Poke um you know and so they were kind
你知道，他们很友善。
of talking with us hey you know we're
和我们交谈，嘿，你知道我们是
exploring this space kind of thing. what
探索太空之类的事情。什么
do you think? And maybe you want to join
你觉得呢？或许你想加入
uh Facebook. I think they had just
呃，脸书。我认为他们刚刚
acquired Instagram too um probably like
也收购了Instagram，嗯，大概是这样吧。
a year earlier or something like that.
比预期早一年左右。
And our view was that Instagram had been
我们的观点是，Instagram 已经
wildly undervalued in that um
在那方面被严重低估了
acquisition ultimately had given up like
收购最终放弃了，就像
a massive massive opportunity. Um
这是一个巨大的机遇。嗯
Instagram was sold for a billion was it?
Instagram 以十亿美元的价格售出了，是吗？
Yeah. A billion. Yeah. And WhatsApp was
是的。十亿。是的。而WhatsApp是
19 billion roughly. Yeah. I think so.
大约190亿。是的。我也这么认为。
You're 23 years old at that point.
那时你23岁。
You've got Facebook, Mark Zuckerberg,
你有Facebook，马克·扎克伯格，
offering you a lot of
为您提供很多
money. I heard that it was $3 billion
钱。我听说金额是30亿美元。
they offered. Yeah, we never talked
他们主动提出。是啊，我们从没说过话。
about it publicly, but yeah. Is is that
虽然我没有公开谈论此事，但确实如此。是吗？
the number? Uh, that's not technically
号码是多少？呃，严格来说，这不算。
the number, but it's what's been
这个数字，但事实就是如此。
reported publicly, so we can go with
已公开报道，所以我们可以这样认为。
that. Okay. And but did you get an
那。好的。但是你得到什么了吗？
offer? There were there was a real
提供？那里确实存在一个真实的
conversation about what it would look
讨论它会是什么样子
like and you know um you know to to join
就像你知道的，嗯，你知道要加入
forces but ultimately you know when we
各种力量，但最终你知道当我们
talked with our board and our investors
与董事会和投资者进行了交谈
you know we decided that we'd rather go
你知道，我们决定还是去吧
it alone. So I'm trying to understand as
单独一人。所以我正在努力理解……
a 23-year-old if someone offers me $3
如果有人给我3美元，我23岁。
billion for an app that I've started you
我为了一个我开发的应用程序赚了十亿美元
said you're probably still at your dad's
他说你可能还在你爸爸家。
house or in the blue office at that
房子里或者那间蓝色的办公室里
point. Yeah I think we were definitely
观点。是的，我觉得我们当时肯定
in my dad's house. you're in your dad's
在我爸爸家。你在你爸爸的
house and someone's offering you $3
房子，有人出价3美元给你。
billion for an app. What wisdom do you
一款应用价值数十亿美元。你有什么智慧？
have that enables you to turn that down?
有办法调低这个音量吗？
Um, I I wish I could say it was wisdom.
嗯，我真希望我能说那是智慧。
I think it was just that Bobby and I
我想只是我和鲍比的事。
loved what we were doing. We loved what
我们热爱我们正在做的事情。我们喜欢什么
we were working on. We believed in the
我们正在研究。我们相信
the future of it and ultimately we were
它的未来，以及最终我们……
able to convince our investors as well
也能说服我们的投资者
that like our opportunity was much
那就像我们的机会一样。
bigger over time. Um, and you know, so I
随着时间的推移，体积会越来越大。嗯，你知道，所以我
think that's, you know, that's what gave
我觉得就是那样，你知道，就是那样。
us, I guess, the confidence in in making
我想，这让我们对制造的信心产生了依赖。
that decision. Did you ever get to meet
那个决定。你最终有机会见到他吗？
with Mark or speak to Mark about it?
跟马克谈谈这件事？
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I've known Mark for a
是的。是的。是的。我认识马克已经有……
long time. And was he he was keen to buy
很久。他是否真的渴望购买？
it?
它？
Um, I you know, I I we had we had some
嗯，你知道，我们有一些
interesting conversations about what it
关于它的有趣对话
could look like for us to work at at uh
对我们来说，这可能看起来像是在……工作
at Facebook. I you know, I want to be so
在 Facebook 上。你知道，我想成为那样的人
sensitive to those conversations. I
对那些谈话很敏感。我
don't want to like speak out of turn,
不想贸然发言，
but um you know he's he's very strategic
但是，你知道，他很有策略。
and very good at identifying you know at
而且非常擅长识别你知道的
the time they had a a piece of software
他们当时拥有一款软件
that was identifying sort of what are
那是为了确定什么是……
the fast growing apps um you know so
你知道，那些快速增长的应用程序。
that they could pursue them for
他们可以追究他们的责任
acquisitions. I'm I'm just so I'm I'm so
收购。我，我就是，我就是，我就是
interested to see how those things play
很想看看这些事情会如何发展。
out. It's almost it sounds like
出去。听起来几乎就像
something you'd see in a movie where you
就像你在电影里看到的那样，你
get this call from someone like Mark
接到马克之类的人的电话
Zuckerberg who's built this massive
扎克伯格一手打造了这个庞大的体系。
empire and you almost it feels like you
帝国和你几乎感觉就像你
get summoned I would imagine you get
我想你会得到召唤。
summoned from your dad's house to come
被从你爸爸家叫来
and meet him and you went to Facebook's
然后你见到了他，你去了Facebook。
offices to meet him I'm guessing in
我猜想，他会在办公室里与我会面。
person. I think at one point I went up
人。我觉得我一度上升了
there we he came and met us at uh we met
他来了，和我们碰面了，我们见面了。
at Cheryl's condo in like Santa Monica
在谢丽尔位于圣莫尼卡的公寓
or something like that. Cheryl had a
或者类似的事情。谢丽尔有一个
condo there and so we I think that's
那里有套公寓，所以我觉得那就是
where we first met Bobby and I met him.
我们第一次见到鲍比的地方，也是我第一次见到他的地方。
And did he tell you that he was going to
他有没有告诉你他要去……
copy you if you didn't sell? He just
如果你没卖出去，他们会抄袭你吗？他只是
explained that he was working on Poke
他解释说他正在开发宝可梦游戏。
and that, you know, it was uh for
你知道，那是为了……
picture messaging and that kind of
图片信息之类的
thing.
事物。
And I'm guessing you didn't want to join
我猜你并不想加入。
a big company at that point. It was it
当时是一家大公司。就是它
was less so like not wanting to join a
更像是不想加入……
big company. I think fundamentally we
大公司。我认为从根本上来说，我们
wanted to build a business that was
想建立一个这样的企业
different. I mean, you go back to our
不同的。我的意思是，你回到我们
first blog post and the way that we
第一篇博客文章以及我们的方式
talked about wanting to offer an
谈到想要提供一个
alternative to social media that we felt
我们觉得，社交媒体的替代方案是……
like social media was about being pretty
社交媒体似乎就是关于漂亮的。
and perfect and we wanted a way to
完美，我们想要一种方法
communicate with our friends that was
和朋友们交流就是
fun. The company ethos, the values, the
乐趣。公司理念、价值观、
visions were so divergent. It was very
彼此的观念截然不同。非常
hard to imagine that like we could keep
很难想象我们能一直保持这种状态。
doing what we love in the way that we
以我们喜欢的方式做我们喜欢的事
loved doing it like as a part of that
我喜欢把它当作其中的一部分来做。
organization because they're just
因为他们只是组织起来了
oriented in a very different way. Was
方向截然不同。曾是
there ever a day where you doubted that
你是否曾怀疑过这一点？
decision? No.
决定？不。
Not even a moment. Not a moment. No.
一刻也没有。一刻也没有。不。
Was Were all of the board supportive?
董事会成员都支持吗？
Yeah. All of our investors were
是的。我们所有的投资者都是
supportive. I They would have made a lot
支持的。他们本来可以赚很多钱的。
of money. Yeah. But they did something
钱。是的。但他们做了些什么
very smart early on in like a prior
早期就非常聪明，就像以前一样。
financing round that I guess around that
我猜那轮融资大概就是那一轮吧。
time or before then where we were Bobby
当时或更早的时候，我们在哪里，鲍比
and I were each able to sell $10 million
我和她各自卖出了价值1000万美元的商品。
of stock. So we each had 10 million
库存。所以我们每个人都有1000万。
bucks and we were like, "Wow, like we
我们当时就想，“哇，就像我们……”
made it." Like we you know what I mean?
成功了。”就像你知道我的意思一样？
we have enough money for ever and that
我们有足够的钱永远用不完。
like allowed us to just swing for the
就像允许我们放手一搏一样。
fences. I mean, you know, at that point
栅栏。我的意思是，你知道，在那个时候
you're like, let's just go for it. So,
你会想，那就放手一搏吧。所以，
there wasn't that feeling of like, oh
没有那种“哦”的感觉。
no, I'm not going to be able to buy a
不，我买不起。
house. I'm not going to be able to like,
房子。我不能像……那样做。
you know, have a family. We were like,
你知道，组建家庭。我们当时就想，
we each got 10 million bucks. Like,
我们每人分到了1000万美元。喜欢，
let's let's go for it. I mean, there's a
咱们开始吧。我的意思是，这里有一个
lesson in there as well for founders who
这其中也蕴含着对创始人的教训，他们
are considering taking, as they say,
他们正在考虑采取，正如他们所说，
taking some off the table. I got a a
把一些东西从桌子上拿走。我得到了一个
voice note from a I was actually
我当时其实是在一条语音留言里
listening to it this morning and I
今天早上听了这首歌，我
responded to her this morning. a friend
今天早上回复了她。朋友
of mine whose business was I think it
我的生意，我想是这样的
was at the top of the market in 2020 was
2020年曾处于市场顶峰
set for an IPO and her board and
准备进行首次公开​​募股，她的董事会和
investors and everyone was telling her
投资者和所有人都在告诉她
that it's going to be a billion dollar
这将是十亿美元
business and that she should carry on
她应该继续经营生意。
going. She approached me and asked me if
去。她走过来问我是否
I would buy some shares off her. I took
我会从她那里买一些股票。我拿
a look at the business and I valued it
我考察了一下这家公司，觉得它很有价值。
at a quarter of a million sorry a
二十五万，抱歉
quarter of a billion so 250 million very
2.5亿，也就是2.5亿，非常
different numbers. Um and her investors
不同的数字。嗯和她的投资者
around her were telling her it was worth
她周围的人都告诉她，这是值得的。
something else. So she had sent me a
别的什么。所以她给我发了一封邮件
voice note which is now 4 years later
四年后的语音留言
this morning saying thank you for that
今天早上我为此表示感谢。
Steven because although we didn't end up
史蒂文，因为虽然我们最终没有……
doing a deal with you, you put this idea
和你做交易时，你提出了这个想法
in my head that I could be being
我脑海里一直想着我可能
basically having a story sold to me. So
基本上就是有人向我推销了一个故事。所以
what I ended up doing a couple of months
几个月后，我最终做了这件事。
after our conversation is I sold some
谈话结束后，我卖出了一些
shares and obviously you know what
股票，当然你也知道。
happened in 2020 with the markets and
2020年市场发生了这样的事情
eventually everything comes crashing
最终一切都会崩溃。
down and she says I would be losing my
她说我会失去我的
mind now because the company's
现在请注意，因为公司的
struggling and obviously the markets
市场举步维艰，显然如此。
have changed if I hadn't have taken some
如果我没有服用某些药物，情况可能会有所改变。
off the table. and she was sending a
不在桌上。她正在发送一封
voice note four years later to say thank
四年后，我发语音留言表示感谢
you for putting that seed in their head.
感谢你把那颗种子播撒在他们脑海里。
And I hear the same with you. I hear
我也听到了你同样的反馈。我听说
that you took some money off the table.
你从桌上拿走了一些钱。
It changed your decision framework. Um
它改变了你的决策框架。嗯
but also you just never know. Yeah. And
但谁也说不准。是的。和
and I think you have to be to your
我认为你必须对自己负责。
point, you have to be careful about
这一点，你必须小心。
approaching these situations as like
以类似方式处理这些情况
zero sum like either we're going to like
零和博弈，要么我们喜欢
go big or you know and with the risk
要么放手一搏，要么就得承担风险。
that we'll lose it all or you know we'll
我们会失去一切，或者你知道我们会
we'll sell the company. I think, you
我们将出售公司。我觉得，你
know, there are all sorts of creative
要知道，创意人士形形色色，不胜枚举。
solutions that allow founders to take
允许创始人采取的解决方案
some money off the table, take care of
把一些钱处理掉，搞定
their families, and still swing for the
他们的家人，仍然在为之奋斗
fences and and build a big business. And
建围栏，然后建立一家大企业。和
venture capitalists are really aligned
风险投资家们确实目标一致。
with the swing for the fences
全力挥杆，争取全垒打
philosophy. Growth investors maybe less
哲学。成长型投资者可能较少
so as the business gets bigger, but when
随着业务规模的扩大，但是当
you have venture capitalists, I mean,
我的意思是，你们有风险投资家。
they're, you know, they're looking for
你知道，他们正在寻找
10x, 100x return. So I I think you know
10倍、100倍回报。所以，我想你知道
to to find a formula that works for
找到一个适用于
founders that allows them to you know
创始人让他们能够……你知道
take care of their families but also
照顾好家人，但也
swing for the fences is I think a
我认为，全力以赴争取全垒打是……
valuable approach. Are you and Mark
很有价值的方法。你和马克
friends? You said you know him. Uh last
朋友们？你说你认识他。呃，最后
I last time I saw him was at the the uh
我上次见到他是在……
Senate hearings I think what last last
我认为参议院听证会的最后环节是什么？
year. Those look fun. Should try it
年。看起来很有趣。应该试试
sometime. No no no chance. No
某个时候。绝对不可能。不
chance. By
机会。经过
2014, when you were 24 years old, 40% of
2014年，你24岁的时候，40%
US adults were using Snapchat every day.
美国成年人每天都在使用Snapchat。
And by 2015, Snapchat was reaching 75
到2015年，Snapchat的用户数量已达到7500万。
million users on a monthly basis. At
每月数百万用户。在
that point, what's life like for you as
那时，你的生活是怎样的？
a CEO, as a founder? This was 2015.
既是首席执行官，又是创始人？那是2015年。
2014, 2015. 2014, 2015. You became the
2014年，2015年。2014年，2015年。你成为了
world's youngest billionaire at the age
世界上最年轻的亿万富翁，当时年龄
of 25, just four years after launching
推出仅四年后，就达到了25岁
Snapchat with an estimated net worth of
Snapchat 的净资产估计为
4 billion at the time. life was pretty
当时为40亿。生活很美好
good. I met my wife in 2014 uh which uh
好的。我是在2014年认识我妻子的，呃，就是那一年。
was a gamecher for me. Um and why now?
对我来说，他是个游戏玩家。嗯，为什么是现在？
She's an incredible just an incredible
她真是个了不起的人，简直太棒了。
woman and and really gave me a huge
女人，而且真的给了我巨大的
sense of stability and a massive amount
稳定感和大量的
of support. She has a she really cares
支持。她很关心别人。
about wellness. That's something that
关于健康。这是……
she's really passionate about. So, it's
她对此充满热情。所以，就是这样。
like I live with a wellness coach
就像我和一位健康教练住在一起一样
basically every single day. And you know
基本上每天都是如此。你知道
to have that sort of stability and
拥有那种稳定性和
support system while going through you
在你经历这一切的过程中，你需要支持系统。
know building our business was just
知道建立我们的业务只是
profoundly helpful. How do you manage
非常有帮助。你是如何管理的
that though? How do you manage a
是吗？你如何管理一个
romantic relationship when you are
当你处于浪漫关系中时
piloting a rocket ship? I think one of
驾驶火箭飞船？我认为其中一个
the things that was really helpful is
真正有帮助的是
she's you know incredibly accomplished
她是一位非常有成就的人。
herself. She has her own business that
她自己。她有自己的公司。
she is working on called Core Organics
她正在研究一个名为“核心有机物”的项目。
which is a an organic skincare business.
这是一家有机护肤品公司。
Um, so she really understands that it's
嗯，所以她真的明白这一点。
hard to be an entrepreneur and was
创业很难，而且
always really supportive, um, you know,
一直都很支持我，嗯，你知道的。
of of my work and my commitment to my
我的工作以及我对我的承诺
work and our team. And so, um, I think
工作和我们的团队。所以，嗯，我想
that was almost something that brought
那几乎是一件带来……的事情
us together, not something that, you
我们在一起，而不是什么，你
know, pushed us apart. And I think it's
知道，这让我们渐行渐远。我觉得是
interesting. I talk to a lot of people
有趣的。我和很多人交谈过
who, you know, sometimes say, "Hey, my
你知道，有些人有时会说，“嘿，我的
relationship's been under strain because
由于以下原因，双方关系一直处于紧张状态。
I'm working so much." And what I realize
我工作非常努力。”而我意识到
when I have those conversations with
当我与……进行这些对话时
people is very often times they met
人们经常会遇到
their spouse when they weren't working
他们的配偶在他们不工作的时候会陪伴他们。
as much. they met their spouse 10 years
差不多。他们相识于10年前
ago, 15 years, 20 years ago, you know,
15年前，20年前，你知道的。
when they were just getting started in
当他们刚刚开始的时候
their career. And I think, you know, it
他们的职业生涯。而且我觉得，你知道，它
can be difficult when you have a much
当你有很多事情要做的时候，这可能会很困难。
bigger job and it's all time, you know,
工作量更大，而且要花很多时间，你知道的。
all consuming and your spouse is like,
这件事占据了你全部的精力，而你的配偶却说：
"Remember when we first met and you
“还记得我们初次见面的时候吗？”
weren't working all that much? You were
工作量其实不大？你曾是
spending more time with me." From the
多花点时间陪陪我。”
minute I met my wife, we were both
我见到我妻子的那一刻，我们俩
working flat out. And so, I think this
全力以赴。所以，我认为这一点
expectation that, you know, we both work
期望是，你知道，我们俩都会工作
all the time to support our our
始终支持我们
business, support our family, do what we
经营生意，养家糊口，做我们该做的事
love to do was kind of just built into
喜欢做的事情似乎是与生俱来的。
the relationship. But then how do you
这种关系。但是，你该如何……
how would you make time to see each
你会如何安排时间去看望他们？
other? Do you need to put systems in
其他？你需要安装系统吗？
place to make sure that you're not just
确保你不仅仅是一个地方
both at the office the whole time? One
他们俩一直都在办公室吗？一
of the things that's really been helpful
真正有帮助的事情之一
that we started doing a couple years ago
这是我们几年前开始做的。
is just having Sunday family day. Always
就是周日和家人一起过家庭日。总是
family day. Um and that means everyone's
家庭日。嗯，这意味着每个人的
at home. And so if our kids want to have
在家里。所以如果我们的孩子想要拥有
friends over or whatever, that's totally
朋友来家里玩什么的，完全没问题。
fine. But they're not going to their
美好的。但他们不会去他们的
friends houses or everyone's together.
去朋友家或者大家一起住。
And you know just dedicating that time
你知道，就是投入那段时间。
to to our family is is really important.
对我们家人来说，这真的很重要。
What role does she play in giving you
她在给你的过程中扮演什么角色？
feedback? Oh wow. Um she she gives very
反馈？哇哦。嗯，她，她非常
uh very candid feedback.
非常坦诚的反馈。
Which is a gift, right? It's a gift.
这难道不是一种恩赐吗？这是份礼物。
Um yeah, and I think she's really
嗯，是的，我觉得她真的很
passionate about areas that are
对以下领域充满热情：
different than what I'm passionate
和我热衷的事情不一样
about. And so, you know, she's able to
关于。所以，你知道，她能够
give me feedback in in different areas
请从不同方面给我反馈
or things that I really even wouldn't
或者一些我根本不会做的事情
consider, you know. Is there any tough
想想看。有没有什么难题？
feedback that she shared with you that
她与你分享的反馈是：
you can share with me? You know, I think
你能跟我分享一下吗？你知道，我觉得
one of the challenges that I have
我面临的挑战之一是
sometimes is I have I can have a very
有时候，我可能会非常
like harsh tone. Like even if what I'm
就像刺耳的音调。即使我
saying is really, you know, I'm trying
说实话，你知道，我正在努力
to be helpful or kind or whatever. I I
乐于助人、友善或其他任何方式。我 我
was raised by my dad was a litigator, my
我由父亲抚养长大，他是一名诉讼律师，我的
mom was a tax lawyer. Like I I grew up
我妈妈是税务律师。就像我长大后一样
listening to my dad have very intense
听我爸爸说话非常激烈
conversations on the phone all the time.
一直都在打电话。
And so like in business mode, I can be
所以就像在商务模式下一样，我可以
very direct. Um, and I don't think it's
非常直接。嗯，我不认为这是……
helpful. And I don't think people want
有帮助。而且我认为人们并不想这样
to listen when you have a, you know, a
当你……你知道的……的时候，要认真倾听。
sharp or aggressive tone. And so I think
语气尖锐或咄咄逼人。所以我认为
she she's always just encouraging me
她总是鼓励我。
like, hey, you could say the same thing
比如，嘿，你也可以这么说。
but in like a slightly different way.
但方式略有不同。
And people will hear it. You know, my
人们会听到的。你知道，我的
girlfriend says that to me because I
女朋友这么说是因为我
think sometimes I I fail to context
有时我觉得我没能理解上下文。
switch out of work, Steve, to then and
史蒂夫，换个工作吧。
you know, because you'll be getting
你知道，因为你将会得到
emails and texts at home sometimes and
在家时有时会收到电子邮件和短信
my girlfriend might come up and she
我女朋友可能会过来，她
might say something and the way I
可能会说些什么，以及我的方式
respond is almost how I would respond as
回应几乎就是我的回应方式。
if I was at the office, but and it just
如果我在办公室的话，但是，而且只是
and I have to say she's always right
我必须说，她总是对的。
because there is a part of my tone which
因为我的语气中有一部分是
I think
我认为
was conveying the emotion I was feeling
表达了我当时的感受
from the thing I was doing to her to try
从我当时对她做的事来看，我试图……
and con to get her to leave me alone.
用计让她别再烦我了。
This is something we can both work on.
这是我们双方都可以努力的方向。
It's crazy. It's crazy that Matt is so
太疯狂了。马特竟然如此……真是太不可思议了。
much at home the way you say something.
你说话的方式让我感觉很自在。
100%. And having an empathy and a and a
100%。并且拥有同理心和……
kindness. Um, and you you've had four
仁慈。嗯，你已经有四个了。
children as well, which is something
孩子们也是如此，这真是一件……
that I've not had. So, for me, that's an
我没有过。所以，对我来说，那是一个
extra responsibility on top of the
除了上述责任之外，还有额外的责任
rocket ship of Snapchat, the
Snapchat 的火箭飞船，
relationship, and now four kids as well.
这段关系，现在他们还有四个孩子。
Yeah. But it's the greatest in the
是的。但它是最棒的
world. I mean, the greatest thing in the
世界。我的意思是，最棒的事情
world to have kids.
世界适合生孩子。
really literally nothing better in the
真的，真的没有比这更好的了。
planet. I mean, I have not found
行星。我的意思是，我还没有找到
anything close. Why? Because the love
任何接近的地方。为什么？因为爱
and connection that you have with your
以及你与你的联系
children is unlike anything else that
孩子与任何其他事物都截然不同。
you'll ever experience. I mean, it's
你将经历的一切。我的意思是，它是
it's profound, you know. How how do you
你知道，这意义深远。你如何
both juggle the the four children, the
他们俩都要照顾四个孩子。
businesses, the relationship?
企业之间的关系？
Well, I think Miranda probably juggles
嗯，我觉得米兰达可能同时兼顾好几件事。
it better than I do. I think um and
它比我做得好。我觉得嗯……
she's really committed to spending time
她真的很投入地花时间
with our children. I mean that's
和我们的孩子一起。我的意思是，那是
something that's so important to her and
对她来说，这件事非常重要，
it's important uh to me. I don't think
这对我来说很重要。我不认为
you know I I spent a lot of time
你知道我花了很多时间
actually over the years just I found
事实上，这些年来我发现
people who are extremely successful and
那些非常成功的人
just like asked them like hey how do you
就像问他们“嘿，你好吗？”
raise great kids like you've been
像你一样培养出色的孩子
extremely successful. How'd you do it?
非常成功。你是怎么做到的？
And my basic takeaway from like a
我从中得到的基本结论是……
hundred of these conversations was
数百次这样的对话
basically that parents that are actually
基本上，那些父母实际上是
committed that can spend that time with
承诺可以花那些时间陪伴
their kids and do it themselves, engage
他们的孩子也参与其中，并且自己动手。
with their kids themselves, they tend to
他们对待自己的孩子往往如此
have really fruitful relationship with
与……建立了非常富有成效的关系
their kids, and their kids seem to turn
他们的孩子，以及他们的孩子似乎都变成了
out really great. And I it breaks my
效果非常好。这让我心碎
heart that there are so many parents
心里想着，有这么多父母
that can't spend that direct one-on-one
无法进行一对一的直接交流
time with their kids or I guess in my
他们和孩子们在一起的时间，或者我想在我的
case one on four time uh with with their
案例一到四次，呃，和他们的
kids because that seems to be kind of
孩子们，因为这似乎有点……
the key ingredient is that connection
关键在于这种联系。
with your parents being there. Yeah. Do
父母也在场。是的。做
you own a business or do you work in
您拥有自己的企业还是在企业工作？
marketing? If that's you, listen up for
营销？如果你就是这种情况，请注意听。
a valuable opportunity from our show
我们节目带来的宝贵机会
sponsor LinkedIn. I'm an investor in
赞助领英。我是某公司的投资者
about 40 odd companies and while they
大约有40多家公司，而他们
operate in different industries, they
他们从事不同的行业。
all face one challenge. Maybe the most
他们都面临着同一个挑战。或许最
important challenge when it comes to
在以下方面，这是一个重要的挑战：
marketing, getting their brand in front
营销，让他们的品牌脱颖而出
of the right audiences. We can probably
面向合适的受众。我们大概可以
all think of times when we've been
我们都想起了那些我们曾经……的时刻
scrolling on social media and received
在社交媒体上浏览并收到
an ad that absolutely wasn't relevant to
一条与主题完全无关的广告
us. LinkedIn has now grown to a network
我们。 LinkedIn如今已发展成为一个社交网络。
of over a billion professionals,
超过十亿专业人士，
including 130 million decision makers,
其中包括1.3亿决策者，
which means you can specifically target
这意味着你可以进行精准定位
your buyers by job title, seniority,
按职位、资历筛选买家
industry, even company revenue. So, stop
行业，甚至公司收入。所以，停下来。
wasting your marketing budget on the
把营销预算浪费在……上
wrong audience and start targeting the
找错目标受众，开始进行错误定位
right crowd through LinkedIn now. And
现在可以通过LinkedIn找到合适的人脉。和
because you're part of my community,
因为你是我的社区的一份子，
LinkedIn is offering you a $100 credit
LinkedIn 为您提供 100 美元信用额度
for your next campaign. Head to
为您的下一次竞选活动做准备。前往
linkedin.com/diary to claim yours now.
立即访问 linkedin.com/diary 领取您的专属日记。
That's
那是
linkedin.com/diary. And of course, terms
linkedin.com/diary。当然，还有条款。
and conditions apply and only available
须遵守相关条款及细则，且仅限部分地区提供。
on LinkedIn ads. I saw your LinkedIn
在 LinkedIn 广告上。我看了你的领英个人资料。我看了你的领英。
page. I saw your bio. Do you know what
页。我看了你的个人简介。你知道吗？
I'm going to say? I think so. Yeah. In
我该怎么说呢？我也这么认为。是的。在
your LinkedIn bio, it says that you're
你的LinkedIn个人简介上写着你是
the I think VP of product at Meta. Is it
我认为是 Meta 的产品副总裁。是吗？
not my joke? We we uh we uh have
这不是我的笑话吗？我们呃我们呃有
appropriated that joke from I think Cara
我觉得这个笑话是从卡拉那里借来的。
Swisser who who originated it. But I
瑞士人是它的创始人。但我
think now that they've copied ephemeral
现在想想，他们已经抄袭了短暂的
messaging and stories, everything, you
信息和故事，一切，你
know, a lot of the stuff we've done in
我知道，我们做的很多事情
augmented reality, of course, now they
当然，现在是增强现实技术了。
say they're working on glasses, um
他们说正在研发眼镜，嗯。
which, you know, we've been working on
你知道，我们一直在努力……
for over a decade. I think, um I think
十多年来。我想，嗯，我想
I've I think I've earned that earned
我认为我已经赢得了这份荣誉
that title. I don't know.
那个标题。我不知道。
That must piss you
那肯定让你很生气。
off because that would piss me off. Like
关掉，因为那样会让我生气。喜欢
I can sit on a podcast and I can say now
我可以坐在播客节目里，现在就可以说了。
I wouldn't be bothered. You know, the
我才不会在意呢。你知道，
thing is that blah blah blah blah blah.
问题是，等等等等。
But no, that would piss me off because
不，那样会让我生气，因为
you just told me that there's a lot of
你刚才告诉我有很多
people that are going to great creative
那些即将成为伟大创意人才的人
lengths to think of these ideas. They're
仔细思考这些想法。他们是
having thousands of ideas. You're you're
拥有成千上万个想法。你是 你是
fighting to find one and then you have
费尽心思寻找，然后你就有了
that moment where you present it to the
当你把它展示给……的那一刻
world. The world says, "This is
世界。世界说：“这是
interesting." You you know the guy that
有意思。“你知道那个人吗？”
came up with it. You sit next to him.
我想出来的。你坐在他旁边。
One of the things that's incredibly
其中一件令人难以置信的事情
irritating about it is they repurpose
令人恼火的是，他们会重新利用
our inventions to make products that
我们发明创造的产品，
make people feel unhappy and bad about
让人感到不快乐和难过
themselves. One of the things that was
他们自己。其中一件事是
so fascinating just in the last year
过去一年真是太精彩了。
there was a study out of the Netherland
荷兰有一项研究
totally independent study out of the
完全独立的研究
Netherlands. we weren't involved.
荷兰。我们没有参与其中。
Another one out of Australia and it was
另一个来自澳大利亚的案例是
comparing I think like Instagram, Tik
我觉得可以和 Instagram、TikTok 之类的比较。
Tok and Snapchat and it it basically
Tok 和 Snapchat，基本上就是这样。
found that Snapchat there there are no
发现 Snapchat 上没有
negative they the study determined there
研究结果为阴性。
were no negative health imp me mental
没有对我的心理健康造成任何负面影响
health implications of using Snapchat
使用 Snapchat 对健康的影响
but there were negative mental health
但存在负面的心理健康问题
implications of using Instagram and Tik
使用 Instagram 和 TikTok 的影响
Tok and in fact I think the study in the
Tok，事实上我认为这项研究
Netherlands found Snapchat actually
荷兰人发现 Snapchat 实际上
promotes well-being and helps uh promote
促进身心健康并有助于促进
your relationships as well and so I
你的人际关系也是如此，所以我
think what's really frustrating is when
真正令人沮丧的是……
people think because they've copied some
人们认为，因为他们抄袭了一些东西。
of our features that the products are
我们的产品具有以下特点：
the same or that they do the same thing
相同，或者他们做同样的事情
when our product is designed in a way
当我们的产品以某种方式设计时
that's very different that's designed to
那与旨在……的设计截然不同
support your relationships with your
支持你与你的人际关系
close friends and family and ultimately
亲朋好友，最终
is something that supports your your
这是对你有所帮助的事情
well-being and so what we never want
幸福，以及我们永远不想要的
anyone to think is if they're using
任何人都可以思考，他们是否在使用
stories on Instagram that that's the
Instagram上的故事就是如此
same as Snapchat and you know even
跟 Snapchat 一样，你知道的，甚至
though they stole the the the name of
虽然他们盗用了……的名字
the product or the way that you know
该产品或您了解的方式
some of some of the functionality of it
它的一些功能
the way that Snapchat is designed on the
Snapchat 的设计方式
whole is something that can have a
整体可以包含
really positive impact in in people's
对人们产生了非常积极的影响
lives And that's not something that
生命，而那不是……
people feel when they use Instagram. Did
人们在使用Instagram时的感受。做过
you ever consider sending Mark an email
你有没有考虑过给马克发邮件？
or like a message or a phone call when
或者像发短信或打电话一样
they first started copying some of your
他们一开始就开始抄袭你的一些东西。
core features like the story feature?
故事功能等核心功能？
No. No, we we didn't do that. I think,
不，我们没有做那件事。我认为，
you know, one of the things that I
你知道，其中一件事是……
really admire about Kevin Cyrum is when
真正欣赏凯文·赛勒姆的地方在于……
they copied the the stories feature,
他们抄袭了故事功能，
they they stopped pretending that they
他们不再假装
were doing anything different. I mean,
我们有什么不同之处吗？我是说，
with with things like Poke, they tried
他们尝试过像Poke这样的游戏。
to sort of pass it off as their own
算是把它当作自己的成果。
creation. Oh, we're do, you know, doing
创建。哦，我们正在做，你知道，做
it a little bit differently. with, you
略有不同。与你
know, with stories. Um, you know, Kevin
通过故事了解。嗯，你知道，凯文
Cistro came out and just said, "Hey, we
西斯特罗走出来，只说了句：“嘿，我们
think this is a really great feature.
我觉得这真是一个很棒的功能。
This is a really great product and like
这是一款非常棒的产品，我喜欢
we're going to steal it and put it in
我们要把它偷走，然后放进去
Instagram and we think you're going to
Instagram，我们认为你会……
love it." And, you know, I I think that
我喜欢它。”而且，你知道，我认为
the honesty at least was admirable. Is
至少这种诚实令人钦佩。是
there do you feel a sense of injustice
你是否感到不公？
when someone steals your idea like that?
当有人这样窃取你的创意时，你会作何感想？
No, not at all. I mean, that that is
不，完全不是。我的意思是，那就是
sort of the the I you know, I'm sure you
有点像我，你知道，我确定你
know the saying like, you know, great
我知道那句话的意思，比如，你知道，很棒
artists uh steal. I think like one of
艺术家们会偷窃。我觉得就像其中一个
the things about our industry is that
我们这个行业的特点是……
people are constantly being inspired by
人们不断受到启发
one another. I mean in the very early
彼此。我的意思是，在非常早期
days I went to visit bite dance when
那天我去拜访了咬舞团
they only had Totia the app Totia which
他们只有 Totia 这个应用程序，它
was a news a newsfeed app essentially
基本上就是一个新闻推送应用
but it was backed by AI by ML and when I
但它得到了人工智能和机器学习的支持，当我
saw that uh that was really inspiring to
看到那件事，真是令人鼓舞。
me and we made a big change to our
我和我们对我们的……做出了重大改变
product. We actually separated out all
产品。我们实际上把所有东西都分开了
the creator and publisher content from
内容的创作者和发布者
our sto from stories from friends and we
我们的商店来自朋友和我们的故事
said hey you know unlike social media
嘿，你知道，不像社交媒体
where you're seeing content based on
你看到的内容是基于
what your friends like or what your
你的朋友喜欢什么，或者你
friends comment on on Snapchat we're
朋友们在 Snapchat 上评论我们
going to do ML driven recommendations.
将会采用机器学习驱动的推荐系统。
So you'll have content from your friends
这样你就能收到来自朋友的内容了
but then you're going to have this whole
但之后你就会面临这一切
other world of content from creators and
来自创作者的其他内容世界
publishers that's going to be
出版商们将会是
recommended based on your interests and
根据您的兴趣推荐
and and what you're passionate about.
以及你所热衷的事情。
And so I do think like drawing
所以我觉得画画就像画画一样。
inspiration from other uh companies and
从其他公司汲取灵感
other businesses is is part of
其他企业是其中的一部分
innovating. Um so so I think it is it's
创新。嗯，所以，我觉得是的。
uh it's a part of the game, but it
呃，这是游戏的一部分，但是
definitely showed us that if we're going
这无疑向我们展示了，如果我们要去
to innovate, if we're going to make new
要进行创新，如果我们想要创造新的事物。
products, we ought to make things that
产品，我们应该制造出这样的东西。
are really difficult to copy. Uh that
真的很难复制。呃，那个
take a long time to copy that are really
复制这些真的需要很长时间
hard to do. Because if you go after
很难做到。因为如果你追随
really difficult and hard things, it's
非常困难的事情，这是
much harder for these large uh companies
对于这些大型公司来说，这要困难得多。
to to just copy them. Cuz I'm thinking
直接复制它们。因为我在想
about so many founders that I know that
我认识的很多创始人都是这样。
have started businesses and it might be
已经创办了企业，而且可能是
anything from a t-shirt company to maybe
从T恤公司到……任何东西
it's a podcast and they're dealing with
这是一个播客，他们正在处理……
people copying their ideas and sometimes
人们抄袭他们的想法，有时
they react really badly and they take to
他们的反应非常糟糕，而且他们会……
social media and they post both and say,
他们在社交媒体上发布这两篇文章，并说道：
"Look, this person copied us." And they
“你看，这个人抄袭了我们。”他们
tag the brand. What advice would you
给品牌贴标签。你会给出什么建议？
give to founders that are being knocked
帮助那些正经历困境的创业者
off? I I think it's really important to
离开？我认为这一点非常重要
very very quickly evolve from being just
非常非常迅速地从仅仅是演变而来
a product or just a feature to becoming
成为产品或功能
a platform or an ecosystem. And so what
一个平台或一个生态系统。所以呢？
I mean by that is if I if I compare the
我的意思是，如果我比较……
early days of stories where people just
故事的早期阶段，人们只是
were posting stories uh for one another,
我们互相发布故事，
it's relatively easy to copy that
复制这个相对容易。
feature. You know, it's you can code
特征。你知道，就是你会编程。
that up pretty quickly. Probably with AI
很快就达到了目标。可能借助人工智能
now, you can code it up very quickly.
现在，你可以很快地编写出代码。
When I look at what we've done with
当我回顾我们所做的事情时
augmented reality, right, we have a Lens
对，增强现实，我们有一个镜头
Core, which is our own rendering engine
Core，也就是我们自己的渲染引擎
for for augmented reality that runs on
用于运行在
the phone, but also on our glasses. We
手机上，还有我们的眼镜上。我们
have a a tool called Lens Studio that's
有一款名为 Lens Studio 的工具，它
an incredibly sophisticated tool that
一款极其精密复杂的工具
developers can use to build these AR
开发者可以利用这些工具来构建这些增强现实（AR）产品。
experiences. We have a huge, you know,
经历。我们有一个很大的，你知道，
hundreds of millions of people who are
数亿人
using these AR experiences on the phone.
在手机上使用这些AR体验。
And we have hundreds of thousands of
我们有成千上万的
developers who are making all of these
开发所有这些产品的开发者
AR experiences. When you have that sort
增强现实体验。当你拥有那种类型
of very complicated technology that's
这是一项非常复杂的技术。
hard to copy and you have an ecosystem
难以复制，而且你拥有一个生态系统
of people that are using it both in
在两个方面都使用它的人
terms of developers, you know, creators
就开发者而言，你知道，就是创作者。
and also our community who love uh those
还有我们社区里那些热爱这些的人。
AR experiences, it becomes very very
AR体验，它变得非常非常
hard to, you know, copy the four million
很难，你知道，复制那四百万
lenses that developers have created for
开发者为镜头创建的镜头
our platform. Uh you know, or move the
我们的平台。呃，你知道，或者移动
the hundreds of millions of people who
数亿人
are enjoying augmented reality on
正在享受增强现实技术
Snapchat to a new platform. And so
Snapchat 迁移到新平台。所以
especially in the technology business,
尤其是在科技行业，
the faster you can evolve from being,
你越快能从现状进化，
you know, a feature or a product to a
你知道，对一个产品或功能来说
real platform, I think that's where the
真正的平台，我认为就在那里。
value is created over the long term. So
价值是在长期积累中创造出来的。所以
it's almost this relationship between
这几乎就是两者之间的这种关系
like how hard and complicated the thing
比如这件事有多难多复杂。
was to build and and create is sort of
建造和创造是一种……
inversely correlated to how easy it is
与它的难易程度呈反比
to copy. I think so. And then you know
复制。我也这么认为。然后你就知道了
how how much of an ecosystem it is in
它究竟在多大程度上属于一个生态系统？
terms of other people using it, right?
用其他人的说法，对吧？
Almost more of like a marketplace,
更像是一个集市，
right? um it it makes it very difficult
正确的？嗯，这让事情变得非常困难。
to to migrate both sides of the
迁移两侧
marketplace.
市场。
Do you think that the technology
你认为这项技术
companies that exist now, those trillion
现在存在的那些公司，数万亿美元
dollar ones, those big social platforms,
那些大型社交平台，比如那些一美元的平台。
are monopolies and should be broken up?
这些企业是否属于垄断企业，应该被拆分？
Because there was a big call originally
因为最初接到了一个大电话。
to break these companies up and you've
要拆分这些公司，你就得……
been, I guess you could say, victim to
我想你可以说，我成了受害者
the strength of a monopoly being able to
垄断的力量在于能够
swoop in, copy, replicate, steal, and
突袭、复制、仿制、窃取，以及
innovation. I think what matters more
创新。我认为更重要的是
about whether or not they're monopolies
关于它们是否属于垄断企业的问题
is sort of what do you what do we think
这有点像你觉得我们怎么想
is going to happen next, right? I mean,
接下来肯定会发生这件事，对吧？我是说，
if you remember, there was a period of
如果你还记得的话，曾有一段时间
time when everyone thought that
当时每个人都这么认为
Microsoft was going to take over the
微软原本打算接管
world. They were caught up in a lot of
世界。他们卷入了很多事情
antitrust legislation or um antitrust um
反垄断立法或反垄断法
sort of inquiries and and uh lawsuits
各种调查和诉讼
and whatnot. And ultimately as a result
等等。最终结果是
maybe of being distracted by the
或许是因为被……分心了
lawsuits but I think also just a
诉讼，但我认为也只是……
function of how they thought about their
他们如何看待自己的功能
business at the time they they missed
当时他们错过了商机。
the entire mobile cycle. Um you know I I
整个移动周期。嗯，你知道我
think people are looking at Google right
认为人们正在关注谷歌。
now and saying is there a similar moment
现在，人们会问，是否存在类似的时刻？
happening for Google? Google is subject
谷歌那边发生了什么？谷歌是……
to a lot of these antitrust um
对很多反垄断机构来说
inquiries. Is chat GBT for example
查询。例如，聊天是GBT吗？
coming along and with AI you know
随着人工智能的发展，你知道的。
actually going to make it a lot harder
实际上会使事情变得更加困难。
for Google's core business to to
为了谷歌的核心业务
compete? And so I I think given just the
竞争？所以我认为，仅就这一点而言
longevity of the regulatory and
监管的长期性和
litigation cycle, I mean you're talking
诉讼周期，我的意思是，你正在谈论的
10 plus years, it almost doesn't matter
十多年过去了，几乎无关紧要了。
so much if the government thinks that
如果政府认为……那就太好了。
it's a monopoly or not because there's
它是否构成垄断，取决于……
not much it seems like that they're able
看起来他们似乎能力有限。
to do about it. So what I think matters
对此采取行动。所以我认为重要的事情
a lot more for small technology
小型技术还有很多其他优势
companies is thinking about what
公司正在考虑什么
fundamental innovations, fundamental
根本性创新，根本
technologies can we work on, can we
我们可以研究哪些技术？
develop that ultimately can help us grow
发展最终能够帮助我们成长的事物
our business and maybe you know one day
我们的业务，也许有一天你会知道。
catch a catch one of these larger
抓住这些大个子中的一个
companies on a on a back foot. Want to
公司处于被动局面。想要
talk about that. But my last question on
谈谈这个。但我最后一个问题是关于
copying was if you were in Mark
抄写就像你在马克笔下一样
Zuckerberg's shoes would you have copied
你会模仿扎克伯格的鞋子吗？
Snapchat? I think given their market
Snapchat？我认为考虑到他们的市场
position it's a very effective strategy.
这是一种非常有效的策略。
They basically have an enormous cash
他们基本上拥有巨额现金
pile. They I think they're investing $20
桩。我认为他们投资了20美元。
billion a year right now just into, you
现在每年就有数十亿美元，你
know, the the AR glasses stuff and some
我知道，就是AR眼镜之类的东西，还有一些
of their VR stuff. AR glasses stuff is
他们的VR产品。 AR眼镜相关的东西
largely copying what what we've been
很大程度上是照搬我们一直以来的做法。
doing. Um and then outside of that, they
正在做。嗯，除此之外，他们
have tens of billions of dollars and all
拥有数百亿美元，而且
sorts of other investments including
其他类型的投资，包括
copying chatbt, right? And all of the
抄袭 chatbt 对吧？以及所有
the progress on large language models.
大型语言模型的研究进展。
So, I think it's quite an effective
所以，我认为这相当有效。
strategy if you're at that scale
如果你达到了那种规模，就应该采取这种策略。
generating that much cash to just, you
仅仅为了赚到这么多钱，你
know, deploy that capital across a bunch
知道，要把这些资金分散投资到很多方面。
of different bets and wait and see what
不同的赌注，然后拭目以待。
companies are successful and what they
公司成功的原因以及它们
make and then try to throw a ton of
制作并尝试投掷大量
capital uh and and hoping that those
资本，呃，并且希望那些
companies don't get to scale. Was was
公司无法实现规模化发展。是
there a hard day for you amongst all of
在所有人之中，今天对你来说可能是艰难的一天。
this copying? Was there a hardist day
这是抄袭吗？有没有最艰难的一天？
that you can recall? Um there there was
你还记得吗？嗯，那里有
a lot of concern when Instagram stories
Instagram Stories 引发了很多担忧
first launched that Snapchat would
Snapchat 最初推出时表示
essentially be obsolete and you know
基本上已经过时了，你知道的。
they they did a very good job talking
他们谈话做得非常好。
about how many people were using you
大约有多少人使用过你
know stories and we got a lot of
知道一些故事，我们有很多
questions and pressure about you know is
关于你的疑问和压力是
Snapchat ever going to succeed and
Snapchat 真的会成功吗？
people didn't I I don't think they
人们没有，我不认为他们
realized at the time that folks were
当时意识到人们是
using Instagram mostly for content
我主要使用 Instagram 来发布内容。
creators and influencers and that sort
创作者、影响者等等
of thing and they were mostly using
东西，他们大多在使用
Snapchat for their friends and family
他们用 Snapchat 与朋友和家人分享
and so we had really focused on this
所以我们一直非常重视这一点。
friends and family use case that was not
朋友和家人使用案例并非如此
really what Instagram was going after.
这才是Instagram真正想要达到的目标。
they were much more focused uh on
他们更专注于……
influencers and and I think it was
影响者，而且我认为是
really only because Snapchat had started
其实只是因为 Snapchat 开始流行起来了。
growing with those influencers. If you
与这些有影响力的人共同成长。如果你
remember, you know, DJ Khaled and some
记得吗，你知道，DJ Khaled 和一些
of those early snaps, there were
在那些早期的照片中，有
influencers who were starting to join
开始加入的有影响力人士
Snapchat just to use stories, right? To
用Snapchat只是为了用Stories功能，对吧？到
use it differently than how we had
它的用法与我们以往的方式不同。
initially designed it for friends and
最初是为朋友们设计的
family. And I think that's what really
家庭。我认为这才是真正的
got Instagram's attention. So, it was
引起了Instagram的关注。所以，就是这样。
really frustrating in those moments
那些时刻真的令人沮丧
where people were saying, well, how's
人们当时都在问，怎么样？
Snapchat going to survive because they
Snapchat之所以能生存下去，是因为他们
didn't understand that stories on
不理解那些故事
Instagram is for a totally different
Instagram 的用途完全不同。
purpose than, you know, stories on
目的比，你知道，故事
Snapchat? You must see that coming
Snapchat？你应该预料到这种情况的发生。
because people start leaking that
因为人们开始泄露这些信息。
there's this new feature coming. I I was
即将推出一项新功能。我当时
running a social media business at the
在一家社交媒体公司运营
time and there were hackers that can
时间流逝，黑客也随之出现。
kind of look into code bases and see
稍微查看一下代码库，看看
what features are about to come and then
接下来会有哪些功能？
it's leaked out to the blog. So as a
消息已经泄露到博客上了。所以，作为一个
team you're managing the emotions of a
你正在管理团队的情绪
group of people and that group of people
一群人和那群人
they're all hearing that the biggest
他们都听说了最大的
player in the game is about to launch a
游戏中的一名玩家即将发射
central feature of your proposition. How
你方案的核心特征。如何
is the leader do you manage the emotions
作为领导者，你如何管理情绪？
of the people through that? Well, I
通过那件事，人们会怎么做？嗯，我
think that can be something that is, you
认为这可能是某种东西，你
know, energizing for a team, right? If
你知道，这对团队来说是一种激励，对吧？如果
you have some of the biggest companies
你们拥有一些最大的公司
in the world validating what you're
在世界上，这证明了你的价值。
working on, that can be really
正在努力，这可能真的
energizing if you approach it that way,
如果你用那种方式看待它，它会给你带来活力。
right? So, I think rather than just
正确的？所以，我认为与其仅仅
saying, "Oh, no, it's, you know, game
他说：“哦，不，你知道，这只是个游戏。”
over, but it might as well shut the
结束了，但最好还是关掉它
thing down and give up." I think if you
把事情放下，放弃吧。” 我觉得如果你
say, "This is really evidence that we're
例如，“这确实是我们……”的证据
on the right path here, that we're
我们走在正确的道路上，我们
building products that people love, that
打造人们喜爱的产品，
they're getting the attention of some of
他们正在引起一些人的关注
the biggest and most powerful companies
规模最大、实力最强的公司
in the world." You know, let's build on
在世界上。”你知道，让我们在此基础上继续发展。
that. Let's continue to go build
那。让我们继续建设吧。
products that billions of people all
数十亿人使用的产品
over the world will use. And I think
世界各地都将使用。我觉得
ultimately to this point of, you know,
最终到了这个地步，你知道的，
can you hire and and, you know, retain
你能招聘并留住人才吗？
really talented, creative people. I
非常有才华、有创造力的人。我
think it's pretty cool if you're a
如果你是……的话，我觉得这很酷。
designer at Snap that the things you're
Snap 的设计师，你正在做的事情
making are not just, you know, used by
制作不仅仅是，你知道，被……使用
the 850 million plus people that use
超过8.5亿人使用
Snapchat, but billions of people that
Snapchat，但数十亿人
use all sorts of other products because
使用各种其他产品，因为
people get so much inspiration from our
人们从我们这里获得了许多灵感
design team and what they build. I I
设计团队及其作品。我 我
think that's pretty cool. One of the use
我觉得这很酷。其中一种用途
cases that emerged pretty much out of
这些案例几乎都是由此而来
the blue, I think, for for Snapchat was,
我认为，Snapchat 的蓝色是……
and this is this is something I was only
而这正是我一直以来所了解的。
thinking about yesterday is you you at
回想昨天，你就是那个你
some point have to make a decision about
在某个时候，必须做出关于……的决定
like adult
像成年人一样
content on the on the app and Only Fans
应用程序和 OnlyFans 上的内容
have built this massive business now,
如今我们已经建立起了如此庞大的企业，
and they're basically in the adult
他们基本上都属于成人组
content business. At some point you must
内容业务。在某个时候你必须
have had been challenged on that by
曾有人就此提出质疑
investors or by users whether you were
投资者或用户是否是
going to allow adult content to be on
允许成人内容上线
the platform because that would have
因为那样的话，这个平台就会……
been presumably that would have been a
想必那会是……
growing user base. Interesting. Yeah, we
用户群体不断增长。有趣的。是的，我们
we proactively scan for pornography and
我们会主动扫描色情内容，
remove it. I mean it's it's against our
把它移除。我的意思是，这违背了我们的意愿。
uh it's our content guidelines. We've
呃，这是我们的内容准则。我们已经
been doing that for a really uh a really
已经这样做了很久很久了。
long time. So yeah, I mean that's just
很久。是的，我的意思是，就是这样
not how we think about you know our our
不是我们那样想的，你知道我们的
core business. And I I also think, you
核心业务。而且我也觉得，你
know, when you when you think about
你知道，当你想到……
self-expression, the importance of
自我表达的重要性
self-expression, the environment that
自我表达，以及这种环境
you're in really matters, right? And
你的参与真的很重要，对吧？和
that's why we have content guidelines
这就是我们制定内容准则的原因。
because we want people to feel like
因为我们希望人们有这种感觉
they're in an environment where they can
他们身处一个可以……的环境中
express themselves. And I think some of
表达自己。而且我认为其中一些
the the conversation about different
关于不同话题的对话
content guidelines or having content
内容指南或内容
guidelines or not having them has been
制定指导方针或缺乏指导方针一直是
really interesting because I think
真的很有意思，因为我觉得
people are missing the broader point. If
人们忽略了更重要的一点。如果
you have a a platform with no content
你有一个没有内容的平台。
guidelines and it's full of people
有各种规定，而且里面挤满了人。
yelling at each other or saying really
互相大喊大叫或者说真的
mean or offensive things or posting a
发布刻薄或冒犯性的内容或帖子
lot of pornography, that's a really
很多色情内容，这真是太糟糕了。
uncomfortable thing for most people,
对大多数人来说，这是一件令人不舒服的事。
right? That's that's uncomfortable. You
正确的？那让人很不舒服。你
say, "Uh, this maybe this platform isn't
比如说，“呃，也许这个平台不是……”
for me. Maybe I don't feel comfortable
为我。也许我感觉不太自在。
expressing myself here because all the
我在这里表达自己是因为所有
stuff I'm seeing isn't really
我看到的东西其实并不是真的
appropriate or or aligned with my
合适的，或者与我的相符
values." And so one of the things we
价值观。”因此，我们重视的事情之一就是
discovered really early on is if you
很早就发现，如果你
want to create a platform where people
想要创建一个人们可以聚集的平台
feel comfortable expressing themselves,
能够自在地表达自己，
feel comfortable communicating with
与人沟通感到自在
their friends and family, having content
他们的朋友和家人，以及他们的内容
guidelines is really helpful because it
指导方针真的很有帮助，因为它
means that the content experience is one
这意味着内容体验是其中之一
that that feels more comfortable. But
这样感觉更舒服。但
isn't that people would say well that
人们不会说“好吧”
censorship? I'm thinking now of the
审查制度？我现在在想……
video that Mark Zuckerberg released
马克·扎克伯格发布的视频
about Meta's change to their moderation
关于 Meta 对其审核方式的改变
systems moving to Texas realizing that I
系统迁移到德克萨斯州，意识到我
think he said that they'd overindexed
我记得他说过他们指数过高。
with their moderators in terms of
与他们的版主沟通方面
left-leaning politics. So, a lot of the
左倾政治。所以，很多
right-leaning content had been censored.
右倾内容遭到审查。
What do you make of that argument for
你如何看待这种论点？
content moderation that we don't want to
我们不希望进行的内容审核
censor people? I think it's a
审查民众？我认为这是一个
misunderstanding of the the First
对第一部的误解
Amendment and and how it applies. If we
修正案及其适用方式。如果我们
look at our country, uh, the way, you
看看我们的国家，呃，看看你现在的样子
know, at least here in the United States
至少在美国是这样。
with the first amendment that really
第一修正案确实
focuses on the way that the government
重点关注政府的方式
interacts with content creators or
与内容创作者互动或
content publishers and it says, hey,
内容发布者们说，嘿，
it's not okay for the government to
政府这样做是不对的
interfere with individuals or publishers
干扰个人或出版商
self-expression, right? That's not
自我表达，对吧？那不是
allowed. But one of the things the first
允许。但首先，其中一件事是……
amendment also does is say, you know,
修正案还规定，你知道，
platforms or individuals can make
平台或个人可以做出
choices about what sort of content they
他们可以选择观看哪种类型的内容
want to promote or want to have on their
想要推广或想要拥有
platform. That's part of the first
平台。这是第一部分的一部分。
amendment. You can't force the Wall
修正案。你无法强行穿过这堵墙。
Street Journal to, you know, put this
《街头杂志》也报道了此事。
article or that article or accept any
文章或该文章或接受任何
article from any author all around the
来自世界各地任何作者的文章
world. The Wall Street Journal as a
世界。 《华尔街日报》作为
paper can decide what, you know, what
纸张可以决定什么，你知道的，什么
authors, you know, it wants to include
作者们，你知道，它想包括
on on its pages. And that's part of the
在其页面上。而这又是……的一部分
protected first amendment expression we
我们受宪法第一修正案保护的言论自由
have here in this country. So this whole
在这个国家，我们有。所以这一切
notion of of censorship doesn't apply to
审查制度的概念并不适用于
to companies that are private businesses
致那些属于私营企业的公司
that actually have a first amendment
实际上拥有第一修正案
right to decide what content is on their
他们有权决定他们的网站上可以显示哪些内容。
platform. And they may want to decide.
平台。他们或许想要做出决定。
We're open to literally anything.
我们对任何事情都持开放态度。
Anything goes. No problem. And it seems
什么都可以。没问题。而且似乎
like some platforms are making that
就像某些平台正在做的那样。
choice. But other platforms like ours
选择。但其他像我们这样的平台
say, "Hey, in order to have a healthy
例如，“嘿，为了拥有一个健康的
set of discourse across our platform, in
我们平台上的一系列讨论，
order to make sure people feel
为了确保人们感到
comfortable when they're viewing content
他们在观看内容时感到舒适
on our platform, we don't want people to
在我们的平台上，我们不希望人们
come across pornography, for example, or
例如，接触到色情内容，或者
violent content or, you know, hateful
暴力内容，或者，你知道的，仇恨内容
content. That that's not something that
内容。那并不是……
makes people feel good. And we actually
让人感觉良好。我们实际上
want to make sure that that that content
想确保这些内容
isn't on our platform because it doesn't
它不在我们的平台上，因为它没有
comply with our our guidelines." And
请遵守我们的准则。”
that may be one of the reasons why in
这或许是其中一个原因。
some of these studies it shows that
其中一些研究表明
people feel better when they use
人们使用后感觉更好
Snapchat because they're not
因为他们不是 Snapchat
encountering, you know, really violent
遇到，你知道，非常暴力
uh content when when they're using
呃，内容当他们使用时
Snapchat. Is there an issue that if
Snapchat。是否存在这样的问题：
you're geographically based in Los
你的地理位置在洛杉矶
Angeles or California, then your content
洛杉矶或加利福尼亚，然后是你的内容
moderation perspective is going to be
温和的视角将是
very left-leaning versus if you're based
非常左倾与如果你是基层主义者相比
in a red state and that might not be
在一个红色州，这可能并非如此
representative of the world. Or do you
世界代表。或者你呢？
just not care? Did you just think, well,
就是不在乎？你刚才是不是在想，嗯？
these are these are our values as a
这些是我们作为一家公司的价值观。
company. So, I don't think so because I
公司。所以，我不这么认为，因为……
don't think saying, you know, extreme
别想当然地认为，说出来会很极端。
violence is not something we want on our
我们不希望看到暴力发生。
platform. I don't think that's
平台。我不认为那是……
political. I I think that's a
政治的。我认为那是
values-based decision. Or saying we
基于价值观的决策。或者说我们
don't we don't want to service
我们不想提供服务。
pornography to our community. I I don't
向我们的社区传播色情内容。我不
think that that's, you know, political
我觉得这跟政治有关。
choice. I think that's a values-based
选择。我认为这是基于价值观的。
decision. So, I think unfortunately
决定。所以，我觉得很遗憾。
right now in our culture, there's
在我们当今的文化中，存在着……
actually a real temptation to politicize
实际上，将此事政治化的诱惑力很大。
things that are actually quite common
一些其实很常见的事情
sensical. And so I think we have to
合乎逻辑的。所以我认为我们必须
avoid that that temptation and instead
避免这种诱惑，而是……
focus on you know what are the values or
专注于你所知道的价值观或
the business choices that people are
人们的商业选择
making. Why do you think Meta have
制作。你认为Meta为什么会有……
rolled back their moderation policies?
他们是否撤销了审核政策？
I I'm not sure. I I think you know there
我不太确定。我想你知道那里
there's a moment in time when they seem
有那么一刻，他们似乎
to have a lot of support to do it. I I
需要得到很多支持才能做到。我 我
think it'll be challenging for them in
我认为这对他们来说将是一个挑战
Europe for example where there's a lot
例如欧洲，那里有很多
of rules and regulations about you know
关于你知道的规章制度
prohibiting things like hate speech for
禁止仇恨言论等行为
example or or terrorist content. And I
例如或恐怖主义内容。我
think um it'll be interesting to see how
想想看，这挺有意思的，看看会发生什么
they navigate that. It's certainly a lot
他们设法克服了这个问题。这确实很多。
less expensive to to avoid moderating
避免审核的成本更低。
content. It costs money to moderate uh
内容。主持节目需要花钱。
content and I that could be a
内容和我，这可能是一个
consideration as well. If you don't
也需要考虑这一点。如果你不
moderate content, does engagement go up?
内容适中，互动率会上升吗？
That's a that's a great question. I've
这是一个很好的问题。我已经
seen some reports and some studies that
我看到一些报告和研究，
show um that, you know, if content is is
让他们知道，如果内容是……
moderated, engagement can go down. Um
如果进行调节，参与度可能会下降。嗯
certainly there are studies that show
当然，也有研究表明
that negative content spreads much
负面内容传播非常广泛
further and faster on social media for
在社交媒体上传播得更远、更快
human reasons. Um but but I'm not sure
人为因素。嗯，但是，我不确定
in this particular instance. How are you
就此而言。你好吗
how are you feeling about the social
你对社交方面有什么感受？
media landscape? It's changed so much in
媒体格局？它变化太大了。
the last six months. It's just not even
过去六个月。这根本就不是……
six months, I'd say 12 months since I
六个月，我想说，自从我……以来已经十二个月了。
think Elon bought Twitter, now called X
想想埃隆·马斯克收购了推特，现在叫X
that it's almost like this domino effect
这几乎就像多米诺骨牌效应一样。
has happened in terms of content
内容方面已经发生了变化
moderation, in terms of the types of
适度，就其类型而言
voices on social media, in terms of this
社交媒体上的声音，就此而言
big movement around censorship and free
围绕审查制度和自由的大运动
speech. There's also been this
演讲。还有这种情况
splintering of social media where lots
社交媒体的分裂，其中许多
of people are now like leaving certain
现在很多人就像离开某些地方一样。
platforms and going to Blue Sky and
平台和前往蓝天
Threads and you know Rumble was the only
Threads，你知道Rumble是唯一的
sort of big right-leaning platform just
某种大型右倾平台
just a couple of years ago and now I
就在几年前，而现在我
don't know it seems like it's all
不知道，感觉好像就是这样
changing before our eyes. I I don't read
在我们眼前发生着变化。我不读书
too much into it to be honest with you.
说实话，我陷得太深了。
To me, it feels like more of a
对我来说，感觉更像是……
continuation of of almost, you know, at
几乎是延续，你知道，在
least in the case of I I think we can
至少就我而言，我认为我们可以
use Meta as the example just because
之所以用 Meta 作为例子，仅仅是因为
they are essentially the social media uh
它们本质上就是社交媒体。
market. Um, and what's really
市场。嗯，还有，这到底是怎么回事？
interesting about their choices is what
他们的选择很有趣。
they've tended to do uh is sort of
他们倾向于这样做，嗯，有点像……
follow the political winds. So, when
顺应政治风向。所以，当
Biden was president, and Mark's been
拜登曾任总统，而马克也曾是总统。
very public about this, they did a lot
他们对此非常公开，做了很多事。
of very proactive content moderation.
内容审核非常积极主动。
And that was something that apparently I
而那显然是我……
guess the White House at the time was
我猜当时的白宫是
asking them to do very proactively. And
要求他们积极主动地去做。和
now it seems like, you know, with the
现在看来，你知道，随着
with the new administration, this new
随着新政府的成立，这项新举措也随之而来。
administration has a different approach
行政部门采取了不同的方法。
to to content moderation and Meta is
内容审核和 Meta 是
following that. And so I what I've seen
接下来。所以，我所看到的
mostly from from Meta over time is that
主要来自 Meta 的随着时间的推移是
they're quite willing to sort of
他们很乐意这样做。
navigate the the political landscape and
了解政治格局并
follow um you know really follow the the
跟着他，你知道，真的跟着他。
lead of of uh politicians here. Is that
这里是一些政客的领导层。是吗？
something to be admired?
值得欣赏的地方？
No, I think it's a it's definitely a
不，我认为它肯定是一个
survivalist approach for sure when
当然，生存主义方法在
you're such a large and powerful
你真是个强大而有力量的人
company, right? You know, if you look at
公司，对吧？你知道，如果你看看
Meta, they have so much litigation with
Meta公司有很多诉讼纠纷。
the government right now. The government
现任政府。政府
is scrutinizing so many different
正在仔细审查这么多不同的东西
aspects of their business. And so when
他们业务的各个方面。所以当
you're at that scale and you're, you
你已经达到了那个规模，而且，你
know, controlled by a single founder. I
众所周知，该公司由单一创始人控制。我
I think it's a survivalist instinct that
我认为这是一种生存本能。
that, you know, means that depending on
你知道，这意味着取决于
who is in the White House, you change
谁入主白宫，你就会改变。
your policies. Are you
您的政策。你是
optimistic about the next four years in
对未来四年持乐观态度
America? I'm incredibly optimistic about
美国？我对此无比乐观。
our country. I I I love our country so
我们的国家。我深爱我的祖国
much. I think uh that
很多。我觉得呃……
Americans across our country uh have an
我们国家的美国人都有
incredible spirit that has allowed us to
正是这种令人难以置信的精神，让我们得以
overcome extraordinary challenges
克服非凡挑战
together. more recently the COVID
一起。最近的新冠疫情
pandemic, you know, longer ago, things
疫情，你知道，很久以前，那些事
like World War II, uh, you know, where
就像二战那样，呃，你知道，就是那里
we came together not only as a country
我们不仅作为一个国家走到了一起
but more broadly in the world to
但更广泛地说，在世界范围内
confront, uh, you know, the horror of,
直面，呃，你知道的，那种恐怖，
uh, the Axis powers. I I think our
呃，轴心国。我认为我们的
country in in very critical and
该国局势非常危急，
important moments comes together in
重要时刻汇聚于
really powerful ways and that's
非常有效的方法，就是这样。
something that's inspires really
真正鼓舞人心的东西
inspires me. Your your oldest child is
激励了我。你的大孩子是
14, you said. Um, he's at that age now
你说14。嗯，他现在就这个年纪了。
where he's going to be getting
他要去哪里
increasing pressures to join social
加入社交的压力越来越大
media. Are you going to let him join
媒体。你打算让他加入吗？
Instagram? He's on Snapchat. I I I He's
Instagram？他有Snapchat账号。我 我 我 他是
on Snapchat. Um certainly on YouTube and
在 Snapchat 上。嗯，当然在YouTube上。
Roblox, which he likes a lot. Um so that
他很喜欢 Roblox。嗯，所以……
that's sort of the current um the
这就是目前的情况。
current situation. You must have thought
现状。你肯定想过
about this. There's so much conversation
关于这件事。有很多对话。
at the moment around the impact that
目前来看，其影响主要体现在以下方面：
social media has on kids, anxiety, all
社交媒体对孩子的影响，焦虑等等。
of the sort of toxic things around
周围那些有毒的东西
comparison and becoming more isolated.
比较和日益孤立。
Have you developed a an agreement with
你是否已经与……达成协议？
your your wife, with your kids, with
你，你的妻子，和你的孩子们，和
your family about social media usage
和家人谈谈社交媒体使用情况
going forward?
接下来呢？
I I think in general our view, you know,
我认为总的来说我们的观点是，你知道，
each of our children are so different.
我们的每个孩子都截然不同。
They're going to develop in different
它们将以不同的方式发展。
ways. So, I don't think like a
方法。所以，我的想法不像……
one-sizefits-all model is the right
均码模式才是正确的
approach here. I think it really depends
从这里过来。我觉得这真的要看情况。
on on where each of our kids are at at
了解我们每个孩子目前的状况
at any given point and who they are and
在任何特定时刻，他们是谁，以及
what they want to do. I think one thing
他们想做什么。我认为一件事
I would really encourage them to be
我真心鼓励他们这样做。
thoughtful about is their privacy,
他们考虑得很周到，尤其注重保护隐私。
especially as young people. And I think
尤其是对年轻人而言。我觉得
there are a lot of young people at a
有很多年轻人
very young age are posting a lot of
年纪很小的用户发布了很多内容
public content and I think it's very
公共内容，我认为这是非常
important to be thoughtful about those
认真思考这些问题很重要。
sorts of decisions because once you've
各种各样的决定，因为一旦你……
posted something publicly you can't get
公开发布了一些你无法获取的内容
that back. And I think you know it's
那个背部。我想你也知道这一点。
really important as we talk about
这一点非常重要，因为我们谈到
technology that we focus on the healthy
我们专注于健康的技术
and constructive ways uh that you know
以及你所知道的建设性方法
Flynn for example at 14 can use
例如，14岁的弗林就可以使用
technology like staying in touch with
像保持联系这样的技术
his friends and family. I think the real
他的朋友和家人。我认为真正的
watershed moment for us as a family was
对我们全家来说，这是一个具有里程碑意义的时刻。
up until the COVID pandemic, we we
在新冠疫情爆发之前，我们
didn't allow Flynn to have a phone. We
不允许弗林拥有手机。我们
really didn't allow him to use a
真的不允许他使用
computer. When the pandemic happened, he
电脑。疫情爆发时，他
had to stay in touch with his friends.
他必须和朋友们保持联系。
There were we knew that that was vitally
我们知道这一点至关重要。
important for his well-being, right? And
这对他的健康很重要，对吧？和
and I think the challenge we have is is
我认为我们面临的挑战是
almost the whiplash that young people
几乎就像年轻人遭受的鞭打
are experiencing because throughout the
正在经历这一切，因为整个
pandemic, they were told you can only
疫情期间，他们被告知只能
talk to your friends on the computer.
在电脑上和朋友们聊天。
You can only talk to your friends on the
你只能通过以下方式与你的朋友交谈：
phone, right? Right. And then coming out
是手机吧？正确的。然后出来
of the pandemic, what they're hearing a
关于疫情，他们听到的
lot from adults now is stay off your
现在很多成年人都会告诉你不要靠近你
phone. Don't use your phone at all. I
电话。完全不要使用手机。我
think both extremes are are are unusual.
认为这两种极端情况都不寻常。
And I for us as parents, we we think a
而我，作为父母，我们认为
lot about what's a healthy relationship
很多关于健康关系的内容
with technology. Of course, we want you
利用科技。当然，我们想要你
to go, you know, run cross country and
去参加越野跑之类的活动，你知道的。
hang out with your friends, you know, or
和朋友们出去玩，你知道的，或者
or go, you know, go for uh go for a
或者去，你知道，去……去……
walk, go to the mall and and and just
散步，去商场，然后，就……
talk. But we know when when Flynn's not
讲话。但我们知道弗林什么时候不在。
with his friends, when you know they're
和他的朋友们在一起，当你明知他们是
spread out all over the world, uh you
遍布世界各地，呃，你
know, or they're after school trying to
知道，或者他们放学后试图……
meet up, like it's helpful to use
见面，就像这样做很有帮助
technology. It's helpful to message your
技术。给你发消息很有帮助
friends. And so I think we have to find
朋友们。所以我觉得我们必须找到
this right balance of saying, you know,
这种恰当的平衡，你知道，
cultivate a healthy engaged lifestyle
培养健康积极的生活方式
with all of your interests, your
结合你的所有兴趣，你的
hobbies, your passions, and then if you
爱好、热情所在，以及如果你
want to use your phone to stay in touch
想用手机保持联系
with your friends or watch entertaining
和朋友一起或观看娱乐节目
content or play a game to relax, like
玩游戏或做其他事情来放松，比如
that's healthy, too. Even if Finn says,
那也很健康。即使芬恩说，
"I want to watch I want TikTok, Dad."
“爸爸，我想看TikTok。”
That that might be a bridge too far.
那可能有点过头了。
We say cuz Tik Tok's like I don't even
我们说因为TikTok就像我根本不……
use Tik Tok myself um personally because
我自己也用TikTok，因为……
it's from what I hear it's like crack
我听说它就像毒品一样。
cocaine for people that they're just on
对于那些吸食可卡因的人来说，他们只是在吸食。
there for like three or four hours a day
每天在那里待三四个小时。
scrolling mindlessly. Um if Finn came
漫无目的地滑动屏幕。嗯，如果芬恩来了
home and said I want to use Tik Tok Dad
回家后，我说我想用抖音爸爸
you'd say no. We we would probably say
你会说不。我们可能会说
no. We have said no uh historically
不。我们历史上曾说过不。
although he hasn't really pressed
虽然他并没有真正施压。
pressed the issue. Tik Tok was going to
坚持追问此事。抖音原本要
be banned and then Trump swooped in and
被禁止之后，特朗普突然介入并
seemed to save the day.
似乎力挽狂澜。
Is that a good thing? Is this as a CEO
这是好事吗？这是首席执行官的职责吗？
of Snapchat, was part of you hoping that
Snapchat 的一部分，是你希望的那部分
it was banned because then maybe more
它被禁是因为那样可能会有更多问题。
people would come over and use Snap? Did
人们会过来使用Snap吗？做过
you think about that? I think it would
你考虑过这个问题吗？我觉得会
be quite good for our business um if
如果这对我们的业务来说相当不错的话
they were banned. I I think the bigger
他们被禁了。我认为更大的
picture that we really have to figure
我们必须弄清楚的画面
out as as a country and in terms of our
作为一个国家，就我们而言
relationship with China is to figure out
与中国的关系需要弄清楚
the areas where businesses are going to
企业迁往的区域
collaborate and do business across the
跨领域协作和开展业务
United States and China and areas where
美国和中国以及其他地区
they are not. So you're probably
并非如此。所以你很可能
familiar many technology companies
许多熟悉的科技公司
cannot operate in China for a variety of
由于多种原因，无法在中国开展业务
reasons. Maybe they don't have a
原因。也许他们没有
license, they haven't been allowed to
许可证，他们一直没有被允许
operate, etc. But they are allowed to
操作等等。但他们被允许这样做。
operate here in the United States where
在美国运营
we have an open market, a free market.
我们拥有开放的市场，自由的市场。
And I think we have to be very
我认为我们必须非常
thoughtful at this point in time as a
在此时此刻，我深思熟虑地……
country because being an open market has
该国之所以成为开放市场，是因为它拥有……
always been a massive strategic
一直以来都是一项巨大的战略举措。
advantage for the United States. It's
对美国有利。它是
something that the United free trade
联合自由贸易
things like that have been massively
诸如此类的事情已经产生了巨大的影响。
supportive of our economic growth. But
支持我们的经济增长。但
we're now at a moment where I think we
我们现在正处于一个我认为我们……的时刻
need to be thoughtful and say with some
需要深思熟虑，并表达一些想法。
countries free trade in some areas makes
各国在某些领域实行自由贸易
a lot of sense. So if it we're talking
很有道理。所以，如果我们在谈论它的话。
about kids toys or diapers or you name
关于儿童玩具、尿布或你的名字
it, right? Like let it rip. That that's
对吧？就像放手一搏。那就是
good for both countries and both
对两国都有好处
countries uh I think uh can do business
我认为，这些国家可以开展业务。
in those areas. But when it comes to
在这些地区。但说到
other areas like you know information
其他领域，比如你知道的信息
services or maybe it's critical critical
服务，或者可能是至关重要的。
minerals, maybe it's some types of
矿物质，也许是某些类型的
pharmaceutical uh you know compounds or
药物，你知道化合物或
or ingredients. Those are areas where
或配料。这些地区
the countries aren't going to be able to
这些国家将无法……
collaborate because ultimately they have
合作是因为他们最终拥有
very different goals, ideologies,
目标和意识形态截然不同，
visions for the future. And and I think
对未来的展望。而且我认为
the issue that the business community
商业界面临的问题
has right now is there's not enough
目前的问题是资源不足。
clarity in that regard. So the more
在这方面要明确一些。所以越多
clarity the government can create and
政府能够创造的清晰度
say, you know, the United States and
比如说，你知道，美国和
China working together can say, hey, we
中国携手合作，就能说：“嘿，我们……”
agree these areas are open for business
同意这些地区已开放营业。
and these areas are areas where we're
而这些领域正是我们所在的领域。
going to compete and we're not going to
我们要参加比赛，但我们不会……
collaborate. that would help the
合作。那会有帮助的
business community because I think
商业界，因为我认为
what's so frustrating imagine being a
最令人沮丧的是什么？想象一下自己是……
Chinese entrepreneur right now building
中国企业家目前正在建设中
this really successful company and then
这家公司非常成功，然后
the US government saying hey you know
美国政府说，嘿，你知道
given our our country and and our values
鉴于我们的国家和价值观
and the strategic relationship we have
以及我们之间的战略关系
with China this is not this isn't it's
对于中国来说，这不是这样，不是这样的。
not going to work it sounds like Trump
这行不通，听起来像特朗普的风格。
wants to buy it which was a very
想买下它，这非常
interesting suggestion and it's worrying
这个想法很有意思，但也令人担忧。
because it sets a bit of a precedence
因为它开创了一个先例。
that potentially an app like Snapchat
这可能是一款类似 Snapchat 的应用程序
the UK might decide listen we don't we
英国可能会决定听我们的，我们不听。
don't know if we can trust you because
我们不知道是否可以信任你，因为
you're an an American, so we want to buy
你是美国人，所以我们想买
the UK version in order for you to have
为了让你有英国版本，
Snapchat be in the UK. That could set a
Snapchat 在英国。这可能会造成……
worrying precedence around the world. I
这在全球范围内都是令人担忧的先例。我
think there's already some early flavors
我觉得已经有一些早期版本了。
of that with folks really focused on
人们非常关注这一点
data localization and and whatnot. And
数据本地化等等。和
and that's sort of my point around I
这就是我关于“我”的观点。
think we need to get really clear about
我认为我们需要非常清楚地了解
with which countries, you know, are we
你知道，我们和哪些国家有关系？
going to have open free flow of data and
将实现数据的开放自由流动
and trade and and which countries are
以及贸易，以及哪些国家是
there areas where that that might not
有些地区可能不会出现这种情况。
work as effectively. Snapchat eventually
工作效率同样很高。 Snapchat最终
goes public. Um, running a public
上市。嗯，运营一家公共机构
company is difficult to say the least
公司情况很难说好听点。
because the share price can go up and
因为股价可能会上涨，而且
down really irrespective of what you're
无论你是什么，都真的要冷静下来
doing and what you're building and it's
你在做什么，你在建造什么，以及它是
really a reflection of the broader
这确实反映了更广泛的情况。
market, people's emotions and vibes, but
市场、人们的情绪和氛围，但是
you have to manage that as a
你必须把它当作一种管理方式来处理。
CEO. Not easy, I
首席执行官。不容易，我
imagine. You know what I a lot of people
想象。你知道吗，很多人都
warned us about going public. Um and
你曾警告过我们不要公开上市。嗯，还有
they said, you know, there were a lot of
他们说，你知道，有很多
uh there's going to be a lot of pressure
呃，压力会很大。
to be short-term oriented and this sort
注重短期利益，以及这类
of thing. Um that the quarterly scrutiny
事物。嗯，季度审查
would be challenging for for our
对我们来说，这将是一个挑战。
business. Ultimately, I think the
商业。最终，我认为
transition from being a private company
从私营公司转型
to a public company was was uh
对一家上市公司来说，呃
challenging. It's it's quite different.
具有挑战性的。这完全不同。
Um but now I I really think the
嗯，但是现在我真的觉得
discipline and the rigor around the
纪律和严谨性
quarterly performance the you know need
季度业绩，你知道需要
to forecast your business really
预测你的业务
effectively and then compare how you're
有效地比较你的表现
tracking to your forecast helps the
跟踪您的预测有助于
company run in a much more effective
公司运营效率更高
way. So that sort of scrutiny I think
方式。所以我觉得这种审查方式是必要的。
can be really helpful you know for the
你知道，这真的很有帮助。
leadership team and then the broader
领导团队以及更广泛的
team in terms of running the business.
团队在业务运营方面。
Now, where it can get difficult
现在，难点来了。
is when it comes to long-term investment
就长期投资而言，情况就是如此。
and and innovation. So, for example,
以及创新。例如，
right now interest rates have gone way
目前利率已经大幅下降。
up. Um folks are uh discounting cash
向上。嗯，大家正在打折现金
flows um you know at a much higher rate
流量，你知道，要高得多
as a result. And so there's a huge focus
因此。因此，人们非常关注这一点。
on profitability for uh many many
关于盈利能力，嗯，对很多人来说都是如此。
businesses across all sectors. What we
涵盖所有行业的企业。我们
know is true for long-term innovation is
了解这一点对于长期创新而言是成立的
that consistency really matters. You
这种一致性非常重要。你
can't just flick a switch and and turn
不能只是拨动一个开关就转过来
on and off innovation, turn on and off
创新有开有关，开启和关闭
um you know, investments in new uh
嗯，你知道，对新事物的投资
products. It's very difficult and
产品。这非常困难，而且
disruptive to do that. And so we've made
这样做会造成干扰。所以我们已经做到了。
a decision through this period of time,
在此期间做出的决定
even though we've made some really
尽管我们已经做出了一些非常
difficult and painful deci decisions to
艰难而痛苦的决定
shut down some of our projects, we're
我们关闭了一些项目，我们正在
still investing at a higher rate uh
仍然以较高的利率进行投资
right now through this period of time,
从现在到这段时间，
even though we know that that means
即使我们知道这意味着
that, you know, our share price might be
你知道，我们的股价可能会……
lower because people are, you know,
低是因为人们，你知道，
discounting our cash flows differently
以不同的方式折现我们的现金流
due to higher interest rates. So I think
由于利率较高。所以我觉得
you know that's when it gets challenging
你知道，挑战就此开始。
the actual reality of of you know
你知道的，现实情况是这样的。
continuing to invest through you know
继续投资，你知道的
challenging periods of time or periods
充满挑战的时期或阶段
where interest rates have gone way up.
利率大幅上涨的地方。
When I think about sitting in your shoes
当我想到要站在你的角度思考时
or sitting in your seat I think about
或者坐在座位上，我想着
all the things you could do as a public
作为公众，你可以做的所有事情
company. I think you could do anything
公司。我觉得你什么都能做到。
like you could go after any game and at
就像你可以去玩任何游戏一样，而且
some point as you kind of said there
正如你刚才提到的那样。
when you use the word painfully you're
当你痛苦地使用这个词时，你是
going to have to make a decision to
我必须做出决定
focus on something. And even at like the
专注于某件事。即使在类似这样的情况下
level I'm at with the businesses I run
我目前所处的经营水平
and so on, I find the hardest thing for
等等，我觉得最难的是
me is especially when you're somewhat
对我来说尤其如此，当你有点……
creative, etc., is to pick something and
有创造力等等，就是选择某样东西，然后
to say no to everything else. And I've
对其他一切都说不。而且我已经
looked at your philosophy and I know
我研究过你的哲学思想，我知道
saying no and focus is so central to
学会说“不”和专注至关重要
your to your sort of leadership style,
你的领导风格，
but also how you think as an
但也包括你作为一个人是如何思考的
entrepreneur. Tell me about those
企业家。跟我说说那些事吧。
painful moments where you had to kill
那些你不得不杀戮的痛苦时刻
something that you didn't want to kill.
你不想杀死的东西。
Yeah, I there there are a bunch. I you
是的，那里有很多。我你
know that that piece of advice was so
要知道，那条建议是如此
helpful to us especially in the early
对我们尤其在早期阶段很有帮助
days of our business. One of our first
我们公司运营的日子。我们最早一批
venture investors was like hey Evan you
风险投资人就像在说：嘿，埃文，你
got to get really good at saying no.
必须学会非常擅长说“不”。
He's like you have almost no resources I
他就像你几乎没有任何资源一样。
think we were a team of four people at
我记得我们当时是一个四人团队。
the time. Um you know and you're going
时间。嗯，你知道，你要走了
to get all this inbound because the
要接收所有这些信息，因为
company's growing. People are going to
公司正在发展壮大。人们将会
want to do partnerships or do an
想建立合作关系还是想做……
interview or what and just if you can
面试什么的，如果你可以的话
just get really good at saying no and
只要学会非常擅长说“不”就行了。
stay focused on your community, stay
专注于你的社区，保持
focused on your customers. Like that's
以客户为中心。就像那样
the that's the secret. And that focus
这就是秘诀。以及这种关注
has really helped us over the years. But
这些年来，它确实帮了我们很多。但
as you point out, there's there have
正如你所指出的，那里有
been times where we've had to refocus or
有时我们不得不重新调整方向或
we've had to reassess uh areas of our
我们不得不重新评估我们某些领域。
business. I think one good example uh
商业。我认为一个很好的例子是……
were mini games. We had an amazing
都是一些小游戏。我们度过了一段美好的时光
hundreds of people using um our our mini
数百人正在使用我们的迷你版
games and people love them. It was an
人们喜欢游戏。那是一个
amazing uh platform. You could play like
非常棒的平台。你可以像这样玩
real-time multiplayer games together
一起玩实时多人游戏
inside of Snapchat and
在 Snapchat 内部和
ultimately it was just clear that that
最终，这一点变得非常明确。
was not going to be a really really big
原本不会是一件非常非常大的事。
business for us at least at that time.
至少在当时，这对我们来说是一笔生意。
And so we had to make the really painful
因此，我们不得不让那些真正痛苦的事情发生。
decision to, you know, shut down uh our
决定，你知道，关闭我们的
our mini games our mini games business.
我们的小游戏，我们的小游戏业务。
So how do you think about what to go
那么，你是怎么考虑要去哪里的呢？
after? There's all these new
后？有这么多新的
technologies. There's these buzzwords.
技术。这些都是流行语。
There's AI now. There's AR. There's VR.
现在有了人工智能。有增强现实技术。还有虚拟现实技术。
There's headsets. There's wearables.
有耳机。还有可穿戴设备。
There's all these things. How how do you
有这么多东西。你如何
decide what bet is your bet? I think
决定好你的赌注是什么？我认为
that's a really good question. That is
这真是个好问题。那是
to some degree where intuition uh you
在某种程度上，直觉……呃，你
know plays an important role but it's
知识固然重要，但它也至关重要。
also where feedback plays a really
反馈在其中也发挥着非常重要的作用。
important role. And that's why for
扮演重要角色。这就是为什么……
example with our last generation of
例如，以我们上一代产品为例
spectacles that we announced last year
我们去年宣布的盛事
the fifth generation of spectacles our
第五代眼镜
goal was just to get it into developers
目标只是把它推广给开发者。
hands as quickly as possible so that we
尽快伸出双手，以便我们
can listen and hear. Okay. So what sort
能听见。好的。那么，是哪种呢？
of things do you want to build with
你想用什么来构建
spectacles? What tools are available?
眼镜？有哪些工具可用？
What what isn't there? What do you what
缺少什么？你做什么
do you think would be really
你觉得真的会吗？
interesting? because the faster that we
有趣的？因为我们速度越快
can learn from people actually using our
可以从实际使用我们产品的人身上学习
our product, the faster we can make it
我们的产品，我们越快就能生产出来。
better and find that product market fit.
更好地找到产品与市场的契合点。
That's so important. And you also don't
这太重要了。而且你也不需要
know the time horizon for when the world
了解世界的时间范围
will sufficiently change in the
将会发生充分的变化
direction that your your bet has been
你的赌注方向已经确定
placed. I think about Google Glass,
已放置。我想到了谷歌眼镜。
which was I don't even know when it was
我甚至不知道那是什么时候的事了。
like a decade ago that people were
就像十年前人们那样
saying, "Okay, we're going to be wearing
他说：“好的，我们要穿……”
glasses." And Google had this Google
眼镜。”谷歌也有这款谷歌眼镜。
Glass thing and it just seemed to like
玻璃制品，看起来就像……
vanish and disappear. Uh, and then I
消失，彻底消失。呃，然后我
think about when Meta bought Oculus and
想想 Meta 收购 Oculus 的那件事
we thought, okay, no, so this is now
我们当时想，好吧，不行，所以现在
when everyone's going to be wearing VR
当每个人都戴上VR设备的时候
headsets and it's still kind of not
耳机，而且现在仍然有点……
really happened. So you could make a
确有其事。所以你可以制作一个
bet, you could be right, but you could
我敢肯定，你说的可能没错，但你也可能……
be 15 years off. You have to be very
差15年。你必须非常
careful in in technology, I think,
我认为，在技术方面要谨慎。
because things change slowly and then
因为事物变化缓慢，然后
they change very quickly. And I think
它们变化很快。我觉得
that was certainly the case with chat
聊天的情况确实如此。
GBT, right? People felt like, wow, this
GBT，对吧？人们感觉，哇，这
new technology came out of nowhere, but
新技术横空出世，但
no, they've been working on it for what,
不，他们一直在为此努力，为什么？
a decade? I mean, you know, and and
十年？我的意思是，你知道，而且
consistently trying to to make progress.
持续努力取得进步。
And so I think, you know, as long as you
所以我觉得，你知道，只要你
find something that you really believe
找到你真正相信的东西
can can make a positive impact that
可以产生积极影响
people can use in a really compelling
人们可以将其用于一个非常引人注目的地方。
way, you're right that sometimes you
没错，有时候你
have to be patient, but other times you
必须耐心等待，但有时你
can invent new things that bring that
可以发明带来这些的新事物。
timeline in. And so I think a lot of
时间线已就位。所以我认为很多
times our our team is thinking about
我们团队正在思考的次数
like okay yeah sure on the in the
好的，当然可以。
current trajectory that could take a
当前的发展轨迹可能会发生以下变化
really long time but what if we thought
时间确实很长，但如果我们这样想呢？
about it differently or invented you
关于它，你的看法有所不同，或者你发明了它。
know some new uh piece of technology
了解一些新技术
that could help us accelerate our vision
这或许能帮助我们加快实现愿景的步伐。
to you know glasses that help people you
你知道，有些眼镜可以帮助人们……
know share these experiences that
了解并分享这些经验
overlay computing on the world and that
在世界之上叠加计算，而这
that's part of the fun too and Meta
这也是乐趣的一部分，而且是元认知。
launched the Ray-B band ones which I've
我推出了Ray-B频段的那些产品。
I've heard about I think I watched a
我听说过，我想我看过一个
video of it which seem to be again
视频似乎又出现了
copying Snapchat
抄袭 Snapchat
Did that piss you off? The only thing
那件事让你生气了吗？唯一的事情
that frustrated me was that the Lxodica
令我沮丧的是，Lxodica
guys had actually come to us probably
可能有人真的来找过我们。
back in 2017. Who's that? Lxodica
那是2017年的事了。那是谁？洛西卡
Lxotica is the company that makes Ray-B
Lxotica是Ray-B的生产商。
bands. They had come to us in 2017
乐队。他们于2017年来到我们这里。
saying, "Wow, it's so awesome what you
他说：“哇，你真是太棒了！”
guys are doing with Spectacles. We love
男人们在戴眼镜。我们爱
it. We should find a way to partner."
它。我们应该找到合作的方式。
So, we talked with them of course all
所以，我们当然都和他们谈过了。
about everything that that we were
关于我们所经历的一切
doing. And then they went radio silent
正在做。然后他们就杳无音讯了。
and decided not to partner with us and
并决定不与我们合作。
then obviously resurfaced doing this
然后显然又重新出现并做了这件事。
with Meta. So, I think ultimately as a
与 Meta。所以，我认为最终作为一个
is something like that. I think
差不多就是这样。我认为
ultimately um you know you learn a lot I
最后，你知道，你会学到很多东西。
think growing a business and and really
想想如何发展业务，真的
understanding how people do business and
了解人们如何做生意
and I think it shows you a lot about the
我认为这充分说明了……
world and and I think it's so important
世界，而且我认为这非常重要
for entrepreneurs to really know um you
对于创业者来说，真正了解你
know that if they've got a a really
要知道，如果他们真的有
compelling idea they've got an amazing
他们有一个引人入胜的想法，非常棒。
service that that they can compete that
他们提供的服务可以让他们参与竞争。
they can build uh really compelling
他们可以构建出非常引人入胜的东西。
businesses even though it seems
企业即便看起来
impossible with such giant you know
面对如此庞大的身躯，这是不可能的，你知道的。
companies whether it's Luxotica which is
无论是像 Luxottica 这样的公司，
the giant in the glasses space or or
眼镜空间里的巨人
Meta um that I think Snapchat hopefully
Meta 嗯，我觉得 Snapchat 希望如此
can be, you know, an example of a
可以，你知道，举个例子
company that's been able to stay
能够留存下来的公司
independent and compete with these
独立并与这些公司竞争
really, really large businesses.
规模非常非常大的企业。
Artificial intelligence has become, I
人工智能已经成为，我
mean, the most talked about technology
也就是说，最受关注的技术
over the last couple of years as it's in
在过去几年里，它一直处于……
many respects, thanks to Chat
在很多方面，这都要感谢聊天功能。
GPT, how are you um thinking about the
GPT，你对……有什么想法？
future of artificial intelligence in
人工智能的未来
terms of how it's going to fundamentally
从根本上来说，它将如何发展
change human connection? You've got four
改变人际关系？你有四个
boys. You must be thinking about, you
男孩们。你一定在想，你
know, we talked about earlier the kind
我知道，我们之前讨论过那种
of jobs that are going to exist in the
未来将会出现的工作岗位
future. There's a big narrative saying
未来。有一种说法是：
that knowledge jobs like lawyer and
律师等知识型工作
accountant aren't going to be the same.
会计师们不会再是以前那样了。
In fact, even when you think about how
事实上，即使你仔细想想……
your kids are going to be educated, your
你的孩子将会接受教育，你的
youngest child is one years old. Are
最小的孩子一岁了。是
they going to go to a school or are they
他们会去上学吗？还是不会？
going to go to a large language model?
打算采用大型语言模型吗？
Like, how are you thinking about that
你是怎么想的？
future? Are you scared? I I really love
未来？你害怕吗？我真的很喜欢
that you jumped to education because I
你之所以投身教育事业，是因为我
think it's so profoundly powerful. I
我觉得它非常震撼人心。我
mean, even in my own experience, my
也就是说，即使以我自己的经验来看，我的
ability to learn such amazing things in
能够学习到如此惊人的事物
such a short period of time and connect
如此短暂的时间和联系
different ideas together, I it's it's an
不同的想法放在一起，我认为这是一个
incredible tool for discovery and for
令人难以置信的发现工具
learning. And so, I I can't wait for our
学习。所以，我迫不及待地想看到我们的
kids to, you know, use uh use these
孩子们，你知道，用这些
sorts of tools. I'm I'm sure Flynn does
各种工具。我确信弗林会这么做。
uh to some to some degree, but as a
嗯，在某种程度上是这样，但作为一个
thought partner, uh you know, AI is just
思想伙伴，呃，你知道，人工智能只是
incredibly powerful. So, so I do think
威力无比。所以，我的确认为……
uh especially for creative people, it
尤其对于创意人士而言，
should be an unbelievably powerful tool
应该会是一个无比强大的工具
to be able to iterate, to get feedback,
为了能够迭代，为了获得反馈，
to explore different ideas, explore
探索不同的想法，探索
different options. Even when I'm writing
不同的选择。即使在我写作的时候
something and I'm stuck on like, yeah,
我有点卡住了，就像，嗯，
this just doesn't feel right. And like
总觉得哪里不对劲。就像
I'm like, give me can you just give me
我就像，给我，你能不能给我？
10 options? Um it it's really helpful to
10个选项？嗯，这真的很有帮助
brainstorm um you know, to to find that
集思广益，你知道，找到那个
that right word. I was wondering the
用词恰当。我想知道
other day when um I was using chat GBT
前几天我用GBT聊天的时候……
or one of the the programs a couple of
或者其中一个程序
days ago. I was wondering if I'm going
几天前。我在想我是否要去
to get worse at writing because this
因为这个原因，我的写作水平反而下降了。
thing's now doing it for me. And writing
现在它对我有效。写作
is such a wonderful way to think and
这是一种多么美妙的思考方式啊！
understand. So therefore, am I going to
理解。所以，我是否应该……
get worse at like understanding things
越来越不擅长理解事物
because I'm now deferring the process of
因为我现在要推迟这个过程
thinking through something logically to
逻辑地思考某事
this
这
computer, whereas back in the day, I
电脑，而以前，我
would have to like really think deeply
需要认真思考一番。
about what I was trying to say
关于我想说的话
myself. I I don't know. I I think it's
我。我不知道。我认为是
going to be really important that
这一点非常重要
obviously people continue to to write
显然人们还在继续写作
and oftentimes like my first draft is on
而且很多时候，我的初稿就是这样。
a piece of paper, right? Um so so I I do
一张纸，对吧？嗯，所以，我……
think that that is going to be
认为那将会是
important, but I think the bigger
很重要，但我认为更重要的
question for me is whether or not AI
我的问题是人工智能是否……
will help people get better at asking
这将帮助人们更好地提问
questions because ultimately asking a
问题最终是因为提出问题
great question and having someone who
很好的问题，而且有个人可以解答
can help answer it is the key to
可以帮助解答这个问题，这是关键所在。
learning. I mean, that's I think, you
学习。我的意思是，我觉得，你
know, perhaps the greatest uh blessing
知道吗，或许最大的祝福
of having a a great teacher or a great
拥有一位优秀的老师或一位伟大的
mentor or a parent is that you get to
导师或父母能让你有机会……
ask all sorts of great questions, right?
问各种各样的好问题，对吧？
And and get those answers. And so I I
然后找到这些问题的答案。所以，我
think if we're now in a you know, a
想想如果我们现在处于一个你知道的，一个
modality that really is all about asking
这种模式实际上完全是关于提问的。
the right question and doing that really
问对了问题，并且真的做到了。
repeatedly, if that can train us all to
反复这样做，如果这能训练我们所有人
ask questions more effectively, uh that
更有效地提问，嗯。
that would be a very big deal.
那将是一件非常了不起的事情。
Interesting. I've not thought about
有趣的。我还没想过这个问题。
that. I don't know if I'm getting
那。我不知道我是否得到了
better. I don't really know. It's really
更好的。我真的不知道。真是
because because there's always a
因为总会有一个
trade-off with new technology. And the
新技术带来的权衡取舍。以及
problem as we saw with social media is
正如我们在社交媒体上看到的那样，问题在于……
we often don't discover the trade-off
我们往往无法发现这种权衡取舍。
until 15 years, 20 years time when it's
直到15年、20年后，那时……
really reared its ugly head cuz it's
它的丑恶面目真的暴露出来了，因为它……
slow then it's fast. So I'm trying to
先慢后快。所以我正在尝试
understand if you're looking around the
如果你四处看看，就能明白了
corner or looking over the horizon now
现在正从角落或地平线上眺望
to think through the trade-off of us
仔细考虑我们之间的权衡取舍
hurtling into something which just like
猛地撞向某物，就像
social media made something better,
社交媒体让一些事情变得更好了。
faster, cheaper, easier but came with a
更快、更便宜、更容易，但附带一个
unintended consequence.
意想不到的后果。
I think generally speaking as we have
我认为总的来说，正如我们所拥有的
looked historically at the evolution of
从历史角度考察了……的演变
technology these sorts of foundational
这些技术是基础性的
technologies you're right that they've
你说的没错，这些技术确实存在。
been disruptive uh but they ultimately
虽然有些扰乱秩序，但他们最终还是
have massively positive and beneficial
具有巨大的积极和益处
uh effects. I mean I think if you look
呃，效果。我的意思是，我觉得如果你仔细看
at a foundational technology like the
在基础技术方面，例如
internet, a foundational uh technology
互联网，一项基础性技术
maybe like the the motor vehicle, these
或许就像机动车辆一样，这些
are the you know an airplane, these are
你知道，飞机就是这样的。
the sorts of foundational technologies
各种基础技术
that I think can really change the
我认为这真的可以改变……
trajectory of the world and ultimately
世界的发展轨迹以及最终结果
make people's lives better. I think the
改善人们的生活。我认为
key will be how do we navigate that
关键在于我们如何应对这种情况。
change together and that'll be something
共同改变，那将是一件好事。
that will be really uh really important
那真的非常重要
to do thoughtfully. And I I think you
深思熟虑地去做。而且我认为你
know in many ways the good news about
在许多方面都了解这个好消息
this sort of technological change is
这种技术变革是
it's always governed by people. I mean
它始终由人来管理。我是说
folks I I think almost overly fixate on
我觉得大家几乎过度关注
new technology developments and don't
新技术发展，而且不
think enough about what is actually the
仔细想想这究竟是什么
human adoption curve look like? How are
人类收养曲线是什么样的？怎样
we making this something that's easier
我们正在让这件事变得更容易。
to use, easier for people to understand,
易于使用，更易于人们理解
easier for people to integrate into
更容易让人们融入
their lives, into their workflows. Um,
将它们的生活融入到它们的工作流程中。嗯，
and so I think a lot of the work for a
所以我认为很多工作都是为了……
big foundational technology like AI is
人工智能等大型基础技术是
going to be much more around how humans
这将更多地围绕人类如何运作展开。
are interacting with it, interpreting
正在与它互动，进行解读
it, understanding how it fits in their
理解它如何融入他们的……
lives. If you spend most days on your
生命。如果你大部分时间都花在你的
computer, you'll probably want to hear
电脑，你可能想听
this. Some recent brain imaging studies
这。最近的一些脑成像研究
have found that handwriting fires up
发现手写能激发灵感
more parts of the brain associated with
更多与大脑相关的区域
creativity and critical thinking. But in
创造力和批判性思维。但在
digital workplaces, it's easy to lose
在数字化工作场所，很容易失去
the cognitive edge of handwriting. So, I
手写带来的认知优势。所以，我
want to introduce you to GoodNotes, a
想向您介绍 GoodNotes，一款
solution that combines both. I've used
结合两者的解决方案。我用过
GoodNotes for a long, long time, well
我用GoodNotes已经很久很久了，嗯
before they became a sponsor of this
在他们成为这项活动的赞助商之前
podcast. It's what I'm using every
播客。我一直都在用它
single time I'm sat here in the D of Sio
我唯一一次坐在锡奥市的这里
on the iPad in front of me during every
在我面前的iPad上，我全程都在看。
recording that I've pretty much ever
记录下我几乎一直
done in the last couple of years. It
近两年完成的。它
holds my research, which I can annotate
里面有我的研究资料，我可以在上面做注释。
in real time, as well as jot down new
实时记录，并记下新的
ideas as they come to me as the guest is
想法会随着我作为客人的到来而涌现。
talking. Outside of the studio, I use it
说。在工作室之外，我也会使用它。
to mark up design concepts in meetings
在会议中标记设计概念
whenever I'm brainstorming and to
每当我进行头脑风暴时，
capture other insights with my team.
与我的团队一起收集其他见解。
GoodNotes is like my second brain. It's
GoodNotes 就像我的第二大脑。它是
the tool that helps me to unlock
帮助我解锁的工具
original ideas and sharper thinking. And
原创的想法和更敏锐的思维。和
their built-in AI lets me build on those
它们内置的人工智能让我能够在此基础上进行扩展。
ideas, too. For collaborative work, your
想法也一样。对于协作工作，您的
team can get a business license or get
团队可以获得营业执照或
it yourself. It only costs £9.99 a year.
自己动手。每年只需9.99英镑。
And they're offering our community a
他们为我们的社区提供了一种
30-day free trial. Just head to
30天免费试用。直接前往
goodnotes.com/doac to get started. No
访问 goodnotes.com/doac 开始使用。不
matter where I am in the world, it seems
无论我身处世界何处，似乎都是如此。
like everyone is drinking matcha. And
感觉每个人都在喝抹茶。和
there's a good chance that that matcher
很有可能那个匹配器
you're drinking is made by a company
你喝的饮料是由一家公司生产的。
that I've invested more than seven
我已经投资超过七个
figures in who are a sponsor of this
赞助商名单中的人物
podcast called Perfect Ted because
播客节目名为《完美泰德》，因为
they're the brand used globally by cafes
这是全球咖啡馆普遍使用的品牌。
like Blank Street Coffee and Joe in the
就像 Blank Street Coffee 和 Joe 一样
Juice and many, many more. Not only can
果汁等等。不仅可以
you get Perfect Ted Matcha in cafes, but
你可以在咖啡馆里买到完美泰德抹茶，但是
you can now also make it at home much
现在你也可以在家自己做了。
cheaper in seconds using our flavored
使用我们风味独特的产品，只需几秒钟即可节省更多。
matcha powders that I have here in front
我面前这些抹茶粉
of me. Perfect Ted Matcha is ceremonial
是我。 Perfect Ted Matcha 是一种仪式性的
grade and sourced from Japan. It is
等级优良，产自日本。这是
smooth. It is naturally sweet, not like
光滑的。它是天然的甜味，不像……
those bitter grassy matches that I tried
我试过的那些苦涩的草火柴
before. Perfect Ted. And if you are one
前。完美的泰德。如果你是其中一员
of those people that have told yourself
那些告诉过自己的人
you don't like matcha, it's probably
你不喜欢抹茶，那很可能
because you haven't tried our Perfect
因为你还没试过我们完美的产品。
Ted Matcher. And you can find Perfect
泰德·马彻。而且你还能找到完美
Ted Matcher in the UK and Tesco,
英国的Ted Matcher和Tesco，
Sainsbury's, Holland and Barrett and in
Sainsbury's、Holland and Barrett 以及在
Waitros or Albertahheine if you're in
如果你在的话，可以去 Waitros 或 Albertahheine。
the Netherlands and on Amazon in the USA
荷兰和美国亚马逊均有售。
or get the full range online at
或在线获取全部产品信息
perfectted.com where you can get 40% off
访问 perfectted.com，即可享受 40% 的折扣
your first order with code
使用优惠码下单，您的第一笔订单将获得优惠码
Steven40. What season is Snapchat in in
Steven40。 Snapchat 现在处于哪个季节？
terms of its company's life? You know,
公司存续期间的条款是什么？你知道，
like you were in that startup phase,
就像你当时处于创业阶段一样，
you're in your dad's bedroom phase where
你正处于迷恋爸爸卧室的阶段
you're scrappy and you're growing
你很有拼劲，而且正在成长。
quickly. Then you went to the blue
迅速地。然后你去了蓝色区域。
office, you know, the met met uh
办公室，你知道，见面了，呃
meteoric growth, you had the IPO. What
你们实现了飞速增长，并成功上市。什么
season is Snapchat in as we sit here
我们现在正坐在这里，Snapchat 的季节已经来临了。
today in 2025? How would you like
2025年的今天？你想要怎样的？
summarize it if you had to poetically
如果要用诗意的方式概括，你会怎么说？
describe the psychology of the business
描述该行业的心理学
now? I mean, in some ways, it feels like
现在？我的意思是，在某些方面，感觉就像
we're emerging from like a two-year
我们刚刚结束了大约两年的时间。
winter into an early spring. The last
从冬季到早春。最后
two years have been really challenging.
这两年真的非常具有挑战性。
We had to rebuild our entire ad
我们不得不重建整个广告
platform, change the way that we go to
平台，改变我们前往的方式
market, you know, really help
市场，你知道，真的很有帮助
advertisers find more success and at the
广告商发现，在以下方面，广告商能取得更大的成功：
same time do a lot of that for creators
同时为创作者做很多这类事情
as well. We've seen a tremendous growth
也一样。我们见证了巨大的增长。
in terms of, you know, I think last
就此而言，你知道，我认为最后
quarter the
四分之一
the creators posting grew something like
创作者发布的内容逐渐发展成类似这样的形式
40% year-over-year. There was a billion
同比增长40%。当时有十亿
public posts a month on Snapchat. And
每月在 Snapchat 上发布公开帖子。和
that's an area we've invested in a lot
那是我们投入大量资金的领域。
as well. But it's been a very
也一样。但这确实非常
challenging last two years. So, I I
过去两年充满挑战。所以，我
would almost say maybe like very very
几乎可以说，也许非常非常
early spring you're starting to see uh
早春时节，你开始看到……
you know some some green shoots but you
你知道，有些许新芽，但是你
know um and the frost is melting. Have
我知道，霜冻正在融化。有
you had any acquisition offers since
自那以后你收到过任何收购要约吗？
that conversation with Mark Zuckerberg
与马克·扎克伯格的那次谈话
once upon a time? Do people still try
曾几何时？还有人尝试吗？
and buy the company like these days? No.
像现在这样收购公司？不。
I I think given the voting structure of
我认为，鉴于投票结构……
the company, you know, Bobby and I uh
公司，你知道，鲍比和我呃
have voting stock and non- voting stock
拥有投票权的股票和没有投票权的股票
is what's publicly uh traded. I think
就是公开交易的那些。我认为
generally, you know, sometimes people
一般来说，你知道，有时候人们
will say, "Hey, if you guys ever, you
会说，“嘿，如果你们以后有机会，你们……”
know, want to retire or something, keep
知道，想退休什么的，继续
us in mind." But I think um, you know,
“我们一直都惦记着你。”但我觉得，嗯，你知道，
in terms of uh, you know, kicking an
就踢球而言，你知道，
offer over the over the sill or
越过窗台或
something that that that doesn't make a
那件事并不能构成一个
ton of sense given our company
考虑到我们公司的情况，这很有道理。
structure. Another thing that I admired
结构。还有一点我很欣赏
when I was reading about the way you run
当我读到你跑步的方式时
Snapchat is this idea of having a
Snapchat 就是这种拥有……的想法。
council. Oh, amazing. Wow. Okay. Can you
理事会。哦，太棒了。哇。好的。你可以吗
tell me about this because I might want
告诉我这件事，因为我可能想要了解一下。
to steal. I shouldn't. Please take it.
偷窃。我不应该。请收下。
Okay. Good. council is something that I
好的。好的。议会是我所关心的事情。
stole uh from uh the school that I I
我从学校偷了东西
went to growing up called Crossroads
成长的地方叫做十字路口
School for Arts and Sciences, which is
艺术与科学学院，即
quite a unique uh school. Um and one of
这是一所相当独特的学校。嗯，还有其中之一
the things that they have at Crossroads
他们在十字路口拥有的东西
is a council. And you know, basically
是一个委员会。你知道，基本上
starting in middle school, you get
从中学开始，你就会
together with a group of let's call it
与一群我们姑且称之为……的人一起
10 or 12 classmates and you sit in a
10到12个同学，你们坐在一起。
circle and there are three rules. It's
圆圈内有三条规则。它是
you know, speak from the heart, uh
你知道，要发自内心地说话，嗯
listen from the heart and be
用心聆听，并成为
spontaneous. And it's essentially uh you
自发的。本质上就是你
know turn-based storytelling where you
了解回合制叙事，你
go around the circle and you know it can
绕着圈子走一圈，你就知道它可以
be anything as simple as like how was
可以是像“怎么样？”这样简单的问题。
your weekend or you know uh what's a
你的周末，或者你知道，呃，什么是……
what's a rose bud and a thorn from you
你眼中的玫瑰花蕾和刺是什么？
know the last uh the last week and it it
知道上周的情况，还有它
really creates an opportunity a for
确实为……创造了机会
people to listen to one another because
人们要互相倾听，因为
you're taking turns going around the
你们轮流绕着……
circle but b you get to know people in a
圈子，但你可以通过它认识人
very very different way and I saw how
方式截然不同，我看到了
powerful it was in middle school. Middle
中学时它非常强大。中间
school is a tough time was a tough time
上学那段时间很艰难，曾经很艰难。
for me, but in council I was able to
对我来说，但在议会中我能够
connect with my classmates uh you know
与我的同学联系，你知道的
in a really thoughtful and and maybe
经过深思熟虑，也许
deeper way that you wouldn't just kind
更深层次的方式，你不会只是那样。
of around the the water cooler or
在饮水机附近或
whatever at the office. And so for us
办公室里的一切。所以对我们来说也是如此。
ultimately when we came to LA and we
最终，当我们来到洛杉矶时，我们
were in the in the blue house, one of
当时我们在蓝色房子里，其中一个
the big decisions we were confronting at
我们当时面临的重大决定
the time was whether or not we should
当时的问题是，我们是否应该
move the company from LA to the Bay
将公司从洛杉矶迁至湾区
Area. And there was a lot of pressure,
区域。当时压力很大。
you know, hey, all the tech talent is,
你知道，嘿，所有的技术人才都是，
you know, in the Bay Area. it's really
你知道，在旧金山湾区。真是
important um for for you guys to be up
很重要，对你们来说要准时起床
there for the for the talent and and so
那里是为了人才，所以
we just got our team together and you
我们刚把团队组建好，而你
know that had our first council and
知道我们举行了第一次理事会，
everyone went around the circle and
大家围着圆圈走了一圈，
shared their thoughts. Should we stay in
分享了他们的想法。我们应该继续待在……
LA or not? How did they feel about that?
洛杉矶，还是其他地方？他们对此有何感想？
What did they think? And what was so
他们怎么想的？而那又是什么呢？
clear coming out of that conversation we
那次谈话之后，我们很清楚地意识到
didn't even need to make a decision. It
甚至都不需要做决定。它
was just obvious that the that we
很明显，我们
believed in LA and wanted to be in LA
相信洛杉矶，也想留在洛杉矶。
and the team thought it was actually
团队认为这实际上
something really important to our
这对我们来说非常重要
business, to our identity, to actually
商业，我们的身份，实际上
the way that we hired talent because
我们招聘人才的方式是因为
people had to really commit to moving to
人们必须真正下定决心搬到那里
LA to be a part of the the company. So
洛杉矶将成为公司的一部分。所以
that was the first time we used council
那是我们第一次使用市政服务。
at at Snap and I saw how effective it
我在Snap工作时亲眼见证了它的有效性。
was in the workplace setting. Then as
当时是在工作场所。然后作为
the business got a lot bigger and it
公司规模越来越大，而且
became much more important to connect
联系变得更加重要
with people who were new to the company
与公司新员工一起
or you know worked in a different area
或者你知道，在其他领域工作过
of the company, council became just a
公司理事会最终变成了一个……
really useful tool for for doing that.
非常实用的工具。
Um and so you know at SNAP we have
嗯，你知道，在SNAP（补充营养援助计划）我们有
council facilitators whose job it is to
理事会协调员的职责是
to run these uh councils and now many
管理这些委员会，现在有很多
more companies are interested in doing
更多公司对这样做感兴趣
this and we we also help help train
这一点，我们也会帮助进行培训。
companies or offer sessions for other
公司或为其他公司提供课程
companies to help um help them bring
公司帮助他们带来
their team members together. What is the
他们的团队成员在一起。什么是
essence of it? It's just get the get a
它的本质是什么？就是得到一个
small team in a certain department
某个部门的小团队
around a table and let everybody speak
围坐在桌旁，让每个人都发言。
from the heart, listen from the heart
用心聆听，用心倾听
and be spontaneous. Yeah. And it's
保持随性。是的。而且是
usually not sitting around a table. It's
通常不会围坐在桌子旁。它是
usually sitting on the floor in a
通常坐在地板上
circle. Um, which again I think helps
圆圈。嗯，我觉得这很有帮助。
create that feeling. You know, when
营造那种感觉。你知道，当
you're sitting in a a circle, everyone
你们围坐成一个圈，每个人
is situated equally, which I think is a
位置相同，我认为这是
really important thing. As you
非常重要的事情。正如你
mentioned, companies have a lot of
正如前面提到的，公司有很多
hierarchy. I think it feels really
等级制度。我觉得感觉真的
different in a company when everyone see
在公司里，当每个人都看到情况时，情况就不同了。
that seat around a circle. Uh, and
围成一圈的座位。呃，还有
everyone's voice is important and
每个人的声音都很重要，
everyone's voice is heard. You know,
每个人的声音都能被听到。你知道，
whether it's just saying, "Wow, I you
哪怕只是简单地说一句“哇，我爱你”
know, that was a a really tough uh
我知道，那真是太难了。
weekend or actually I had an amazing
周末过得非常棒，或者说，我度过了一个美好的周末。
time. I went out to dinner with my wife.
时间。我和妻子出去吃饭了。
It was fabulous." And and I think people
太棒了。”而且我认为人们
find new points of connection that they
找到新的连接点
maybe wouldn't have found otherwise
否则或许就找不到答案了。
without it. Interesting. As a leader,
没有它。有趣的。作为领导者，
how do you know in those situations
你怎么知道在这些情况下会发生什么？
whether to listen to your team or not to
是否听从团队的意见
listen to your team? Because you know,
听从团队的指示？因为你知道，
it sounds quite risky for a founder, I'm
听起来对创始人来说风险相当大，我是这么认为的。
not saying this is what you do, but for
我不是说你就是这么做的，但是……
a founder to run their company on
一位创始人来运营他们的公司
consensus, i.e. making sure everybody
共识，即确保每个人
agrees on something. And we're actually
在某事上达成一致。而我们实际上是
seeing this in the post-pandemic world
在后疫情时代看到这一点
with this whole like remote work debate
关于远程办公的整个争论
where some companies originally were
有些公司最初是
okay everybody's going to be remote and
好的，所有人都要远程办公。
then it went back to a lot of companies
然后它又回到了许多公司手中。
are like no come back into the office
就像没人会回办公室一样。
and I mean if you ask a team they're
我的意思是，如果你问一支球队，他们会说
probably not going to all say let's run
可能不会所有人都说“让我们跑吧”。
back to the office but as a CEO you have
回到办公室，但作为首席执行官，你拥有……
to make a call and what is this the the
拨打电话，这是什么？
remote policy with Snap at the moment we
目前我们使用 Snap 进行远程策略开发
are more than four days a week in the
每周超过四天
office on average more than is that by
办公室平均而言比那更多
policy or is that just what's happening?
政策如此，还是这只是事实？
That is by policy and also what's
这是政策规定，也是实际情况。
happening. Okay. And did you ever move
正在发生。好的。你搬过家吗？
on that? Was there ever a moment in the
就那件事而言？是否曾有过这样一个时刻？
pandemic where you thought during the
疫情期间你的想法是什么？
pandemic I thought I would never go back
疫情期间，我以为我再也回不去了。
to the office. I was like, you know,
去办公室。我当时就想，你知道吗，
going into the pandemic, I I was waking
疫情爆发之初，我醒来时……
up before our kids woke up. I was
在孩子们醒来之前我们就起床了。我当时
getting home after they were asleep. I
他们睡着后，我们才回到家。我
there was a moment I was like, what am I
那一刻我心想，我到底是什么？
doing with my life? I'm never seeing our
我的人生目标是什么？我永远也见不到我们
kids. What am I going to do? And the
孩子们。我该怎么办？以及
pandemic happened and it was like a
疫情爆发了，就像……
miracle. I'm like, oh my god, I get to
奇迹。我当时就想，我的天哪，我居然可以
see our kids every single day. I get to
每天都能见到我们的孩子。我得去
wake up and see our kids. And I have an
醒来看看我们的孩子。我有一个
open door policy. If I'm working from
实行开放式政策。如果我正在工作
home in my home office, our kids can
在我的家庭办公室里，我们的孩子可以
come in anytime. It was only a problem
随时欢迎光临。这只是个问题。
once when uh one of our boys came in
有一次，呃，我们其中一个男孩进来了。
fully nude with two Oreos, which
一丝不挂地拿着两块奥利奥饼干，
actually prompted me to consider going
实际上促使我考虑去
back to the office. But I really I I
回到办公室。但我真的我真的
thought it was important for our kids
认为这对我们的孩子很重要
that, hey, if I'm at home, I'm not like
嘿，如果我在家，我就不会那样。
shut shut away in in my office. You can
我把自己关在办公室里。你可以
come in anytime, you know, with anything
随时都可以来，任何东西都可以。
and and and I'll help you out. Sometimes
我会帮你的。有时
it meant they spent a lot of time
这意味着他们花费了大量时间
sitting on my laps and sitting on my lap
坐在我的腿上，坐在我的腿上
in in in meetings. But in any case,
在会议中。但无论如何，
there was a period of time in the
有一段时间
pandemic where I was like, why would I
疫情期间，我当时想，我为什么要这么做？
ever go back to the office? I'm here
还会回办公室上班吗？我在这里
with my family and but but I think you
和我的家人在一起，但是，但是我觉得你
know that the adrenaline and the
要知道肾上腺素和
teamwork that happened you know during
你知道，在团队合作过程中发生的那种合作
the pandemic when we were all able to
疫情期间，我们所有人都能够……
work together really effectively
合作非常有效
remotely that was only possible because
远程操作之所以成为可能，仅仅是因为
we had been working together physically
我们之前一直在一起工作。
for such a long period of time. We had
如此长的时间。我们曾
all of that trust built. We had all that
这一切都建立在信任之上。我们拥有这一切。
shortorthhand built. We had that you
速记本。我们曾经有过你
know many times you know long road
很多时候，你知道漫漫长路
mapaps of ideas we had come up with to
我们想出的各种想法的地图
get physically together and that really
真正地聚在一起，这才是真正的
sustained the company through that
该公司得以维持运营。
period of time and it became clear to me
过了一段时间，我才明白过来。
that the culture was starting to fray
这种文化开始瓦解。
right people don't learn the culture as
合适的人不会像其他人那样学习文化。
quickly when they're alone and and and
当他们独处时，很快就会……
remote uh you know separated all all
远程的，你知道，所有东西都分开了
around the world and I was really
环游世界，我真的
worried about our ability to
担心我们是否有能力
consistently be creative which is so
始终保持创造力，这真是太棒了！
important to our business if we weren't
如果我们不是，这对我们的业务来说就非常重要。
physically together. So ultimately um
实际在一起。所以最终……
you know and especially after that Oreo
你知道，尤其是在奥利奥之后
incident we thought it was pretty
我们认为这起事件相当
important to get get back to get back to
重要的是要回到……
the office. How was that received? One
办公室。反响如何？一
of the things that we tried to do that
我们尝试做的事情中，有
was you know helped team members is just
你知道，帮助团队成员就是
give a pretty long runway. We we made
留出相当长的跑道。我们制造
that decision pretty early on and then
很早就做出了这个决定，然后
gave team members quite an extended
给团队成员提供了相当长的……
period of time. I think it was like six
一段时间。我想大概是六点吧。
or nine months for folks who had you
或者对于那些有你的人来说是九个月。
know extenduating circumstances. We you
了解扩展情况。我们你
know would grant exceptions and over
知道会授予例外情况并超过
time that allowed people to adapt their
这段时间让人们得以调整自己
lives. you know, sometimes they'd rented
生命。你知道，有时候他们会租
a house or bought a house somewhere else
在别处买了一套房子或房子
and needed to move back to one of our
需要搬回我们其中一个住处。
hub office locations. And so, we wanted
枢纽办公地点。所以，我们想要
to give people enough flexibility to do
给予人们足够的灵活性去做
that, not just, you know, have them wake
不仅仅是让他们醒来
up one morning and say, "Come come back
一天早上醒来，我说：“回来吧，回来吧。”
to the office." That's not super
去办公室。”这不太好
thoughtful. For any entrepreneurs that
周到。对于任何企业家来说，
are out there now listening to our
现在有人正在收听我们的节目。
conversation and they're at the very
对话正在进行中，他们正处于最……
beginning of their journey and they are
这是他们旅程的开始，他们是
um they're thinking about so many
嗯，他们在考虑很多事情。
different things, so many different
不同的事物，很多不同的事物
problems, their products aren't working,
问题在于，他们的产品无法正常工作。
their customers are complaining. When
他们的顾客都在抱怨。什么时候
you think about the principles of being
你思考存在的原则
successful as an entrepreneur that that
作为一名成功的企业家，
are transferable across all
可在所有领域转移
industries, have you defined what those
行业，您是否已经定义了这些行业？
principles are in your mind to be
原则在你心中是……
successful in any endeavor? We talked
在任何领域都取得成功吗？我们聊了
about some of them already. We said
已经了解其中一些情况了。我们说
about culture, we said about hiring. Is
关于文化，我们谈到了招聘。是
there anything else that you've come to
你还有其他事要办吗？
learn in your wisdom that entrepreneurs
用你的智慧去领悟企业家们
like me should be thinking a lot about
像我这样的人应该好好想想……
as fundamental principles of success?
作为成功的基本原则？
To me, it seems like the biggest
在我看来，这似乎是最大的
differentiator is how much you care. I
关键在于你有多在意。我
mean that just seems day in and day out
这意味着这种情况似乎日复一日地发生。
as I meet entrepreneurs and people
当我遇到企业家和人们时
working on businesses. How much do you
从事商业相关工作。你多少钱
care about your business, your team,
关心你的事业，你的团队，
your customer? Uh and those are the
您的客户？嗯，那些就是
entrepreneurs I think that are really
我认为真正的企业家
successful. They go that extra mile and
成功的。他们会付出额外的努力，
and that care can come from different
这种关怀可以来自不同方面
places, right? It can be about the
地方，对吧？这可能与……有关
impact that people want to make in the
人们希望产生的影响
world. It can be about something that
世界。它可能与某事有关
people really want to invent. It can be
人们真的很想发明创造。它可以是
their love of their customers and seeing
他们对顾客的爱和感受
the smile on their customers faces. But
顾客脸上的笑容。但
how much people care about what they do
人们有多在意自己所做的事情
seems to me to be quite a large
在我看来，这似乎相当大
predictor. if not the predictor of of
预测器。如果不是预测因子
success. Can you care too much? I I
成功。你会太在意别人的看法吗？我 我
don't think so. Sounds stressful though
我不这么认为。听起来压力很大。
caring that much. I thought in your book
如此在意。我想在你的书中
you talk about Don't talk about my book.
你谈论……别谈论我的书。
I'm not I'm not disagreeing. I'm just
我并没有反对。我只是
playing devil's advocate. That's one of
扮演反方角色。那是其中之一
the things I loved about your book is
我喜欢你这本书的地方在于……
you said, "Hey, people are thinking
你说，“嘿，人们都在想……”
about stress wrong." Which I thought was
关于压力的说法是错误的。”我当时觉得
really really powerful. Like I I wish
非常非常强大。就像我希望的那样
more people talked about it that way
更多人这样谈论这件事。
because I think you know you just
因为我觉得你知道你只是
Anyways, you you wrote it. You don't
总之，是你写的。你没有
even need to. No, but no, but it's it's
甚至不需要。不，不，但它是它的
a good point. Something I was going to
说得有道理。我原本打算……
ask you about is the stress of of being
问问你，压力是什么？
you and do you have techniques to manage
你和你有什么管理技巧吗？
that stress, especially running a public
那种压力，尤其是在运营一家公共机构时。
company? I just think it's psychotic.
公司？我觉得这简直是精神错乱。
Well, what I what I thought was hilar
嗯，我当时觉得很搞笑
So, this has been one of my hilarious
所以，这是我经历过的最搞笑的事情之一。
findings from my ring over the last
过去一段时间里，我从我的戒指中发现了一些东西。
couple of days trying it out. I finally
试用了两天。我终于
had enough days that it like gave me a
日子过得够久了，感觉就像给了我一个
stress score or whatever, and I'm just
压力评分之类的，我只是
not stressed during the day, which
白天不感到压力，
really lines up with like how I
这与我的想法非常吻合。
experience work. I don't find work to be
积累工作经验。我不觉得工作是
very stressful. I think a lot of it has
压力很大。我认为很多方面都……
become very normal because you know over
变得非常正常，因为你知道超过
the years we've grown our business and
这些年来，我们的业务不断发展壮大。
encountered all sorts of wild situations
遇到过各种各样的突发状况
that at this point it's it's just a a
就目前而言，它只是一个
daily normal thing. Um, do you
日常琐事。嗯，你
celebrate? Do you get really happy when
庆祝？你什么时候会感到非常快乐？
you have professional moments where I
你也有在专业场合中我
don't know, you launch a new feature and
不知道，你推出了一项新功能，
it's wellreceived. Do you get really
它广受好评。你真的会这么想吗？
happy? No, it's something that I I need
快乐的？不，这是我需要的东西。
to work on, especially celebrating our
努力的方向，尤其是庆祝我们的
team as well. Like I, you know, just
团队也是如此。就像我，你知道，只是
providing more of that really positive
提供更多真正积极的因素
feedback. That's not something I do um a
反馈。那不是我会做的事。
ton, especially around like outcome
吨，尤其是在类似结果的周围
focused goals. When I see a great idea,
目标明确。当我看到一个好主意时，
if I see a great new idea, then I get
如果我看到一个很棒的新想法，那么我就会……
really happy and excited. I love it.
非常开心和激动。我喜欢它。
But, you know, to me, uh, you know, some
但是，你知道，对我来说，呃，你知道，一些
of these big corporate milestones, like
这些重大的企业里程碑，例如
the growth of the community is cool. I I
社区的发展壮大令人欣喜。我 我
was talking to someone the other day.
前几天和某人聊过这件事。
They were like, "You should throw a
他们说：“你应该扔一个
party when you guys reach a billion
等你们粉丝突破十亿的时候一起庆祝吧！
people." I was like, "Oh my god, what a
人们。”我当时想，“我的天哪，这真是……”
great idea." Like that. Why didn't I
好主意。” 就是这样。我为什么没想到呢？
think of it? Um, so I think we should
想想看？嗯，所以我觉得我们应该
celebrate uh things like that. I wonder
庆祝诸如此类的事情。我想知道
if that there's an element of defense to
如果其中存在防御因素的话
this because I was speaking to a lot of
这是因为我当时正在和很多人交谈
founders recently and they were telling
最近，创始人们都在讲述他们的故事。
me how they've over time and with
让我了解他们随着时间的推移以及与
maturity, they almost just developed
成熟的时候，他们几乎才刚刚发展起来。
this calm within all the chaos where
在一切混乱之中，却又如此平静
they're not moved up or down. And and
它们既没有向上移动，也没有向下移动。而且
some of them make the case to me that if
他们中的一些人向我证明，如果
you are moved up by something that
你因某事而晋升
happens externally, it's impossible
如果是外部因素造成的，那是不可能的。
therefore not to be moved down when
因此，当……时，不应向下移动。
something bad happens externally. So
外部发生了不好的事情。所以
founders develop this almost like
创始人开发这个几乎就像
coldness to them. That would be a real
对他们冷漠。那将是一件真正的
problem for me because so much of
对我来说是个问题，因为很多
creating products is about connecting
产品创造的本质在于连接
with people and listening to people and
与人交往，倾听他人，
being able to empathize with them. So
能够理解他们的感受。所以
like I absolutely under no circumstances
我绝对在任何情况下都不会这样做
can cut off my emotional response. I
可以切断我的情感反应。我
think, you know, I pick the things or I,
你知道，我觉得，我挑选东西或者我，
you know, the things that make me feel
你知道，那些让我感觉
really happy are things like being with
真正快乐的事情包括和……在一起
our children or something or, you know,
我们的孩子或者其他什么，你知道的
Hart did really well on his math test
哈特数学考试考得非常好
the other day and I was like, "Awesome."
前几天我看到的时候就想：“太棒了。”
You know what I mean? I got super
你知道我的意思？我超级
excited about that. But I I think to
对此我感到很兴奋。但我认为
your point, one of the things I I do
你说得对，我做的其中一件事就是
regret at some point is not celebrating
后悔有时就是没有庆祝
some of those great moments. I think,
那些美好的瞬间。我认为，
you know, sometimes as an entrepreneur
你知道，有时候作为一名企业家
when everything is like going up to up
当一切都像向上攀登一样时
and to the right and and going super
向右，然后超级
well, you're always like, "What's going
你总是会问：“发生了什么事？”
to go wrong?" You know, what could go
会出什么问题呢？”你知道，会出什么问题呢？
wrong? And so you don't think about
错误的？所以你不会去想……
celebrating that great moment because
庆祝那个伟大的时刻
you're thinking about, you know, the
你在想，你知道，那
next day or or what what you could be
第二天或者你可能会是什么情况
doing differently to make sure the
采取不同的做法来确保
business can keep growing. And and I
企业可以持续发展。而且我
think breaking out of that like, you
想想如何摆脱那种状态，就像你
know, what could go wrong, which
我知道，可能会出什么问题，哪个
actually is quite helpful. That paranoia
实际上很有帮助。那种妄想症
is probably pretty helpful. But
可能很有帮助。但
celebrate those moments um is is
庆祝那些时刻，嗯，是的
important. So that's a good takeaway
重要的。所以这是一个很好的结论。
from from our chat. Was there was there
摘自我们的聊天记录。那里有吗？
a hardest day for you? A day when you
你经历过的最艰难的一天是什么？有一天，你
were challenged the most as the CEO of
作为首席执行官，我面临的挑战最大。
Snapchat that comes to mind when I say
说到这个，我首先想到的就是 Snapchat。
that?
那？
I think some of the hardest days um the
我认为最难熬的几天是……
the painful days have been you know when
你知道，那些痛苦的日子就是什么时候。
we've had to make changes to our company
我们不得不对公司进行一些调整。
structure things like things like
结构化事物，例如
layoffs. I mean I I feel like just a
裁员。我的意思是，我觉得自己就像一个
huge sense of responsibility to our team
对团队有着强烈的责任感
members and so when we let them down
成员们，所以当我们让他们失望时
like that uh you know that's those days
就像那样，你知道，就是那些日子。
are are the worst. I mean that's that's
是最差的。我的意思是，那就是……
you know of course you know in many
你当然知道，在很多方面你都知道。
cases worse for them and I you know um
他们的病情更严重，你知道，嗯
but but as a leader the sense of shame I
但是，作为一名领导者，我感到羞愧。
feel when we have to make a decision
当我们必须做出决定时，会有什么感觉？
like that that's you know that's sucks.
你知道，那样太糟糕了。
Do you ever have imposter syndrome
你有没有过冒名顶替综合症的经历？
because I think about the odds of you
因为我想到你成功的几率。
the odds of launching a social media
推出社交媒体的几率
communications application as we said
正如我们所说，通信应用
earlier like a billion in one or
早些年就像十亿合一或
something great I don't know this it's
我不知道这是什么，这很棒。
staggering and I guess it's not a
令人震惊，我想这并不是什么
billion there's not been a billion of
十亿，还没有十亿。
them but the odds are just against you.
虽然他们可能成功，但你成功的几率很小。
So when that happens and it explodes and
所以当这种情况发生并爆炸时，
it becomes this major global app, is
它成为了这款全球主流应用，是
there not any feelings of imposter
没有冒名顶替的感觉。没有那种觉得自己是冒名顶替者的感觉。
syndrome?
综合征？
I don't like the word imposter syndrome
我不喜欢“冒名顶替综合症”这个词。
because it doesn't sound very nice. And
因为听起来不太好听。和
I I think imposter syndrome is actually
我认为冒名顶替综合症实际上是
a a good thing in the sense that it
从某种意义上说，这是件好事。
means that you feel like there's more to
这意味着你觉得还有更多……
learn, right? And so like for me, you
学吧？所以对我来说，你
know, as I approach any situation or,
我知道，当我面对任何情况时，或者
you know, any meeting or, you know,
你知道，任何会议或者，你知道，
anything that we're trying to do out in
我们在外面尝试做的任何事情
the world, I'm always trying to think
这个世界，我总是试图思考
like what else could I learn here? I
我还能在这里学到什么呢？我
obviously, you know, this is an
显然，你知道，这是一个
opportunity for me to really listen to
让我有机会认真倾听
learn to figure out how I can how I can
学会思考我该如何做我该如何做
grow. And so like I never want to feel
生长。所以，我永远都不想有这种感觉。
like, oh, I you know, I've I've got
比如，哦，你知道，我有，我有
this. I always want to feel like what
这。我一直想感受那种感觉。
else could I learn? What could I be
我还能学到什么呢？我能成为什么？
doing differently? You know, how could I
另辟蹊径？你知道，我怎么能这样呢？
grow? And I I think sometimes when we
生长？而且我觉得有时候当我们
call it imposttor syndrome, like that's
可以称之为冒名顶替综合症，就像那样。
not super helpful. I think we should be
帮助不大。我认为我们应该
telling people, hey, it's a it's a good
告诉人们，嘿，这是个好东西
thing if you feel like you've got more
如果你觉得你还有更多，那就想想办法。
to learn. It's a good thing if you feel
学习。如果你觉得……那是一件好事。
like, hey, maybe this isn't totally
比如，嘿，也许这并不完全
normal to be running a big company,
经营一家大公司是件很正常的事。
right? Maybe maybe it's a good thing to
正确的？或许，这或许是件好事
stay open to to different different
保持开放的心态，接受不同的事物。
ideas or ways of doing things. If um if
想法或做事方法。如果嗯如果
Snapchat goes away today,
Snapchat今天正式关闭。
what does Evan end up doing? Starting a
埃文最后做了什么？开始
new company. I would probably continue a
新公司。我可能会继续
lot of the work that we've been doing as
我们一直在做的很多工作都是如此
a family to to give back. I mean, I
一个想要回馈家庭的人。我的意思是，我
think that's been like the greatest
我觉得那简直太棒了
blessing of this whole SNAP experience
整个 SNAP 经历带来的福气
is being able to to give back. Um, you
能够回馈社会。嗯，你
know, we've done a lot as a as a family.
我知道，我们全家一起做了很多事。
We've done a lot with SNAP and the Snap
我们在 SNAP 和 Snap 方面做了很多工作。
Foundation. And like that to me is like,
基础。对我来说，这就像是……
you know, hopefully the the rest of my
你知道，希望我的其余部分……
life is that story. You wouldn't want to
人生就是这样一个故事。你肯定不想
start another tech company? Never in a
再创办一家科技公司？从未在
million years. Really? No chance.
百万年。真的吗？没戏。
No chance. Why? Um, it's it's way too
没戏。为什么？嗯，这太过了。
hard. Way too hard.
难的。太难了。
I told you it was psychotic. I could
我早就跟你说过，那是精神病。我可以
have told you that when you started it.
我当初在你开始的时候就告诉过你了。
You should have asked me. Whenever I
你应该问我的。每当我
meet a serial entrepreneur, I'm like,
遇到一位连续创业者，我的反应是：
"What? What?"
什么？什么？
What when you say it's hard? This is I I
当你说这很难的时候，你会怎么想？这是我
asked this question. I paused on it
提出了这个问题。我停顿了一下。
because I actually posted about this my
因为我其实发帖说过这件事
Instagram and my Snap this morning about
今天早上我在Instagram和Snapchat上发布了关于……
how hard it is and how nobody talks
这有多难，而且没人谈论这件事。
about that. And so when you experience
关于那件事。所以当你经历
the hardship as a founder, you kind of
作为创始人的艰辛，你大概会……
look in the mirror and think it's you.
看着镜子，想象那是你。
Do you know what I mean? You think, "Oh,
你明白我的意思吗？你会想，“哦，
this is evidence of my inadequacy."
这证明我的能力不足。
But it really I mean, why' you say that?
但我的意思是，你为什么这么说？
Because it sounds like you have PTSD.
因为听起来你好像患有创伤后应激障碍（PTSD）。
No, it's more I think like the the hard
不，我觉得更像是困难的一面。
kind of to your point about how do you
有点像你刚才说的，你如何……
turn stress into something positive,
将压力转化为积极因素
right? The hard is a good thing in the
正确的？困难在某种情况下是件好事。
sense that like what makes it so fun but
感觉就像是什么让它如此有趣一样，但是
also so challenging is the rate at which
同样具有挑战性的还有速度
you have to change and grow. Like that
你必须改变和成长。就像那样
is what has been so unbelievably hard,
真正令人难以置信的是，
right? that you know the business at
正确的？你知道这家公司
four people is really different than the
四个人的情况与四个人的情况截然不同。
business at 100 people. The business
企业规模100人。这家公司
when we're supporting a million people
当我们支持一百万人时
is different than the business
与企业不同
supporting 850 million people using our
我们为 8.5 亿人提供支持
service. And to have to change so much
服务。而且要改变这么多。
over that period of time, to have to
在那段时间里，不得不
grow so much over that period of time,
在那段时间里成长了很多，
like that's what's hard. Like, because
这就是难点所在。比如，因为
you just have to force yourself to
你只需要强迫自己
change and grow and think about what you
改变、成长，并思考你
you know, how do I how do I need to
你知道，我该怎么做？我需要怎么做？
adapt to to be the the person that our
适应成为我们想要的那种人
business needs six months from now,
企业未来六个月的需求
which inevitably will be different than
这必然会与……有所不同
than who I am today. So, do you think
比现在的我更像现在的我。所以，你觉得
you could run Snap for the rest of your
你可以运行 Snap 来度过剩下的时间
life? I would certainly be an honor. I
生活？我当然感到非常荣幸。我
mean, I'd love that.
我的意思是，我非常乐意。
Maybe you you'd leave Snap and then
也许你会离开Snap，然后
you'd get bored and then you'd start
你会感到无聊，然后你就会开始
some some new new company. Who knows?
一些新公司。谁知道呢？
And we have a closing tradition on this
我们还有一个结束仪式的传统。
podcast where the last guest leaves a
播客节目中，最后一位嘉宾离开了
question for the next guest not knowing
下一位客人不知道这个问题
who they're leaving it for. And the
他们要把房子留给谁？以及
question that has been left for you
留给你的问题
interesting. Feel like I may have asked
有趣的。感觉我可能问过这个问题
this before, but you're going to have to
以前也发生过这种情况，但你必须……
do your very
做你自己
best. What is the hardest thing you ever
最好的。你经历过的最难的事情是什么？
had to overcome?
必须克服什么？
Yeah, I think that the hardest thing,
是的，我觉得最难的是……
maybe this is a good segue from what we
也许这可以很好地引出我们之前讨论的内容。
were just talking about. The hardest
我们刚才在谈论的。最难的
thing I've ever had to overcome is
我曾经克服过的最大挑战是
myself, right? I've constantly had to
是我自己，对吧？我一直不得不
force myself at at every stage to grow
强迫自己在每个阶段都成长
and change and be different and evolve
改变，变得不同，不断进化
to meet the needs of our our business
为了满足我们业务的需求
and our community or my family. And I
以及我们的社区或我的家人。我
think, you know, that that's the that's
想想，你知道，那就是那个。
the the battle with yourself to become a
与自己斗争，最终成为一个
better version of yourself every day.
每天都成为更好的自己。
That that that's a tough one.
那确实是个难题。
self-awareness. I was thinking about
自我意识。我一直在想……
that as you were just saying that about
正如你刚才所说，
the idea of self-awareness as a CEO and
首席执行官的自我意识理念
how you how you develop that because
你是如何发展出这种能力的？因为
it's such an important thing when
这真是一件非常重要的事情
there's so much counting on you being
有太多事情都指望着你。
aware. So I don't know how you think
意识到的。所以我不知道你是怎么想的。
about self-awareness as a leader and how
关于领导者的自我意识以及如何
if there's any system you've had to
如果你曾经使用过任何系统……
cultivate that awareness that's been
培养那种意识
productive. I I love that you said that.
高效。我喜欢你说的这句话。
I I think
我认为
um it's so challenging and it becomes
嗯，这太具有挑战性了，而且会变得
harder and
更难
harder I think as the business grows and
我认为随着业务的增长，难度会越来越大。
you grow as a leader a because you
你之所以能成长为一名领导者，是因为你
become busier. So it's harder to tune in
变得更忙。所以更难调频。
and really connect with people right in
并真正与人们建立联系
the way that you really need to to to
你真正需要的方式是
understand how they really feel or what
了解他们的真实感受或什么
they're thinking and to create a trusted
他们正在思考，并试图建立一个值得信赖的组织。
relationship so they feel like they can
建立关系，让他们觉得自己可以
tell that to you. As the company grows,
告诉你们。随着公司的发展，
you know, I think people become very
你知道，我觉得人们会变得非常
focused on curating the information that
专注于整理以下信息：
you're receiving. So you're constantly
您正在接收。所以你总是
getting a lot of reporting that you know
收到很多报道，你知道
shows leaders and and their teams in a
展现领导者及其团队
very positive light. And so you have to
非常积极的光线。所以你必须
think about proactively breaking that
考虑主动打破这种局面。
because that will be the the default
因为那将是默认设置。
that the organization I think will do.
我认为该组织会这样做。
All of a sudden they will just try to
突然之间，他们就会尝试
make sure you're receiving information,
请确保您已收到信息。
right? That that shows them in a in a
正确的？那表明他们在
great light because they want to be
明亮的光线，因为他们想要成为
successful. It makes perfect sense. But
成功的。完全合情合理。但
I think you have to really do a lot of
我认为你真的需要做很多……
work to break that and to get out deeper
努力打破这种局面，并深入探索。
in the organization and just talk to
在组织里，只要和……交谈即可
people and and I think there's no
人们，而且我认为没有
substitute. I wish there was, but
代替。我希望有，但是……
there's really no substitute to just
真的没有其他办法可以替代它
walking around and talking to people.
四处走走，和人们聊聊天。
And I found that that's an unbelievable
我发现这简直难以置信。
way in our organization to just get
在我们组织里，有办法做到这一点。
great information really quickly. And
信息非常有用，而且速度很快。和
then you see as a CEO, someone's working
然后你作为CEO会看到，有人在工作
on a presentation, they're like, "Oh,
在演示中，他们会说：“哦，
yeah, this presentation will get to you
是的，这场演讲会让你印象深刻。
in like six weeks, you know." Um, but
大概六周后吧，你知道的。”嗯，但是
yeah, sure. I can show you a little bit
好的，当然可以。我可以给你展示一点。
bit of it right now. You know, because
现在有一点。你知道，因为
the way that uh you know, calendars work
你知道，日历的运作方式
as a as a CEO and business reviews work
作为首席执行官和业务审查工作
and that sort of thing, all this sort of
诸如此类的事情，所有这些
information, I think, you know, ends up
我认为，信息最终会……
flowing in a way that's just slower than
流动速度比……慢。
it than it did in the in the beginning
它比一开始的时候要好得多。
of the company. So, I think, you know,
公司。所以，我觉得，你知道，
really taking the time to connect with
真正花时间与人建立联系
people and form those trusted
人们并形成那些值得信赖的人
relationships. Uh being really proactive
人际关系。嗯，要非常积极主动。
about breaking the information system
关于破坏信息系统
that will form around you, right, if
那会在你周围形成，对吧，如果
you're not more deliberate about going
你并非刻意选择前往。
and getting other sources of
并获取其他来源
information. That's that's really
信息。就是这样。
important. And then you know I think
重要的。然后你知道，我觉得
just you know that empathy and intuition
你知道，同理心和直觉
really helps because sometimes people
真的很有帮助，因为有时候人们
feel uncomfortable saying how they
难以启齿地说出他们
really feel and it's only because you
真切地感受到了，这仅仅是因为你
know you just notice something in their
你注意到他们身上的一些特质了吗？
eye or their affect or whatever it is
眼睛，或者他们的表情，或者其他什么
that you're like is that you know is
你的感受就像你知道的那样
that really how you feel you know we
你知道，这就是你真正的感受吗？
should or should we really be doing this
我们应该这样做吗？或者我们真的应该这样做吗？
differently and I think you know the
不一样，我想你知道的。
ability to really understand how how
真正理解如何运作的能力
people feel and create a space for them
人们感受并为他们创造空间
to actually share their perspective it
实际上分享他们的观点
just you know is so so valuable. Do you
你知道这一点是多么宝贵。你
ever find yourself feeling a little bit
有没有发现自己感觉有点
impatient with your team? Cuz I get this
对你的团队不耐烦了吗？因为我明白这一点
a lot. I'm always trying to make things
很多。我总是尝试做事情。
move faster. And I think maybe there's a
加快速度。而且我觉得或许存在……
point of privilege where as the leader
特权点，而领导者
of an organization, you know, you can
你知道，对于一个组织来说，你可以
just break everything to make things
为了创造而打破一切
happen, but maybe the intern in the
可能会发生，但也许是实习生
office doesn't feel like they've got
办公室感觉不像他们有
that permission, but
获得许可，但是
urgency as a leader, speed. You talked
作为领导者，要有紧迫感和速度。你谈到
about increasing the learning speed of
关于提高学习速度
the organization. Do you ever feel
该组织。你是否曾有过这种感觉
impatient as a leader? I'm
作为领导者，你是否缺乏耐心？我是
extraordinarily impatient. Like, and I
极度缺乏耐心。就像，而且我
think it's in my DNA. I mean like my
我觉得这已经刻在我的基因里了。我的意思是，就像我的
father would not like the idea of
父亲不会喜欢这个想法
waiting like if you want to just like
就像你想的那样等待
punish my father you put him in a line
惩罚我父亲，把他排成一列
for anything like he will go ballist
任何类似的事情他都会暴跳如雷。
like it's just like he the thought of
就好像他想到……
waiting in a line for him would just
排队等他简直就是
drive him crazy because he's a very
把他逼疯，因为他非常
impatient person. I think I have some of
缺乏耐心的人。我想我有一些
that some of that impatience. You know
那其中有些许不耐烦。你知道
if I asked your team members what's Evan
如果我问你的团队成员埃文是谁，我会怎么回答。
like as a leader what do you think
作为领导者，你觉得呢？
they'd say? Oh my goodness.
他们会这么说？哦，我的天啊。
Um I don't know. They might all have
嗯，我不知道。他们可能都有
different perspectives because I really
不同的视角，因为我真的
try to like bring out the best in our
努力展现我们最好的一面
team members by showing different parts
团队成员通过展示不同部分来组成团队
of myself. I'm not the same leader to
我自己。我不再是以前的那个领导者了。
every individual. That would be
每个人。那将是
terrible. Uh I think so much of being a
糟糕的。嗯，我觉得成为一名……
leader is trying to figure out for each
领导者正试图弄清楚每个人的情况。
individual and each person what sort of
个人，以及每个人，什么样的
communication style will bring out the
沟通方式会暴露出来
best in them and their unique abilities.
他们各自的优点和独特能力。
So, you know, they engage the the way I
所以，你知道，他们参与的方式与我相同。
engage with our CEO, Derek, is different
与我们的首席执行官德里克互动是不同的。
than the way I engage with Betsy, who's
比我与贝齐的相处方式要好得多，贝齐是
our chief brand officer, is different
我们的首席品牌官与众不同。
than the way I engage with our our
比我与我们互动的方式更甚于我们
design team. And that that's important.
设计团队。这一点很重要。
If I asked them what you're good at,
如果我问他们你擅长什么，
what would they say?
他们会说什么？
Um, I think I'm good at a at a couple
嗯，我觉得我擅长几件事。
things. I think I'm quite good at
事物。我觉得我在这方面相当不错
um really understanding human needs and
真正了解人类需求
and wants and figuring out how to
以及想要的东西，并想办法
reflect that in our product. Uh I mean
这一点体现在我们的产品中。呃，我的意思是
oftentimes it's one of the competitions
通常情况下，这是其中一项比赛。
I like to have with our team is, you
我希望我们团队里有你。
know, a lot of times in in uh in
我知道，很多时候在呃……
engineering people like to run AB tests,
工程师喜欢做A/B测试，
right? So they'll like they'll run four
正确的？所以他们会像四人组那样跑四场。
AB tests and there they'll sort of pick,
AB测试，然后他们会从中挑选出来，
you know, the the one that performs the
你知道，就是那个执行……
best, right? And like this is the case
最好，对吧？情况就是这样。
for like a text string or something like
例如文本字符串或其他类似的东西
that. If they want to put a, you know,
那。如果他们想放一个，你知道，
text in the app, they'll write four
在应用程序中输入文本，他们会写四个
different variants of it or whatever.
它的不同变体或其他什么。
And I what I really like to do is figure
我真正喜欢做的事情是计算
out can I write the variant that will
我可以写出那个变体吗？
win the AB test without you know, you
赢得AB测试，你却浑然不知。
know, without them having to to run it.
他们无需运行就能知道。
And I think that sort of intuition of
我认为那种直觉
what people will respond to, uh, you
人们会对什么做出反应，呃，你
know, what makes sense to them, what's
要知道，对他们来说什么是合理的，什么是……
clear in terms of communicating through
沟通清晰
our product, our features, you know, and
我们的产品，我们的功能，你知道的，还有
that that sort of thing. I think I
就是那种事。我觉得我
that's something that I can offer the
这是我可以提供的。
team and and part of that's just because
团队，部分原因就是因为
I've been doing it for for 13 years
我做这件事已经13年了。
right every you know every week or
没错，你知道，每周或
almost every day looking at work with
几乎每天都在看着工作
our team and trying to figure out what
我们的团队正在努力弄清楚什么
what you know will resonate with the
你所了解的会引起共鸣
people that use our products. Um so I
使用我们产品的用户。嗯，所以……
think I'm good at that. I also think um
我觉得我挺擅长这个的。我也觉得……
kind of maybe this kind of to my earlier
或许有点像我之前提到的那种。
point. I really work hard to bring out
观点。我真的非常努力地去展现
the best in people. And I think, you
激发人们身上最美好的品质。而且我认为，你
know, hopefully if I've done my job
我知道，希望我没做错什么。
really well, people say like, "Wow, I
真的很好，人们会说，“哇，我
didn't think I could do that." Or, "I
我没想到我能做到。”或者，“我
didn't know I could do that." Or, "I
我不知道我能做到这一点。”或者，“我
didn't know that I was a really creative
我以前不知道自己这么有创造力。
person, but you showed me that I'm
你让我明白，我是一个人。
actually a really creative person.
其实他是一个非常有创造力的人。
That's so cool. Thanks." How? I think
太酷了。谢谢。“怎么做到的？”我想
oftentimes it's by giving people the
很多时候，这是通过给予人们
courage and the space uh to be creative
勇气和创造的空间
and also to show them the different ways
同时向他们展示不同的方法
that creativity applies. So for example,
这种创造力是适用的。例如，
you know, I think uh a lawyer might
你知道，我觉得律师可能会……
think, how could I be creative as a
想想，我怎样才能发挥创造力呢？
lawyer, right? But if you have a
你是律师吧？但是如果你有一个
conversation with a lawyer, as you know,
如你所知，与律师的谈话
as we did early on in our business and
就像我们创业初期所做的那样
say, you know, the problem today is all
比如说，你知道，今天的问题是所有
these privacy policies that are written,
这些已制定的隐私政策，
they make no damn sense. And I don't
它们完全没有道理。我没有
know if you've ever tried to read a
你知道你是否曾经尝试阅读过一本
privacy policy of one of these internet,
其中一家互联网公司的隐私政策
it doesn't make sense. What if we were
这说不通。如果我们是
creative and we actually wrote a privacy
富有创意，我们实际上写了一份隐私声明
policy that people could understand?
一项民众能够理解的政策？
Like wouldn't that be cool? like how how
那岂不是很酷吗？比如如何如何
could we solve this problem differently
我们能否用其他方法解决这个问题？
and have have a different sort of set of
并且拥有不同类型的
expectations and then people say wow
人们抱有期待，然后他们会说哇
that's interesting let's try doing that
那很有意思，我们试试看。
and they do it and they're like oh wow
他们照做了，然后惊叹道：“哇！”
no I am creative we can solve this
不，我很有创造力，我们可以解决这个问题。
problem differently we don't need to
换个角度思考问题，我们不需要……
just have another privacy policy just
再制定一份隐私政策就行了
like everybody else we can work really
和其他人一样，我们也能真正工作。
hard to put it in human terms and that
很难用人类的语言来表达，而且
would be better and so I think showing
会更好，所以我认为展示出来会更好。
all sorts of team members across our
我们团队中各种各样的成员
company the way that their work can be
公司以他们工作的方式
creative in service of our community or
以创意服务于我们的社区或
in service of our advertising partners
为我们的广告合作伙伴服务
that's something uh that I I I hope to
那是我希望……的事情
bring to our team and conversely what
为我们的团队带来什么，反之亦然
are you not good If id asked all of
你不好吗？如果我问了所有人……
them, I said, "What's Evan not good?"
我问他们：“埃文有什么不好？”
Almost everything else. I mean, that's
几乎所有其他东西。我的意思是，那就是
the that's the challenge. There's got to
这就是挑战所在。必须
be some defining traits that you're
列出一些你最显著的特质
like, if you ask my team after this,
比如，如果你事后问我的团队，
they'll tell you what I'm not good at.
他们会告诉你我不擅长什么。
They'll tell you what I'm good at, but
他们会告诉你我擅长什么，但是
they'll also tell you what I'm not good
他们还会告诉你我有哪些不足之处。
at, and they'll all agree. They'll have
他们都会同意的。他们将拥有
total consensus. Um, no, but I but I do
完全一致。嗯，不，但是我，但我确实
mean that seriously, that like in almost
我的意思是，认真地说，就像几乎
every area of our business, whether it's
我们业务的各个领域，无论是什么
HR or legal or um, you know, finance,
人力资源部、法务部或者财务部，你知道的，
whatever, I'm certainly far from the
总之，我离那边肯定很远。
best. I mean we our our team members are
最好的。我的意思是，我们，我们的团队成员是
extraordinarily talented at what they do
他们在各自的领域都极具天赋
across our uh business and by nature I'm
在我们整个业务范围内，就我而言，我天生就是
just not very good at those things. And
就是不太擅长这些事。和
so I think for me the real like uh you
所以我觉得对我来说，真正的你就像……
know secret I guess or not a not a
我知道这个秘密，我猜也可能不知道。
secret the the focus of what I've tried
秘密是我尝试过的重点。
to do over the years as so many
多年来，做了很多事情
entrepreneurs do is say how can I spend
企业家们会问：我该如何花钱？
more of my time doing what I'm good at
我把更多的时间花在自己擅长的事情上
you know collaborating with our team
你知道，和我们团队合作
trying to create new products be
尝试创造新产品
creative and then you know have a team
有创造力，然后你就知道要有团队了。
around me that's so much better at
我周围有比这好得多的人
everything else that you know I couldn't
其他所有你知道我无法做到的事
possibly be be better at es especially
可能更擅长英语，尤其是英语。
as a being a younger CEO I think that's
作为一名年轻的CEO，我认为这是……
probably even more important than it is
可能比这更重要
for for other people to be be able to
为了让其他人能够
have that self-awareness and humility to
要有那种自知之明和谦逊的态度
say I don't know all the answers cuz you
我说我不知道​​所有答案，因为你
started this company at bloody what like
这家公司是在我最需要的时候创办的。
21 years old 22 years old so you've
21岁 22岁，所以你已经
you've never done running a public
你从未运营过一家公共机构
company before so there I think humility
公司之前，所以我觉得谦逊
is probably even more important for
可能对……更为重要
someone like you at that stage I'm
像你这样的人，到了那个阶段，我
interestingly it's it is the strategic
有趣的是，这正是战略所在。
advantage right to be 20 years old and
拥有20岁这一优势
to not know anything so that you can ask
什么都不知道，这样你就可以问了。
any question and not look like an idiot
提出任何问题，都不会显得像个傻瓜
is the greatest gift in the world I mean
我的意思是，这是世界上最棒的礼物。
I was almost always the youngest person
我几乎总是年纪最小的。
in the almost always, you know, and that
几乎总是这样，你知道，而且
that was such a blessing because
那真是一件幸事，因为
everyone's like, "Oh, what what are you
大家都会说：“哦，你是什么？”
working on?" "Oh, an app. That's cool."
“在开发什么？” “哦，一个应用程序。”这很酷。”
And I'd be like, "Yeah, actually, would
然后我就会说，“是啊，实际上，会
you mind talking to me about like, you
你介意跟我聊聊你吗？
know, the best ways to prepare your
了解准备工作的最佳方法
company to be public?" And people are
公司要上市吗？”人们都在说
like, "Sure." You know, uh, so I I I
比如，“当然。”你知道，呃，所以我我我
think, you know, being able to use that
想想，你知道，能够利用这一点
naive as as the fundamental advantage to
天真地认为这是根本优势
be able to learn quickly is so
能够快速学习是如此重要
important. But have you lost that now?
重要的。但你现在已经失去了那种感觉吗？
Uh, hopefully never. I mean that's the
呃，希望永远不会。我的意思是，那就是
whole that that's like what I love to do
我觉得那正是我喜欢做的事情。
is the curiosity, the asking questions.
是好奇心，是提问的天性。
Evan, what is the this is my last
埃文，这是我的最后一次
question. What is the most important
问题。最重要的是什么？
question for entrepreneurs that are
给创业者的问题
listening to this conversation
听这段对话
now based on everything that you know
现在，基于你所知道的一切
and have
并且有
done that will help them that I didn't
这样做会帮助他们，而我没有。
ask?
问？
I think they should really ask
我觉得他们真的应该问问
themselves if they love what they're
如果他们热爱自己所做的事情，他们自己也会如此。
doing. And if they really love what
正在做。如果他们真的喜欢什么
they're doing, that will be the fuel
他们正在做的，那将成为燃料。
that will carry them the whole way. But
这将帮助他们一路前行。但
there are so many people who are trapped
有太多人被困住了。
building businesses or, you know, in
建立企业，或者，你知道，在
jobs that don't really love what they
那些并不真正热爱自己所做工作的工作
do, who haven't found how to use their
确实如此，但他们还没有找到如何使用他们的
special gifts in a way that applies to
以适用于以下情况的方式赠送特殊礼物
the the business world. And I think so
商业界。我也这么认为。
much of life is trying to figure out
人生的大部分时间都在试图弄明白
what is that thing that I can do that I
我能做的那件事是什么？
just love that brings out the best in me
就是喜欢这种能激发我最好一面的感觉。
and my talents. And I I think not giving
以及我的才能。而且我认为不给予
up in pursuing that is just so
努力追求这一点真是太棒了
important. Evan, thank you so much.
重要的。埃文，非常感谢你。
Thank you so much for doing this today.
非常感谢你今天抽出时间来做这件事。
I know you don't do a ton of podcasts,
我知道你不经常做播客节目，
so I was I was particularly honored that
所以，我感到格外荣幸。
you'd come and sit here with me. And
你会过来和我一起坐在这里。和
hopefully it wasn't it wasn't a
希望不是，真的不是。
nerve-wracking experience. I had a lot
令人神经紧张的经历。我有很多
of fun and thank you for helping me with
非常有趣，谢谢你帮助我
my 2025
我的2025
resolution. Going to try and make some
解决。我打算试着做一些
progress here. I'm so keen. I'm so keen
取得进展。我非常热衷。我非常热衷
to know who who in your life has been
了解你生命中曾经存在过的人。
nudging you to get out there more
鼓励你多走出去
because there must be someone
因为肯定有人在场。
unfortunately like everybody which is
不幸的是，就像所有人一样。
why which is why I've caved. So,
这就是我最终妥协的原因。所以，
well, thank you so much and it's so
非常感谢，这真是太好了。
wonderful to get to know you more and
很高兴能更了解你。
understand how you're thinking about all
了解你对所有事情的看法
of these things. And thank you for the
这些事情。谢谢你。
wisdom that all of the entrepreneurs,
所有企业家都拥有的智慧，
the founders, the listening to this
创始人，聆听这一切
conversation have gained from you. And I
我们从你的谈话中受益匪浅。我
do encourage you to do more of this kind
鼓励你多做一些这类事情
of thing because there's so many of us
因为我们人太多了。
that are so curious um about the ups,
他们对上升点非常好奇，
the downs and everything in the middle
低谷和中间的一切
of being an entrepreneur, building a
成为一名企业家，建立一个
company like you have in a world that is
在这个世界上，像您这样的公司非常难得。
changing at absolute light speed. So
以绝对光速变化。所以
it's a real service to all of us to get
这对我们所有人来说都是一项真正的服务。
to know you, to get to know the thinking
了解你，了解你的想法
of the company. Um but also to be able
公司。嗯，但也要能够
to learn from the experience you've had.
从你过去的经历中吸取教训。
And I'm really excited now to go and try
我现在真的很兴奋，迫不及待地想去尝试一下。
these spectacles. Awesome. Let's do it.
这些眼镜。惊人的。我们开始做吧。
We launched these conversation cards and
我们推出了这些对话卡片，
they sold out. And we launched them
它们都卖光了。我们推出了它们
again and they sold out again. We
他们又一次售罄了。我们
launched them again and they sold out
它们再次上市后便销售一空。
again because people love playing these
再次因为人们喜欢玩这些游戏。
with colleagues at work, with friends at
与同事在工作中，与朋友们在……
home, and also with family. And we've
在家，也和家人在一起。我们已经
also got a big audience that use them as
也拥有大量将其用作
journal prompts. Every single time a
写作提示。每一次
guest comes on the diary of a CEO, they
一位嘉宾出现在CEO的日程安排中，他们
leave a question for the next guest in
请留下一个问题，以便下一位客人提问。
the diary. And I've sat here with some
日记。我一直和一些人坐在这里。
of the most incredible people in the
世界上最了不起的人
world. And they've left all of these
世界。他们留下了所有这些
questions in the diary. And I've ranked
日记中的问题。我已经排名了
them from one to three in terms of the
它们在各方面都从一到三名不等。
depth. One being a starter question. And
深度。第一个问题是引导性的。和
level three, if you look on the back
第三层，如果你看背面的话。
here, this is a level three, becomes a
这里，这是三级，变成了
much deeper question that builds even
一个更深层次的问题，甚至会引发更多问题。
more connection. If you turn the cards
加强联系。如果你翻牌
over and you scan that QR code, you can
扫描该二维码，即可
see who answered the card and watch the
看看谁回复了卡片，然后观看。
video of them answering it in real time.
他们实时回答问题的视频。
So, if you would like to get your hands
所以，如果你想得到它
on some of these conversation cards, go
在某些对话卡片上，去
to the diary.com or look at the link in
访问 diary.com 或查看链接
the description
描述
[Music]
[音乐]
below. Heat. Heat. N.
以下。热。热。 N.